In the early hours of the morning, a cutter carrying
women and children from the wrecked Royal Navy troopship HMS Birkenhead
is rode to safety. From a distance. They watch in
horror as the officers and troops stand fast on
deck, silent, at attention as the
stricken ship rapidly sinks beneath them.
HMS Birkenhead is one of the first iron hulled ships built for
the Royal Navy. It's originally designed as a steam
frigate, but during construction it's converted to be a troopship.
A frigate is an agile warship commonly used as an escort
vessel for larger convoys. The Admiralty are uncertain
of the relatively new steam power in ships and don't want
to risk their fleet with an untested technology. As a
troopship, it can quickly deploy troops where needed, but won't
need to fight. The ship has twelve watertight
compartments separating the forward sections, the ship's
machinery midship and the aft compartments.
HMS Birkenhead is designed by John led and
built in the John led shipyard in Birkenhead, Lancashire.
It's originally christened HMS Vulcan and launched
by the Marchones of Westminster on 30 December
1845. By the end of the year, it's renamed HMS
Birkenhead in honor of the town where it's built.
HMS Birkenhead is 64 meters in length with a beam
of 11 meters and a draught of 5 meters below
the waterline. The ship's powered by two forester and CO
564 hp steam engines driving
a pair of paddle wheels 6 meters in diameter.
With a top speed of ten knots, the ship has a full complement
of sails and the steam engines provide additional maneuverability
and speed. The ship's manned by a crew of 125
officers and men. HMS Birkenhead
sails its maiden voyage from Birkenhead to the Royal Navy
Base in Plymouth, Devon, in 1846. It's in
service for five years before it's laid up in Plymouth, where it's refitted
before going back into service. In January 1852,
under the command of Captain Robert Salmond, HMS Birkenhead
sails from Portsmouth bound for Algoa Bay on the east
coast of South Africa. On board are troops belonging
to ten different British army regiments. The troops
will reinforce British forces fighting the 8th Causa
War against the indigenous Causa tribes of the Eastern
Cape region of South Africa. On the 5 January,
Birkenhead calls at Queenstown in Ireland to pick up more troops,
as well as the wives and families of several of the officers
on board. After six weeks at sea, Birkenhead docks in
Simonstown in False Bay on the morning of the 23 February,
the Royal Navy took over the harbor at Simonstown in
the 1790s to build out a naval base which still
exists today under the South African Navy. Most of the women and
children on board disembark together with several troops who have
become ill during the voyage. During their stay in Simonstown,
nine cavalry horses, several bales of hay, and 35 tons
of coal are taken on board in preparation for the last leg of
the voyage to Algoa Bay. This last leg is around 450
nautical miles and will take two days to sail.
At 1800 on the 25 February, in clear skies and
calm seas, Birkinhead set sail for Algoa Bay with
between 630 and 643 men, women,
and children on board. The exact number isn't recorded.
In order to make the best possible speed, Captain Salmon decides to hug
the coastline, setting a course that will keep Birkenhead approximately
3 miles off the coast.
On the voyage south from Plymouth, Birkenhead sailed against the Benguela
Current, sailing up the east coast of southern Africa. It faces
the Mozambique Current. These standing ocean currents
are most powerful in deep water. Closer to land,
the currents encounter resistance from the land in shallower water, which slows
them down, and so it's easier to sail against the current in shallower
water while hugging the coastline. Just before 200
on the 26 February, Birkenhead is making 8.5
knots. While passing danger point off the coast of
Hansbai, the leadsman in the bow takes a deaf sounding.
There's 22 meters of water beneath Birkenhead's bow.
When sailing at night, the land might not be visible,
and so one way to navigate is to follow a depth contour.
The Leedsman takes regular depth soundings by dropping a
weighted rope and counting the number of knots in the rope between the
ship and the seabed. If the depth gets shallower, they turn
the ship out to sea, and if the depth gets deeper,
they turn back to land.
Before the leadsman can make his next sounding, Birkenhead strikes
an uncharted rock 3.7 meters below
the bough. In stormy weather, when waves have high crests
and deep troughs, the rock can be seen clearly in the
rough waves. But in these calm conditions,
the long swell rolls slowly and is neither high
nor deep, so the rocks are hidden below the waterline.
Captain Salmond rushes on deck, orders the anchor dropped,
the quarterboats to be lowered, and one turn, a stern of
the engines. As the ship backs off, the sea rushes
in through the large hole created from striking the rock.
The long rolling swell pushes Birkenhead forward,
and it strikes again, buckling the plate of the forward
bilge and ripping open the forward bulkheads.
The forward compartment and the engine room flood.
Over. A hundred troopers sleeping below deck are
drowned in their bunks. The surviving officers, men,
women and children assemble on deck. Captain Salmond orders
Lieutenant Colonel Seaton, the senior military officer aboard,
to send men to man the bilge pumps.
60 men are assigned to the pumps, 60 to man
the lifeboat tackles, and the remaining men assemble on the poop
deck towards the back of the ship in an effort to lower the
stern and in turn raise the bough.
The women and children are placed in the ship's cutter, which is
lying alongside. Captain Salmond orders two further
large boats, each capable of carrying 150 people,
to be launched. The first is immediately swamped and lost,
while the second can't be launched because the tackle blocks haven't been maintained
and the ropes don't run through them. This leaves
only the cutter and three small lifeboats to take men aboard.
The surviving officers and men now assemble on the poop deck,
where Lieutenant Colonel SetoN calls for his officers and
men to maintain discipline and order. Everyone is silent.
The only sounds in the air are Captain Salmon quietly
reminding his men to stay calm, the horses kicking on deck
and a small swell rolling up on the side of the ship.
Ten minutes after Birkenhead first strikes the rock.
With the engine still going asturn, Birkenhead strikes
the rock a third and final time. Tearing open the bottom plates.
The ship breaks into just behind the main mast.
The funnel collapses and goes overboard. The four parts
of the ship sinks rapidly. The stern section, now heavily crowded
with men, begins to flounder and sink.
Captain salmon calls out all who can swim. Jump overboard
and swim for the boats. Lieutenant Colonel Seton
realises that order will cause a rush for the cutter
and the three small lifeboats, which risks swamping
them, endangering the lives of the women and children. He orders
all troops to stand fast. Only three troopers
break ranks and swim for the Qatar. The nine cavalry horses
are released and driven into the sea. One breaks
its leg and is quickly killed by great white sharks.
The other eight make it safely to shore.
Khanspai is one of the world's great white shark hotspots.
The cold Benguela Current and the warm Mozambique Current
collide in this region, both bringing a supply of nutrients that filter
up the food chain. These African great white sharks feed
predominantly on the large seal population in the area and
are happy to supplement that diet with a few British soldiers
if the opportunity presents itself. The soldiers
and their surviving officers stand fast, not moving,
as the Birkenhead sinks beneath them. Barely 20 minutes
after striking the rock. Some soldiers do manage to swim
the 2 miles to shore. Many drown,
die of exposure, or are killed by the frenzied
great white sharks. Early the next day, the schooner Lionesse
discovers the cutter takes on board the women and children as
well as survivors from one of the small lifeboats, then heads
for Birkenhead's location. Arriving in the afternoon,
Lionesse finds 40 survivors clinging to Birkenhead's rigging
and takes them on board. The total number of persons aboard the Birkenhead
at the time of the disaster has always been uncertain.
An estimate of 638 is published
in the Times newspaper in London. The survivors consist
of 113 soldiers of all ranks,
six Royal Navy Marines, 54 sailors of all ranks,
seven women, 13 children and one civilian.
A total of 194 men, women and children,
444 men died.
The traditional wooden naval ships at the time, or a ship designed
without watertight bulkhead compartments, would have broken up more
quickly and the death toll would likely have been higher.
The stronger metal gave some protection from the rock, and the watertight
bulkheads slowed the flooding, which gave the crew enough time to
evacuate some of the survivors. Several sailors are
court martialed aboard HMS Victory in Portsmouth on eigth
of May, 1852. The court case generated
an enormous amount of interest from the British public because
none of Birkenhead's senior officers survived the accident. No one
is held responsible. A lighthouse standing 18
meters tall with a light that's visible for 25 nautical miles
out to sea, was built at Danger Point in 1895.
In 1936, a remembrance plate to the Birkenhead
was affixed to the base of the lighthouse by the Naval League of South Africa.
The discipline and valor of the officers and troops aboard Birkenhead,
together with the decision to place the women and children in the Qatar before
anyone else, has led to what is now known as the Birkenhead Drill,
or more commonly accepted as women and children.
First,
thanks for watching. If you enjoyed this video and would like to watch more videos
from this channel without any ads, please consider joining our
patreon. The link is in the description. You can join for free
or select a membership with benefits ranging from ad free videos through to
early access and live Q A calls. I look
forward to meeting you there.