The traditional retail model is shifting rapidly, and there's a
golden opportunity for anyone, yes, anyone, to dive into
the world of ecommerce. Young, ordinary people who have
zero experience in the world of business, very little startup capital
and limited free time, are taking advantage of this
opportunity to make thousand, 10,000,
and even upwards of a hundred thousand euros every month.
So how are they doing this? Well, they are utilizing the business
models that I'll be breaking down and comparing in this video.
In the end, I'll even show you my stepbystep framework
that I've personally used to grow eight brands that collectively have done
over €50 million in revenue over the past two and a half years.
But before we get into it, I do want to be absolutely
transparent with you. If you've clicked this video, it's most likely because
you've got a goal of one day running a successful online business.
But the honest truth is that 95% of people
who start a business, a side hustle or whatever it might be, fail within the
first few months. And I cannot guarantee you that you will see the same results
that I have. But what I can guarantee you, however, is by watching
this video and paying close attention to what I'm about to tell you,
you will have taken the first but crucial step towards becoming
a part of the 5% that do succeed.
In case you've never seen or heard of me, my name is Nicolai
Peterson. I've been trying to make money online ever since I was 16
years old, and it was only recently that I actually found success
through ecommerce. Prior to that, I've personally experienced with a
long list of different business models. I've done day trading.
I build a SaaS platform, a fashion brand, a printondemand
company, and the list goes on. Therefore,
I'm speaking from my own experience when I talk about these business
models. So, let's get into it. When picking what business model best suits
you, there are a few things you need to consider. First and foremost,
do you have any specific skills that you can leverage?
Maybe you already know how to code a website. Or perhaps
you're naturally a sociable person who knows how to sell a
product. If you possess any skills, you're already ahead of most
people. Next thing to consider is the starting capital.
How much money can you realistically invest in the business?
You also have to be aware of how many hours you're willing to put into
the business to make it work. Now, you can definitely become
incredibly wealthy with any of these business models
that I'm about to go through, but some of them are way easier to get
large profits with than others. Lastly, when you
finally got a business up and running, you also want to consider to what
degree the operation is able to run without your personal interference.
Are you able to make it into passive income? Partly passive perhaps.
Or do you need to be there full time, nonstop? With all
of these categories in mind, let's now look at some popular online business
models. A service based business model leverages your skills to either consult,
coach or perform a specific task for your clients. It often
takes a higher level of expertise, but luckily the startup costs
are minimal or nonexistent as you only really are relying
on your own skills to get started. However, that also means that the time
you have to invest is quite substantial and the possibility
of autonomy is virtually zero. However, because people
usually value high quality one on one work,
the profit margins tend to be great in this space. Now another
very popular recent business model is info products.
These are things such as online courses, ebooks and
even YouTube videos. In the case of YouTube videos, you can obviously get
started without money or any particular skills. But usually
info products require a high level of both skills and time
investment. I've personally in the past year spent over €50,000
developing the best possible info product, but that would be a
lot of money for a beginner to put into a product. As for the
profitability, the margins are usually very high in info products based
business, and that's because you've got virtually no cost of the product.
The primary catch here is that you have to spend some money on marketing.
Now the possibility of autonomy here depends on what kind of info product
you're selling. An ebook can become passive income.
While that would be impossible with a YouTube channel,
yet another business model that you might have heard of is called affiliate
marketing. Now this is where you earn a commission by marketing another
company's product. There are few startup costs here in the
form of so me ads and building a website.
The adventurous thing about affiliate marketing is that the company
which product you are selling handles the entire fulfillment
side of the process, which obviously lowers the barrier of entry
in the form of skills and time needed. But the problem
with a lower barrier of entry is that it's usually followed by a
lot of competition. Now when it comes to autonomy, the entire
process can be mostly automated if you outsource your marketing.
Another business model is obviously software, also called
SaaS software as a service, and that's a subscription based
software that you can access via the Internet. And you already know
a bunch of these. These are things like Netflix, Office 365,
Zoom perhaps, and so on. The catch here is that these
often require a lot of time, money and expertise,
and are rarely suited for beginners. They do,
however, have the highest profitability and possibility of
autonomy. And also, if you want to sell your software business,
this is where you'll get the highest possible price for
your business. Lastly, we've got ecommerce, which is a bit
of a broad categorization, but we'll get into the specifics in
just a minute. Now, the type of e commerce that I'll be teaching you
does require a fair bit of skill. Sourcing your product
through a reputable supplier, negotiating beneficial shipping
arrangements, creating a conversion optimized Shopify store,
marketing your product on Meta TikTok and etc. In a way that
attracts customers. Thankfully for you, these are skills
you can acquire right here on YouTube, and I'll even help
you get started today. You do need a bit of starting capital to get
your product off the ground, though, but nothing major here around
€100 should be sufficient. I personally got started with my first
and to this day most successful ecommerce brand with
exactly €513 on my account,
and I launched the brand for around €60.
Initially, you'll have to invest time to get your store
ads and supplier relationships up and running, but most of
these operations can be outsourced quite easily when you've got a sufficient
cash flow. But the absolute best thing about ecommerce is
nearly the infinite scalability and profitability.
And now look, I'm obviously slightly biased towards ecommerce. It's where
my personal expertise lies and it's what's made me my
money and it's what I teach my students. But the honest
truth is that you have to choose a business model that fits your skill
set. Your business should be a reflection of who you are as a person,
so it's crucial that you choose one that fits your
criteria. With that said, it's now finally time to
get into my four step ecommerce framework that I've used to grow and scale
my brands. To start with, your ecommerce brand
as lean as humanly possible. What I always love to
do is to start with something called preorders, and using
preorders is what I've had success with with all of my
brands, over 20 successful Shopify stores. And I know what
you're thinking. If it was that easy, wouldn't everyone just do it?
The reason why this works is actually because there are so
many people trying to take advantage of customers by selling trendy,
poor quality products. My whole framework, on the contrary,
is built upon providing as much value to the customers
as possible. And that's honestly one of my largest personal
secrets. So I won't ever teach you how to do dropshipping or
scam customers. And this is by no means a get
rich quick scheme. I want you to build a legit, stable business that
provides actual value to its customers.
We simply just use the technique to validate our product and
after one to two weeks we switch to a completely in
house brand with a three PL and such. So the first
step is sourcing a winning product. What I love to do here
is to simply look at other successful brands.
And I actually like to call this method open your eyes, because so
many people out there are obsessed over the best products by software
tools. But in reality, you don't need anything else than
to open your eyes and to simply become aware of what's performing
for other brands. Take a look at what products successful brands are
promoting in either your country or in other markets.
Personally, I love being aware of what brands in the US or
Australia do and then implementing that in Europe or Scandinavia.
With that said, a winning product in my eyes has some very
specific criteria which yours need to be able to
uphold by. Here's the three most important ones.
A high AOV and that's average order value. This means
that your product should just basically, in my opinion,
cost at least €60. The second thing is
a high margin. Your sales price for the product should at least
be three X your purchase price for the product,
preferably more. The third and final thing is a good market,
and this is a market without many competitors but still with a significant
size. I typically determine this by doing some kind of online
research on my product by simply Google searching it and looking for competitors.
And if I can't find any, then that's a good sign. It's also completely
fine if there are competitors in the market. The most important thing is
that you know how to beat them. Setting up your store
this is the point where you sign up to Shopify. We've got a discount link
below and create your first store. There is a free trial
on Shopify, so this is once again completely risk free.
So sign up, set up your Shopify store and then you're good to
go. If you want a step by step guide on how to set up your
Shopify store, be sure to subscribe because I'll have a video coming
out about that shortly. Now, once you're making your store,
it's crucial to make it as trustworthy as humanly
possible. So what I strongly recommend here, if you are a beginner, is to go
onto larger, established stores and take a look at how exactly they've
built their store and then get inspiration from that. Don't copy,
but take inspiration, because chances are they've tested a lot
on their site to improve their conversion rate. So by using their
learnings and the entire landing page structure, you should be working
in the right direction. Creating a brand we
want to strongly brand our product once we've seen some serious proof
of concept for the product. So initially, when you're creating your brand,
do it as lean as possible. And what I mean by that
is you shouldn't spend hours making a logo or coming up
with a clever name. You can always change and improve that later.
So for now, we just want you to focus on testing the product as soon
and as lean as possible. With that said, as soon as you found proof
of concept with your product, one of the first things you should do is to
create brand guidelines. I've got a template for you to download for free
down below. By setting up clear brand guidelines quite
early, it just makes your brand seems so much more professional
compared to your typical dropshipping stores. This is something a
lot of beginners fail to do. Once again here, if you're new,
take inspiration from your competitors as to how they've
positioned their brand. Take a look at the colors they've used,
the fonts, the tone of voice and etc.
Marketing your product now it's time to test your product.
I've always done so on meta through Facebook
and Instagram ads. A good rule of thumb that I always use is
that you should be able to test whether your product is viable by at most
three X the sales price of your product on ads. So if
your product is selling at €100, then you should never
spend more than €300. Testing your product through
ads most times I've tested all my products for around 150
to €200, and that's because once you've spent that amount,
you should have sufficient data to be able to read and determine whether
or not your product is viable. The main metric we're analyzing
here is something called ROAs, which stands for return on ad
spend. And that's basically just how much revenue you generate
on €1. Spend on ads. So if you spend €100 on ads
and you've generated €200 revenue, then that's
a roas of two. Therefore, it's calculated by dividing your
revenue with your ad spend. If we can achieve a roas of
above three, then we are really onto something and I
would see that as a successful test of your product.
I want to make it clear that this is obviously easier said than done,
and if you're doing this on your own, you'll likely spend a few months working
things out and that's completely fine. That could either be because you
can't find the exact winning product you're perhaps struggling with
conversion optimization on your Shopify store or your ad creatives
are lacking. These are issues I see all the time, and often when people
encounter them, they simply quit. But I strongly encourage you to
keep going. Take each failed product as a lesson
and eventually, if you try hard enough for long enough, you will
see results. There's no doubt about it. If you're someone who
wants to get started right away from the get go and skip all of
the months of trial and error, I've created the solution for
you. Scaling with E Comm is an e commerce mentorship course that
I've created with some of the best experts in the field.
But SWE is not just another course. We are
a completely result orientated community that help entrepreneurs
build and scale e commerce stores all the way from your first million
in revenue to a potential life changing exit.
We do this with personalized counseling, including a tailored
roadmap just for you, weekly coaching calls
with myself as well as the other experts on the team.
And contrary to most other courses on the market, SW is
built by a team with actual results in the industry. Just to
reiterate, I myself personally have done €15 million
in revenue across all my ecommerce stores in the past
two and a half years. And on top of that, we've got experts
in the community with knowledge from over €33
million in ad spend. SWE is much more than
just a course. While we do have plus 50 step by
step modules that will take you from an absolute beginner to a
seasoned ecommerce Pro. We also offer you access to my network
and resources, including agencies, suppliers,
logistics and more. You will have complete access to my team
and I. Best of all, we've got an ambitious
community of like minded entrepreneurs who share advice and
success stories to keep each other motivated. If you think you're a good
fit for SWE and want to become a part of the community
and learn the ways of ecommerce, well then check out the link below to
book a call with us.