On September 28, 2008, John Manili,
alongside his trusted friends John Valentin and Charles Reed Henry,
embarked on a daring exploration of the sorcerer Dudube's Cave,
hoping to create lasting memories. Tragically,
this adventure turned into a heart wrenching tale as fate had a
somber outcome in store forever in printing Manili's
name in the cave's history in the most devastating way.
Born John Manili's life
was intense, with passions for motorcycling and scuba diving.
His early training days were spent locally, but it wasn't long before
he joined Brighton's British subaquatic Club, or BSAC
ranks. His presence was quickly felt.
He became an integral and reliable member, urging his fellow
divers toward experiences and heightened safety in their underwater endeavors.
His thirst for the unexplored was insatiable. He wasn't
content with being a regular diver. He yearned for more.
This led him to acquire a rebreather and embark on specialized training,
propelling him into advanced diving groups and exploring deeper, more challenging
wrecks. Rebreather diving recycles exhaled air,
removing carbon dioxide and adding oxygen, allowing longer,
quieter dives. It's challenging due to the complex equipment
management and the need for precise gas balance.
Inexperience can lead to life threatening situations like oxygen toxicity
or hypoxia, making it risky for untrained divers.
His journey eventually steered him towards the world of cave diving in
the UK and France. Parallel to Manili's journey
was John Valanthen, a figure synonymous with the pinnacle of
cave exploration and rescue. Holding a world record.
Volanthan's impact on the field, especially his crucial role in
the 2018 Tham Lewing Thai rescue has redefined cave diving
over two decades. His fearless explorations had written new
chapters of these newly discovered super caves. On November
18, 2007, Philanthropan etched another landmark of
achievement in the history of cave diving. By braving the sorcere dude,
he navigated its treacherous depths, overcoming formidable obstacles
and laying down 476ft, or 145 meters of line.
A year later, Andre Glore and Pedro Bellardi ventured into the
cave, flaying a second marked line, reaching a new tremendous 1549ft,
or 472 meters from the entrance. Their efforts
were followed by successive dives continuously pushing the boundaries,
extending the cave's known limits to an astonishing 3445ft,
or 1050 meters. Inspired by these feats,
John Manilia was drawn deeper into the quest to explore the
source of Dudup. To embark on this formidable journey, he enlisted the
support of his friends and trusted divers, Charles Reed Henry and John
Valanthan together, they prepared to confront the cave's daunting
depths, a testament to their unyielding spirit and shared bond in the face
of the unknown. The three friends expedition into the cave's
depths would be fraught with danger at every turn. The narrow, shallow passages
presented a treacherous challenge, with the ever present risk of damaging
crucial equipment in an environment where every inch and every
second counted. These constricted pathways significantly impeded the
possibility of a swift retreat in case of an emergency.
On the eve of this fateful dive, John Maniley faced grave concerns
from his friends and fellow divers John Blanthen and Charles Reed Henry.
They warned him about the considerable size of his rebreather,
underscoring the severe impracticality and inherent danger of
using such bulky equipment in the cave's more restrictive and perilous
sections. Yet Manili, in a move marked by recklessness,
chose to disregard these warnings, emboldening himself to confront
the cave's looming threats with gear ill suited for its harsh realities.
Adding a layer of peril to this already dangerous endeavor was Maneli's
compromised physical state. He bore the lasting scars of
a severe back injury from a motorcycle accident in 1998,
an injury that had not just left him with physical marks but also persistent
limitations. This critical aspect of his condition,
often overlooked, became a pivotal factor in the events
that unfolded. The injuries severely curtailed his maneuverability,
especially in the cave's tight, unforgiving passages that demanded the utmost agility
and flexibility as the three friends would have to delve
deeper into the cave system. The combination of the challenging environment,
the bulky equipment, and Manili's physical limitations created a
scenario fraught with danger. The cave's claustrophobic
passages became a gauntlet barely wide enough to allow passage.
Each move carried weight in the hostile underground world, and the shadow
of potential catastrophe loomed large over the journey.
Beneath a modest twelve x 16 foot, or three by four meter opening,
the beginning of the cave plummets to a daunting 5 meters.
Divers begin their descent through a vertical crack, or known as s one,
leading to the ominous edge of a shaft called S three. The cave's
complex layout includes several chimney halls dropping
to a chilling 215ft, or 65 meters.
A hazardous passage, widened yet treacherous, lies 541ft,
165 meters beneath s three.
The journey beyond is marked by poor visibility,
dense sediment, and the challenges of navigating with scooters.
The fissure's floor, strewn with sharp, fossil rich boulders,
leads to a constricted passage culminating in a disturbance zone
at 1800ft, 555 meters. That descends into
a steep, gravel filled corridor. This formidable cave stretches
over 4576ft.
1400 meters, presenting a harrowing challenge to even the
most skilled cave divers. The secluded sorcere dude is
an obscure water filled cave at the foot of Montrezu, near Mutt,
France. It's infamous as France's coldest town
endures brutally low temperatures in winter, contrasting sharply
with its intense summers. This extreme climate gave it
the name Little Siberia. The cave, a hidden gem
in the middle of this rugged landscape, sits at the level of a
place where silence and solitude reign. Its dense, sprawling forest
are a hallmark of the Jura region. Adding to the seclusion of the
surrounding area. This range also serves as a natural boundary,
marking the national border between Switzerland and France.
The cave, with its crystal clear waters, is a diver's enigma.
Inviting, yet intimidating. Promising adventure, but also echoing
with the solitude of its surroundings. Delving into the cave's
depths, divers are met with a relentless chill. As the water temperature stubbornly
hovers around 43 degrees Fahrenheit, six degrees Celsius.
This constant cold forms an unyielding barrier. The cave's waterways
carve a complex path towards the rocks, weaving an intricate web
that has long baffled even the most seasoned divers.
The source of Dudupe has become a siren call for daring divers,
drawing them into the depths in the quest for discovery.
Yet this pursuit is not without its perils.
The cave has claimed the lives of many who have dared to go too far
into the cave. On September 28,
2008, the expedition commenced with John Manili, John Valanthan,
and Charles Reed Henry to explore the sorcere dudup.
Embracing the practice of autonomous diving, each member ventured
into the cave's depths independently, facing the unknown. Without the aid of
a team. The entrance to the cave presented the first test of their
resolve. Buried with a cumbersome rebreather, John Manili cautiously
navigated the confined space. Every move was measured
as the risk of entrapment in such tight quarters was a constant threat.
Approximately 13 meters into the dive, John encountered the upper ledge
of the shaft, known as S Two. Descending into S
two was like plunging into an abyss. The water turned icy
and pitch black, forcing him to rely solely on his flashlights
to pierce the engulfing darkness. The shaft's nearly vertical
descent tested his skills and nerves. As he made his way deeper.
The chilling waters in the oppressive darkness created a sense of claustrophobia.
The cave walls looming ominously close. Every decision John
made carried weight, as a single misstep could lead to a
catastrophe. The cave's depths were unforgiving, and the
complexity of the environment demanded constant vigilance. The underwater
passage was a labyrinth, with each twist and turn holding potential dangers,
from sudden drop offs to narrow bottlenecks that could easily ensnare John.
The chilling silence of the cave was broken only by the sound of
his breathing and the bubbles rising from his rebreather. As he
ventured further, the cave's claustrophobic grip tightened.
The passage narrowed, and the sediment strewn floor became more
treacherous, with dragged rocks and boulders lurking in the shadows.
The cave's environment was a constant battle against the elements.
The cold water was sapping his strength, and the narrow passages demanded
precision and the darkness challenging his senses.
Every meter he descended took him further from the safety of the surface,
deeper into the heart of the cave. As he progressed, the cave's futures
became more daunting. Stalactites and Stalagmites formed
eerie shapes in the beam of his lights. The water's chill penetrated
his wetsuit, reminding him of the cave's indifference to human presence.
As John Manili descended deeper into the sorcere dude, the environment
transformed into a more menacing and constricted labyrinth. At 1056ft,
322 meters, the shaft's descent became steeper.
It led him to an ominous, more giant obstruction hole, its mouth
cluttered with chunky, blocky materials. To the right of
the shaft floor, a narrow crevice beckoned, leading to an
uphill cave passage. This area was fraught with challenges.
A significant sediment accumulation resulted in intense turbidity,
clouding John's vision and complicating navigation.
The water, thick with particulate matter, created a disorienting, murky veil,
demanding the utmost concentration and skill to proceed.
Despite the conditions, John's resolve remained unshaken.
The underwater realm fueled his determination with its dark beauty
and profound silence. Navigating through the cave, John encountered
a passage on the left, a gateway to a further valleyside
corridor. The narrow and treacherous passage had been slightly expanded
in 2002, yet remained a daunting challenge.
With seasoned expertise, John meticulously maneuvered through
the claustrophobic route, his every movement calculated and deliberate.
The confined space demanded exceptional control and awareness,
as any misstep could lead to entrapment or equipment failure.
Monitoring his depth gauge and air supply with unwavering attention,
John advanced through the passage and commenced directly below into the shaft
floor of S three. The once open hall had succumbed to a collapse,
burying its initial 98ft, or 30 meters and transforming
it into a treacherous maze of debris and tight squeezes.
After covering a daunting distance of approximately 1821ft,
or 550 meters. He arrived at the first major fold zone,
a geological challenge marked by steep slopes and unpredictable
terrain. Angling sharply downward, the passage
was lined with accumulations of gravel banks, remnants of ancient
underwater currents. Now silent and still, the gravel banks,
a labyrinth of natural barriers, impeded his progress,
forcing him to navigate cautiously. The loose gravel and
the steep incline created a treacherous landscape where every movement
could trigger a cascade, altering the cave's delicate equilibrium.
As John delved deeper, the cave's confining walls seemed to close
around him, creating a palpable sense of claustrophobia. The limited space,
combined with the sheer depth he had reached, underscored the risks of
his solitary endeavor. His air supply, a lifeline in this submerged
world, was dwindling, and he was acutely aware of its preciousness.
Adhering to the rule of thirds, a critical safety protocol and cave
diving, John calculated his air reserves, ensuring he retained
enough for a safe ascent. In scuba diving,
particularly in overhead environments like caves and wrecks, the rule
of thirds is a critical guideline for gas management. It mandates
that divers allocate one third of their gas supply for the onward journey,
another third for the return, and reserve the final as a crucial safety
margin. The rule is essential where direct descent is not an
option. And the divers must retrace their path to exit.
When diving with a buddy, especially one with a higher gas consumption
rate, the third is often based on the buddy's supply,
necessitating an earlier turnaround or carrying extra gas
for safety. This cautious approach ensures a safe return. From these
treacherous underwater environments. As he prepared for return
to the entrance of the cave, he felt good that he made it this deep
into the passages. But due to his air running low, he knew he needed
to get out. Retracing his path, John faced the obstacles
he had navigated on his descent. Each twist and turn of the cave was
a puzzle, demanding meticulous attention and skill. The journey
back was as much a mental challenge as a physical one.
Each stroke took him closer to safety. But the oppressive darkness
and the knowledge of the cave's hidden dangers weighted heavily on him.
The return swim was a race against time and his dwindling air reserves.
Navigating through the cave's claustrophobic passages with a cumbersome rebreather
presented a formidable challenge. The precariously positioned boulders
could easily become dislodged. Transforming the route into a perilous trap.
John was aware of this, but he continued to push. The end
of the S two section posed a formidable challenge. Strewn with large boulders
that created a series of tight squeezes. Maneuvering through this section
was a delicate balance of technique and caution. The tight confines of the
underwater labyrinth seemed to constrict around him, leaving little room for
maneuver. To alleviate his struggle, John made a critical decision
that would soon escalate into a dire situation. He chose to remove
his rebreather, a decision that, under the circumstances, seemed necessary,
but was fraught with risk. Squeezing through the narrow gap without the bulk of
a rebreather, he relied on an alternate air source, a bottle
he held under his arm. This temporary solution,
however, brought its own set of dangers. The cave's
oppressive walls, unyielding, enclosed, pressed in on him,
exacerbating the difficulty of his movements. His preexisting
back injury from 1998 further complicated his situation,
making it impossible to put on the rebreather again in such confined quarters.
Faced with limited options and a rapidly deteriorating situation,
John decided he needed to move faster to head back to the surface,
navigating the torturous path with the air bottle tucked under his arm.
The ascent, however, took a treacherous turn. Suddenly,
the bottle detached from the rubber hose of his mouthpiece, leaving him in a serious
predicament far from the cave's entrance. Stranded without an
air supply in the suffocating embrace of the underwater cave, panic set
in. In a frantic and desperate search, John attempted
to retrieve the lost air bottle. But his efforts were in vain. The murky
waters in the tight space hampered his movements, turning the cave
into a disorientating, treacherous maze. As the precious seconds
ticked away, the lack of oxygen began to take its toll on John.
His breaths became shallow, his movements sluggish,
and his vision blurred. The cave transformed from a challenging
dive site into a nightmarish trap. In these harrowing moments,
the darkness of the surroundings, the weight of the water above, and the daunting
realization of his predicament converged, creating an overwhelming
sense of dread. As oxygen deprivation intensified,
John's struggle reached a critical point. His consciousness began
to slip away, succumbing to the suffocating grip of hypoxia.
Isolated and helpless, far from the safety of the surface
and trapped within the unyielding confines of the cave, he faced
the stark reality of his circumstances. A diver alone
in the depths. Confronted by the unrelenting and indiscriminate
force of nature, a dire situation was unfolding in the depths of
the source. Doodoo. Doob. John Manley's diving partners,
John Valanthan and Charles, emerged from the cave, only to be confronted
by their friend's absence. As time ticked by with no sign of
John, a feeling of impending doom enclosed them.
Concern mounted rapidly, transforming into a tangible fear for
his well being. Recognizing the gravity of the situation,
they urgently called for emergency services. Their minds
racing with worry, resolved to leave no stone
unturned, John Valanthan and Charles decided to plunge back into the
cave's claustrophobic maw in a desperate search for John.
The cave, a silent and unyielding entity, seemed to
echo their concern. As they reached the path they had previously taken.
Their worst nightmares materialized when they stumbled upon a heart
wrenching scene. John's lifeless body lay trapped
under a ledge in the main shaft of the cave. At a depth of
85ft, or 26 meters, John had met
his untimely end in the oppressive confines of the underwater
labyrinth. John Belanthan and Charles, grappling with shock
and grief, undertook the solemn task of retrieving John's body from the
cave's clutches. Upon reaching the surface, they were
met by firefighters who immediately commenced resuscitation
efforts. But the harsh reality set in. It was
too late. John had succumbed to the dangers of the cave.
The tragic loss of John Manili at the age of 32 was
a stark reminder of the risks inherent in cave diving.
His demise was not just a personal tragedy, but a somber lesson
to the diving community. I want to say thank you for
joining me today and if this story moves you, please consider liking the
video and subscribing to our channel. I'm looking forward to seeing you at the next
one.