There's one big question on people's minds. After over a decade
since GTA Five, what does Rockstar have in store this time? The bar
couldn't possibly be higher. Thanks to its massive release and its online
economy, GTA Five is probably the highest grossing piece of media of
all time. Never has there been an opening like
this in the entertainment industry. This week,
Grand Theft Auto Five pulled in $1 billion
in deals in three days. No movie or
music release has ever come close to that. I'm here for
Grand Theft Auto Five, yeah. Reaching over
$6 billion, a figure that Rockstar would be lucky to match the next time
round. But with a reported development budget between one and $2 billion alone
for GTA Six, people will be expecting the world.
Most of all, people are going to be looking for something that builds on what
GTA Five did so well. The sheer scale of the game was
one of the things that really blew people away. The way the world seemed so
alive and the heist missions were dazzling spectacles which acted like
minifinalies. The story and the characters were incredibly well done, if a
little all over the place. You could definitely tell that each plot point had at
least 50 writers working on it. But that didn't stop the dialogue from being snappy
and the characters from being some of the funniest and most interesting we've seen in
a long while. At the end of the day, any game where you can steel
a blimp has at least something going for it. What cemented it all together,
though, were the mechanics of the game. Everything from the driving,
the flying, the combat mechanics, it all worked pretty much perfectly.
A massive step up over the previous games in the series. If any of these
elements were subpar, it would have ruined the entire game.
If the driving felt clunky or stiff, then it would have turned all the long
drives into a chore rather than a welcome change of pace.
Instead, the time you spend driving just seems to disappear. And this focus
on the core mechanics actually being fun over and over again is what's missing from
so many games today. But for GTA, it was what enabled Rockstar
to turn it into a massively successful MMO that's been running for nearly
a decade straight. If Rockstar doesn't get these essentials right for GTA
Six, then it might turn out as one of the biggest blunders of all time.
But it's unlikely. So then, what do we know about the game so far?
Well, speculation about GTH Six has been going on for years and years now,
but it wasn't until 2020 that we learned anything concrete. Even that
was part of a leak from the company. In a Kutaki report, insiders at the
studio said it was still a ways away, but they did add some details.
Even at such an early point, Rockstar has, and still is, infamous for their culture
of crunch and overworking their developers. Anyone who's played Red Dead Redemption
Two will know the sheer amount of time that must have gone into each tiny
detail. So to try and ease the burden, sources of the company said the game
would be limited in scope at first, but expand over time as new content gets
added. Although whether this is just an excuse for Rockstar to repackage paid DLC
is another story. Other than that, though, details were scant. It wasn't until
last year that we really done some other details. Five months after Rockstar officially
announced it was coming out, Bloomberg released a report on some of the upcoming game's
main features. We learned that the game would originally start off in Miami,
a fact that was later all but confirmed when development footage was leaked.
It wasn't long before people took some of the buildings they saw and matched them
exactly to some of Miami's real life structures. One detail, though,
was that while the map was going to be smaller than usual, we would have
far more indoor locations. Rockstar Games have always been
more focused on immersion in a real world, so this will be a welcome
change. On top of this, the game was confirmed to have two protagonists, one male
and one female, maybe a step back from the three main characters of GTA fIve,
but still interesting. Not many people base their judgments about a game on the amount
of protagonists anyway, but a few months later and there would be a much larger
leak showing footage from the unfinished game, raw code, and even
some voice acting from scenes in the game. Lots of it was scrubbed by
Rockstar shortly afterwards, although what was seen confirmed some early reports about
the game, and the leak actually turned out to be a 17 year old from
Britain who had hacked into Rockstar with a fire TV stick in a hotel room,
connected his mobile phone, and it wouldn't be all that surprising if a similar character
ends up in the game itself. But outside of the confirmed details, we can make
a lot of pretty strong predictions based on both what Rockstar's done with their previous
games, as well as a little common sense. But before we continue,
I want to talk about our video sponsor. Have you ever Googled yourself and were
shocked to see your personal information exposed on one of those public listing sites?
Databrokers are making a fortune selling your information to robocallers,
spammers and others who want to learn more about you, like where you live.
And that's why I'm excited to tell you about today's sponsor, Aura.
Aura can identify data brokers exposing your info and submit
opt out requests on your behalf. Now, brokers are legally required
to remove your info if you ask them to, but if they make it super
hard to do, let aura handle it for you and you can try aura for
free for two weeks using my link. Aura also does so much to protect
you and your family from online threats you can't see. It's super easy
to set up, and you don't have to download several different apps to get things
like parental controls, antivirus, VPN, password management,
identity theft, insurance, and more. Instead, you get everything in one at an affordable price.
So let Aura do the hard work of keeping you safe online so that you
can focus on other tasks with peace of mind. You can either let people continue
to exploit and profit off your private information, or you can go to
forward Slash Moon to start your two week free trial. Also linked
down in the description below, there will almost certainly be an online site of the
game, most likely separate from the single player. GTA's online Shark cards and
microtransaction kept the company afloat for a decade, promising perpetual income
for very little effort. In comparison, their effectiveness is most likely a
large part of why we haven't gotten GTA six sooner. Rockstar were pretty much
releasing a game every year before GTA Online came out. Since then,
we've seen just one major release in a decade. Another thing we can almost certainly
expect is a focus on satire. GTA Five was full of it,
as were the other games in the franchise, but today it's going to be a
bit trickier. Past ten years have seen real life surpass fiction
and how absurd and comical it is. Things we laughed at yesterday are normal today,
and so it's hard to imagine how Rockstar and the legions of writers will come
up with anything more crazy than what's in the news. Could life Invader from GTA
Five really be renamed into something dumber than Meta? Or could they come up with
anything more redundant than X? How could they even approach how insane an over
the top modern politics is today? Judging by what we saw in the last game,
though, there's a few obvious paths they could take. Two characters from GTA
Five that seem so much more relevant now are Michael's two children, Jimmy and
Tracy. Jimmy is the stereotypical gamer. He's a toxic manchild,
unaware of how awkward he is while also blaming everyone around him for the
fact he spends all days smoking and playing games. If they didn't drill it in
enough already, he's literally got the world entitled tattooed on
his neck. Tracy is on the other side of the coin. A stereotypical blonde airhead,
she goes through life entirely obsessed with status, image, and her own popularity.
She throws tantrums, is even more spored than her brother, and she's painfully
naive. This was RockstaR's over the top but disturbingly accurate
betrayal of teenagers at the time the game came out, and today nothing's really changed
except that these people grew up and now they're the ones setting the example and
guiding social media for everyone younger than them. It's a self perpetuating
cycle that began with people like these characters, and so you can be
sure that Rockstar's gonna roast the hell out of them. The Jimmies and traces of
yesterday are the influencers of today, the most entitled, Degenerate People
making the most money of all, considering how blatant and clearly greedy some
influencers are. Every week, like clockwork, there's another controversy about
some influencer pushing some awful product, usually a scam,
whilst failing to hide how stupid they think their audience is. Just look at
one of Pokemon's most recent scandals, trying to sell $28 cookies,
then insulting the people who call her out on it by saying they're just poor
and stupid cookies that are just an obvious rebrand or some other more
cheaper cookie, let alone all the crypto scams that influencers like Logan Paul Push.
Equally likely, though, is Rockstar making fun of both the Sims, calling these
people queen unironically so. Ruby Rose is a very popular
individual right now, and she posted this on Twitter. Today I ran into
my number one spinder on OnlyFans and we are blessed with
two magnificent pictures. Here on the left,
it is Ruby Rose posing with her number one
piggy bank dumper. Now let's turn our attention to exhibit B and we
can get the statistics. So he has been subscribed to her only fans
for a month and has spent a total of $62,000,
as well as the people spending their whole lives raging in comment sections.
Often, though, they're just the same people. GTA also excels at
specifically deconstructing American culture as well. While lots of other shows,
movies and games do this, GTA does it in such a complete and direct way
that it's unique. Every detail is a masterclass in satirizing America.
From the way the adverts on the radio sound to the ridiculous political campaigns
and billboards, it's uncanny how close they are to reality. The same report
says he allegedly used campaign money for a fleshy Las
Vegas holiday, a shopping spree at makeup store Sephora,
and for payments to OnlyFans, a site known for adult
entertainment. He's now facing 23 federal charges.
The Saturday is most visible, though, in the names Rockstar gives their fake companies.
Facebook turns to life, Invader Fox becomes Weasel news, and Goldman
Sachs is renamed to Schlonberg Sachs. While they might be juvenile,
these names are working on another level. Beyond crass humor, they're poking fun
at the double speak way that companies name themselves. Some of this ubiquitous today,
companies don't fire people anymore. They downsize, or they restructure.
Reductions in pay or the company's revenue becomes adjustments.
Instead, what began as little more than stupid buzwords in boardroom meetings has
infected every layer of society. Today, companies are so terrified
of the truth in their PR image that the names barely mean anything anymore.
Facebook became meta and Twitter turned into X. Both of the previous names actually
meant something. Facebook actually was a book of faces in the beginning.
Now they don't mean anything at all. Even company logos become bland and
featureless. Just compare any big name brand's logo to what it was ten
years ago. Nearly every time, it's just a simplified geometric version of it.
But with GTA Six said to be the most expensive AA game in history,
it might be an issue for Rockstar to properly satirize these megacorporations.
They are one now. It'll take a bit of the momentum out of every shot
they take at corporate America when they're a massive part of it. Although it might
not be as big of a problem as people expect. After every GTA
game, and for the entirety of GTA Online, you're invited to get straight back into
the criminal grind. Whatever lessons the protagonists learn about how they
should value their family or get out while they still can always fall away.
If they actually landed, the game would just end. Instead, there's an irony in how
the main character can finish the Rock, become a complete person, learn all
these core values about humanity, then get right back into murder and mayhem.
Rockstar are the same. Their character's arc finished with GTA Five. It was the definitive
GTA experience, and they became one of the largest gaming companies in the industry.
But now they're back to it all over again. But bigger and better. Rockstar themselves
are large enough to be satirized in the GTA game. If only they weren't the
ones making it. This is just one example of the million different ways Rockstar could
take on modern culture in GTA Six, there's literally a whole world of options
for them. Considering it's taking place in Miami, we're pretty much likely to see some
SoundCloud rappers at the very least, and all the degenerate podcasters.
But overall, the way Rockstar just cuts through the nonsense and
goes straight for the jugular is what makes GTA some of the best satire around.
The only thing left to see is whether they can keep the ball rolling for
GTA Six. These sorts of massive AA releases only come
along once in a while, and they're always a complete gamble. The more highly anticipated
a game is, the bigger risk there is of a complete flop if it doesn't
reach people's expectations. For gaming audiences especially,
the reactions can be a little on the extreme side. Considering people have been
waiting over a decade and the games have had more than a billion dollars thrown
at it, the possibilities are limitless.