It's about that time of the month again where a multimillionaire influencer decides
that they're gonna go fully mask off and prove to everybody just how
out of touch they are. Out of touch with what, you ask.
Reality completely living in another dimension of privilege,
entirely forgetting that the only reason they exist in such privilege
is built from standing on the shoulders of the people they now laugh at.
Yes, I'm now going to talk about Pokemon. When people
are like, oh my God, $28 for cookies.
It's four bags. That's seven.
$7 a bag. I know, I know, math is hard
when you're an idiot, but if
you're a broke boy, just say so. Anyways, for those of you that don't
know what you've just seen, let me fill you in. Pokemon is a popular streamer
on Twitch, one of the most popular. In fact, she's got tens of millions
of followers across all social media platforms, tens of millions of dollars in assets,
and like most other live streamers, has done her fair share of oopsies while
Live, which has resulted in some absolutely classic YouTube apology
videos. Hi everyone. I hope you're doing well. This video
is to address recent comments and criticisms that
I've received, so I'm going to try and speed run the info of what the
big controversy is and not go into too many details. A lot of videos covering
this are probably going to go into the many controversies of Pokimane, what she said,
what she's done over the years, but that's done to death. So instead, I want
to look at how ridiculous this entire situation's been and how
this drama has basically been created out of nothing at all apart from ego.
First off, timeline of events. What started it all was the most mundane,
boring shit you can imagine. Pokemon released some cookies.
Seriously, that's what this is all about. Her snack brand,
Minor, was released along with the first product called Midnight
Cookies. These cookies were heavily criticized for two reasons.
First, the price. Each pack of 4oz cost
$7, with the only way to buy a pack being a
four pack for $28 plus. Then of course, shipping and handling
fees. Basically, $28 for 16oz of
cookies. Expensive? Yeah, definitely. Then the other
reason for the criticism that ties directly into the pricing is
that these cookies were very quickly discovered to be a slightly different version
of an existing snack that is sold in Costco called Totes
Midnight cookies. Now, these were already criticized by some people for
being expensive, although nice, and they were $10 for
14oz. So for like a third of the price, you get almost the
same amount. So there you go. That's the whole drama,
at least the initial part of it, that shouldn't have really been a big
deal in the first place. Basically, people were accusing her
of ripping off the brand. Now, obviously,
multimillionaire didn't rip off a well known cookie brand. She just worked
with the creators of those cookies creation foods to
make her own version with a slight change up in formula and with her own
packaging. This is commonly referred to as white labeling, and sorry to be
the bearer of bad news, but this is how a lot of things are made,
especially influencer products. So basically, this drama is
that the cookies are similar to all the cookies and more expensive.
If this entire story ends there, obviously I'm not going to talk about it and
I'd basically be sleeping, because realistically, no one should care about
any of this. Influencer products are always going to be more expensive because
you're buying something almost exclusively for the name brand behind it to
support them, at least to begin with. Later on, maybe the product
stands on its own and takes a life of its own away from
that brand name, but at the very beginning, you're basically paying a premium
because it's from the creator that you watch. Otherwise, why would you buy them in
the first place? You can probably get good cookies at a local place.
Why would you need to get these? So them being expensive is
not that much of a drama, in my opinion, other than to say, oh,
greedy influencer millionaire wants to earn more money for
their greedy influencer millionaire lifestyle, which waters
wet, I guess. So this was kind of confusing to me to see everyone going
too crazy about it, because this is just another thing that they do.
Obviously, nobody's ever seen an influencer version of a product having
unique value or being a lower cost of a generic brand. That's just
not real life. So as a content creator myself, when I saw
this going on, I thought, Pokemon's been around on the Internet for
such a long time, doing this job for such a long time, she's just going
to ignore people talking about the price, clarify on the fact it's not a
ripoff, and move on with life, continue to just earn her dragon's
horde of wealth like she's been doing for the last five or so years.
Life goes on because obviously, as a multimillionaire sitting
in a mansion, why the fuck do you care if people are complaining about things
you do on the Internet? It just doesn't matter, does it? But obviously, Pokemon made
me the classic mistake of addressing a controversy that she had
no reason to even acknowledge, and in doing so, revealed how ridiculously out of
touch she is with reality. Like, oh my God, $28 for cookies.
Now let me first explain to you that you absolutely do not,
as a multimillionaire influencer, ever, ever talk
about money. Nothing you say regarding finances or money is going to be relevant
to 99% of your audience. The audience who literally made you that money,
by the way. You don't have their problems with finances, you don't live in the
same world as they do, and you've likely been so far away from that world
for such a long time if you ever lived there in the first place,
that you're entirely out of touch with it now. So don't pretend to have money
struggles. Don't talk about how much money you have. Don't flex the amazing new
lavish things that you've bought or done. Just leave the topic alone. No good can
come from it. Ever. Pokamine, however, looked at
people talking about her product, most of which were not her customers in the
first place, and decided to address the whole situation with a broad stroke
of nothing but stupidity, essentially shitting
on every one of her audience who shared the criticism that the cookies
are too expensive by calling them broke boys
for not wanting to buy her expensive influencer marked up products
like if you're a broke boy, just say so. Anyways, moving on.
And of course, this is the same energy. You're broke,
you're fucking poor. Now, before we continue, just for context, here is
another clip of pokey talking about money and how much of it she has.
Why would I compromise my morals and ethics
for more money when I have money? Something about that is so cringe
to me personally. Obviously people started digging around her VODs and
finding things, and the broke boy shit immediately set fire to this whole situation
simply because Pokimane thought the best way to address criticism is to make
broad statements about anyone making that criticism. What made
this all worse is that instead of just understanding that this was a glaring mistake
and being a human being with a response to the shitstorm, Pokemon tried to style
it off as a joke, when clearly anyone
who has a functional brain can see and hear that this is
not a joke, it's her actual feelings on the topic. To say
this is a joke illustrates either she doesn't understand what a joke is,
wants to gaslight the entire population that does know what a joke is by saying
it is one, or is going with the stupidest PR move
possible when there's a real easy alternative. All she had to
do at this point was to say yes, sorry guys, been getting slammed
on social media over this and I was frustrated. So I made a remark that
I shouldn't have done, and upon reflecting on what I said, I understand it was
wrong and I shouldn't have conveyed my thoughts in that way. My emotions
just got the better of me, a super easily understood human
response, instead calling people broke boys and then
saying Lol, I'm actually joking. Ha. XD it
doesn't really work, does it? Now that's all I'm going to say on the whole
Pokimane what she said and did. Instead, I now want to talk about the
Pokimane Defense Force and the elephant in the room. So buckle
up, because this is where it gets wild. A Twitter user, and I believe
also a Twitch streamer, posted this in response to the
backlash about Pokimane, not the cookie drama, but of course
when she called her audience broke boys for not buying the cookies.
It says essentially that because some other bad content creators
who do bad things don't get dogpiled for doing so,
people doing it to Pokemon for a slightly less bad thing are sexist
and checks notes hates women.
Now obviously this tweet is patently false
in every single way, and aside from the fact I can read the words that
are there in English and understand what they mean, it makes no real
sense from start to finish in any other way.
Firstly, the content creators she mentioned are some of
the most criticized creators on the planet. There are literally
hundreds of videos about them, and some of these creators are actually deplatformed
off most of the big social media sites. The idea that those people aren't
being criticized for their actions is so wrong that in order
to think so, you would either need to be unaware of who they are in
the first place, making their example useless,
or to ignore this fact in order to build a lie about
what comes next. The framing is that people are criticizing
Pokomane purely because she wants to sell cookies, which, as far as
I'm aware, is a straw man. I've not forensically analyzed
every account on social media in existence, but I've also not seen
any highly upvoted, liked, or retweeted posts that do this.
People criticized her for the price and for the white labeling that they likely
didn't understand, and not for the simple fact that she wanted to
sell cookies. If she said I'm going to sell cookies, and people went oh
no, that's really bad, you shouldn't do that, that would mean they were criticizing the
choice and not the fact that people said, oh, they're too expensive, which means
they're criticizing the price. Obviously both of the points here that
are made are already wrong, but both are only there to prop up this
idea that to criticize someone for something is inherently sexist
just because they happen to be a woman for the sake of things.
What is sexism? It's prejudice or discrimination based on sex.
So she's saying you can't have an issue with what Pokimane said
unless you hate women, which obviously is not how any
of this works. Now I will also say, just because this is a
real thing, there are a lot of sexist gamers and a ton of people who
will jump on any bandwagon against any woman for
any reason because they are sexist. And that does exist.
But that doesn't mean the actual core criticism means you
are being sexist. If you use that core criticism,
there will be sexist people who jumped at this opportunity and got involved. But that
happens regardless. And labeling real complaints such as this as
sexism does nothing but harm people who do experience real
sexism based on their gender and not on complaints about a human's
actions. And to illustrate that this isn't based on sex, you only have to
look so far as any other content creator in history who has been
criticized for similar practices, XQC flaunts his wealth by sending
pictures of his expensive watch to H three h Three during
their disagreement, and of course gets rightfully, utterly shit
on by the internet for being an out of touch clown about money.
XQC responds to criticism about him making money, reacting to war
footage, tweets a picture of him holding money to his
ear with a suitcase full of cash. Again, complete criticism
from pretty much everybody for him doing this. Logan Paul
sells Prime, you know, that drink that all the kids go wild
for, and he of course gets utterly shit on when it's being overpriced
in shops. In fact, you only have to be a content creator
to know there's a vocal portion of everyone's audience that will utterly destroy
you in your comment section or anywhere on the Internet for anything.
When it comes to making money, sponsors, merch products, anything you
do, this is a common thing. For whatever reason,
people don't want you making money. And if you make something and it's
expensive or more expensive than other things, despite the fact you probably don't
have all the infrastructure built up to make them cheaper in the first place,
people will criticize you. It doesn't matter who you are, what you look like what's
between your legs. This is nothing to do with gender, never was.
So basically, we can add this to the list of things people turn into something
it isn't, in order to push their very clear bias and agenda.
Apparently no one can have legit criticisms about something someone does nowadays
without it being some form of prejudice or hatred if that person is
a certain group, a concept that only harms when people experience
actual prejudice for real reasons.
So realistically, this whole thing was a complete non issue until Pokimane
made it an issue and started doing something she should have known better than to
do. She's been a creating house for close to a decade, I believe. She's been
through so many controversies and posted hall of Fame YouTuber apology videos regarding
the things she's been caught doing, so it should very much confuse you when she's
getting caught up in something so clearly stupid. It's a
classic case of letting your ego get in the way, something that these multi millionaire
influencers seem to be incapable of escaping. But then again, I guess
that's why people like Elon Musk buy Twitter. When you've got all the money in
the world, what else do you have other than your vanity? But there
we go. That's how Pokimane turned an absolutely nothing burger
into an indulgent family feast.