Hey, guys, it's Will. And in this video,
I'm going to share with you what I would do to make
ten K per month ASAP if I had to
kind of start again from scratch. Now,
what I'm going to share with you is, well, it made me multimillionaire
about 90% of the millionaire,
of the millionaires that I know, this is what made them a millionaire as
well. And it is
for many people. They just kind of don't know about this yet. They don't even
know that this exists and that they can actually do it
and how easy and simple and fast
it actually is. Right. And I'm going to share
that with you. I'm going to prove that to you in this video. So keep
watching. Right. And let me explain. Now,
the thing that prompted me to make this video was
I had coffee this morning with woman
downstairs in the cafe where I live.
And she is, I won't say kind of her exact age,
but let's say she's between 40 and 50 years old, lives here
in Dubai, and she makes roughly 14,000
pounds per month. So I think that's about $16,000 US,
something like that. So let's use dollars.
So she makes about 1516, $17,000 a month
teaching knitting.
I'll say that again, 1516,
$17,000 a month teaching knitting online.
So the way that she does this is
she has a small YouTube
channel and she posts two videos a week
all about, like, I don't really know a lot about knitting, but like knitting patterns,
where to buy the materials and stuff,
stuff like that. Right. And she's been doing it for about
nine months now, 910 months.
And it's not the most money in the world, but to a lot of people,
that's like life changing, isn't it? To most people out there
who are making two, three month in a job that they hate,
imagine making 1516,
17,000 per month consistently,
reliably doing what you love and just helping other people.
This is the best part about what I'm going to share with you here.
Like, it's very high integrity,
it's very high respect because you're just sharing
your knowledge and people will pay you to learn
what you know that they don't yet know. Right.
So I had coffee with this woman this morning and
she explained to me what she was doing. YouTube channel. She has a free
group as well. Let's just call it a Facebook group.
It's on this platform called School Skol.com.
If you don't know what that is? School is basically Facebook groups,
but better. Okay? You can sell products in
there, and it's just like Facebook groups, but better.
So she has a YouTube channel, she has a school group,
and she has an online course where
you learn everything to do with knitting, right?
And it is nine nine five.
So it's like $1,000. And she's selling about
15 of them a month. 14, 1516 of those a month.
1000 each. 16,000. And she's
been doing this for almost a year now.
It just made me think you really can teach
anything, whatever people would pay to learn, which is
most things, because of every
niche and every industry, there's just
one or two or three or 4% of people that will pay to
learn to do it very, very well at a very high level.
So for every hundred people, let's take
stopping drinking alcohol, because one of my friends has a very successful
company teaching how to stop drinking alcohol, and he makes multi
six figures a year, hundreds of thousands of dollars a year teaching
that, just selling an online course.
So let's take stopping drinking alcohol. Well,
98 out of 100 people might just want
to try and stop on their own, or maybe not stop. Maybe they like drinking
each to their own. But one or two out
of every hundred people might really want to stop.
They need some help. Along comes my friend, and they pay him.
I think he charges, I think six,
six and a half
think it's six and a half thousand that he charges for
his, like, stop drinking alcohol program. And multiple
people every month invest in that training. And here's the
thing, like, you only need at that price, you only need,
I mean, two people a month is like $13,000.03.
Four, five people a month. And you're up there in the multiple five
figures per month. And I
know a lot of people. In fact, pretty much. Pretty much every
single one of my friends does this sells information.
And I mean, God, the least amount of
money that any of my friends makes is like 80,
90,000 a month. That's like the least. I've got a couple of friends
who make upwards of three
and a half, 4 million a month, a month
doing this. In fact, one of them, Cole Gordon,
recently spoke at my mastermind. You can watch his talk here on. On the YouTube
channel. When he did that talk, he was making 3.9 million a
month teaching people how to become sales reps.
And here's the repeating pattern, that I
see people learn something first,
and then they just teach it to other people. So I've got friends that sell
everything from like how to stop drinking alcohol,
how to get a six pack, how to buy and sell items on
Amazon, how to become a barber. I've got a friend that sells
how to become a barber. He's doing over one hundred K a month. I think
he's doing more like almost 200 a month actually teaching people
to become barbers and cut men's hair. I've got friends that sell
trading education, and that's what made me a multimillionaire.
I learned to trade, then I taught people to trade, and that
made me almost $20 million. So trading how
to invest in real estate is a big one as well. How to source
deals and sell them to investors, how to actually invest in
your own properties. I've got a friend
that sells how to make ebooks and put them on audible.
And you don't even want to know what he's making. If I told you,
you wouldn't believe me. You would not believe it's multiple millions a month
that he's making. I've got friends that teach how
to get commercial cleaning contracts,
hire someone to do the work for them, and they stay at home and just
make a little bit of the profit. So they might get a job for 1000,
get someone to do it for 600, stay at home and keep the 400.
I've got friends that have how to buy and sell luxury watches
online course, how to start an agency again,
Cole Gordon, how to become a sales rep. Like any
knowledge that you have, you can sell.
And even if you don't yet have knOwledge, you can learn knowledge and
then sell that as well. And this is like the fastest, easiest way
to make minimum, minimum, ten K a month.
Minimum. Like ten K.
It's tiny. In this industry,
ten K is not even the hygiene standard. And again,
the recurring theme is usually that the people I know that
do this, eight times out of ten, they have a skill that
they've done, then they teach it. So I just
started working with a guy recently who teaches people
how to play piano for $3,000
for his online course and coaching program. And you have access to
that for three months, one call a week with him, and he's doing
really well, over 100,000 a month teaching people to
play piano. And again, here's the thing.
For every hundred people that want to learn piano, 95,
six, seven might not have a budget.
They want to learn themselves through books, through YouTube, and that's okay.
That's okay. And then there's just the one or
two or three that think to themselves, you know what? I want to work with
a professional. I know how important it is to invest in
yourself and in knowledge to learn what you want to learn. I want
to shortcut the learning curve, and I just want to learn to play
piano at a very high level ASAP.
Those are the people that will pay the $3,000 that he charges and
three clients a month. Three, six, nine. You're pretty much
touching on ten K. It is so easy.
Selling knowledge is the fastest, easiest way to
make money on the Internet that I know of.
Truly, I've done it myself. The vast
majority of my friends have done it as well. Again, like nine out of
ten millionaires, multimillionaires that I know sell their,
their knowledge to get there. And here's the thing as well. It's a very high
margin. Like, the profit can be as high as
95%. So there's a lot of great businesses
out there doing a lot of money, but their margins are 5%,
15%, 25% selling information.
The margin is 80%, 90% as standard.
This is why people get rich kind of so fast.
And coming back to you, the person watching this video, you can either
teach a skill or a talent that you have right now,
whatever that is. Maybe it's football, maybe it's barbering, maybe it's fitness,
maybe it's music, maybe it's trading, maybe it's
starting a brand, a clothing brand, or an agency.
If you build an info business correctly,
you price your product correctly, you sell the product correctly, on and
on and on.
Right now, the money is waiting to be picked up
and put in your pocket and put in your bank. You just have
to learn how to do it,
and it's really not that hard. And even
if you don't have a skill right now, you can just learn
one. So let me give you an example that one of my mentors once
shared with me. So he said,
let's use golf as an example. Now, I've never played
golf in my life. So on a scale of one to 100
is me, Tiger woods is ten.
Right? Now, if I want to learn to
play golf and I want to learn properly and get their
ASAP, I'm going to have to hire a coach. I'm going to have to pay
someone for their information and training.
Now, I don't need a ten out of ten. I don't need a seven out
of ten. I probably don't even need a five out of ten. I just need
someone who's a few steps ahead of me, someone that's like three on the knowledge,
knowledge scale. So if
you want to teach golf, all you need to be is a three. You don't
need to be a ten, you don't need to be a seven, you don't need
to be a five, you just need to be three,
four, because I ain't going to have a clue what I'm doing.
I'm a zero, remember? So I just need
a two, three, four to teach me in some format,
right? So if you're watching this right now and you're thinking,
oh, I don't have any valuable skills or talents,
number one, you probably do, you just haven't thought
about it properly yet. And if you truly don't
just learn something, it's not hard to
learn piano.
One, two months of books, of YouTube, of this thing,
of that thing of practice and you're going to start to get good
with enough time. Same for me. I mean
I learned myself to trade financial markets and then after a
certain period of time one of my friends actually asked me for help
and then he offered to pay me for my help. And I was not a
millionaire trader, I was just doing relatively
well. I was probably like a three or a four
on the knowledge scale and he was a one and he wanted to get up
to a four so he paid me and I helped him get up to a
four. That's it.
So you don't have to be an expert.
You can be a three that teaches zeros, you can
be a five that teaches threes, you can be a seven
that teaches fives, you can be a nine that teaches sevens,
that kind of thing. So it's
not hard to do this and if you just want to make ten K a
month, I mean that's not hard. I've worked
with people in the past. In fact, the commercial cleaning guide that I
mentioned earlier, he came to me and said, look, here's what
I'm doing, can I teach this to other people? And within
about 810,
twelve weeks, he was already at like 30,000 pounds
a month teaching that,
the highest month that he's ever had. I think it was a couple of months
ago he did about fifty K. Fifty five K.
So I mean, imagine earning 55,000
pounds from home just teaching people
what you're good at, what you know how to do.
Like what impact would that have on your life, on your family's
life? You could buy the car that you want, you could buy the watch that
you want, you can go on a holiday that you want, you can even travel
whilst doing this because it's like location independent. That's why
I moved to Dubai, because one of my dreams was to
live in a hot, sunny country. I was like, I can do that. So that's
what brought me over here. Tax, of course, is 0%.
Tax is very helpful. I'm not going to lie. That was part of the decision.
But it was those two things. Number one, the weather. Number two,
the tax and selling information. You can do it
from anywhere. You can do it from England, from America,
from Thailand, from Australia, wherever you.
So it can be
done. And I dare say that I'm one of the best in
the world at doing this now. I mean, I've made almost $20 million doing this.
I've won awards for making all the
money that I've made. I've worked with some of
the best kind of people on earth that do this. Like Sam
Ovens, Alex Becker, Cole Gordon, Alan Sultanik,
Dan Bradbury. And I've been in this
world for almost a decade now.
And this is how I've made my money. If you
look at me here in Dubai, living in the building that I live in,
living the life that I live, it all came from selling information.
And it is not hard.
It's not hard to do. So let me explain kind
of how to do it. So I've told, you know, you can
either teach a skill that you have or learn a skill and then teach that.
I've told you about the different kinds of skills that can be taught. Making ebooks
and selling them on Amazon, teaching people to become sales reps,
teaching people to trade, all of that stuff.
So stage number one is skill. Stage number two
is getting attention and showing people that
you have the skill and
from there, kind of building, well, not even building an audience.
I mean, there's two ways to do this. Number one is you can build an
audience on Instagram, on YouTube, on Twitter, whatever you
like, or you don't even have to do that. You can just run
paid ads if you have the budget. You do not need a website,
you do not need a brand or a reputation or a personal,
big, shiny Instagram, you do not need it. I've got
friends that do not have a personal brand. No one
knows who they are. They've just got ads into a sales process,
into a sales call. They get on a call, they explain how they can
help, and blah, blah, blah, and clients come
on board. So if you think that you need a personal brand, you categorically
do not. You categorically do not. If you've
got a brand, helpful, if you have an audience. Oh,
my God. I mean, if you've got four, five, six, 7000 followers on
Instagram or more, you should be making tens of thousands a month.
If you've got a YouTube following of above 510 thousand subscribers,
you should be making multiple tens of thousands a month. Same for TikTok,
same for Twitter. It's so easy to monetize an audience and
sell them information, or you can run paid ads
and all that you do is you just ask people if they need help.
That's it. And this is the part that I love about doing this, because again,
it's very high integrity, high respect, and it's very valuable.
By sharing information, you're adding a lot of value to the world.
You're helping people that want the help and can't find the help and you come
in and give them the help. Right?
So that's part of the reason why I love it, because you can have a
big impact on people's lives. Some of the clients that
I've helped in the past, I mean, I've made three or four or five people.
I've actually made them over a million dollars through working
with them. And some of their testimonials
are here on the YouTube channel as well. If you haven't seen the testimonials,
please go and watch them. And don't trust me, ignore me, go and listen
to the people who will tell you how much money that
they've made by
doing this. So again, the steps are decide
on a skill, generate attention,
ask people for help, speak to them,
and if they want to learn from you, they buy
and they give you money. And if they don't want to learn from you,
that's okay. Those are the steps,
right? Skill, attention.
Ask if they need help. If they need help,
then they exchange their money for your value, and you
very quickly make money. And again, ten K is so easy.
The price is, you should be charging at least. I mean,
the lowest price that I know of personally is the
lady that I had coffee with this morning who's only charging nine nine five.
I actually said, that's way too low. But she's comfortable there. She's happy
with the 1516, 17,000 a month that
she's making. She likes to live a calm life,
do her thing. She loves very, very, she's very passionate about knitting,
loves teaching people, people love learning. So it's just awesome.
What a great way to live. You do what you love, you make really
good money doing it, and you help people and add value and
impact the world. If that's not the best thing ever, I don't know what is.
And that's what I do now as well.
So the main thing that I'm doing at the moment is
just helping other people to do this. So people that are
already selling information but they're not making as much as they should
be, I help them get it right, scale up,
implement systems and operations and whatever needs to be done
to get them up to month, one hundred K a month, quarter of a million
a month and beyond, like I've done myself. So the people I work with right
now are either doing this already and they want to scale or every
now and again I help beginners as well. So if
you have a great idea for a program for a course,
then you can book in a call with me at the link in the description.
By the way, we can jump on a call, we can chat about this some
more and I'll give you some feedback, some guidance. And then if you want
my help, I can coach you one to one and help you scale up
and get this thing working, or I can just kind
of add some value for you, answer some questions, and at the very least,
even if we don't work together, you've kind of got a free coaching call out
of it anyway. So yeah, for any of you that
are doing this already and you want to scale, or if you're not doing this
yet and you would like to book in a call with me at the link
in the description,
and the last thing that I will say is this, if a
woman, I'm not kind of discrediting this lady,
but she's going to kill me
for saying this, but if a random woman that's
like in her kind
of late 40s can make 1516,
17,000 a month from home teaching, knitting,
then you can probably make five or ten K per
month. And if you're very good at what you do, then you should be making
one hundred K a month, a quarter of a million a month, half a million
a month and beyond. And I'm a big believer
in karma. And I think if you truly help people and
add value in the world, you get rewarded.
And you get rewarded in a big way by
making a lot of money. You can do great things in your own life
as well. Buy yourself a car, buy yourself a big
house, go on a holiday, fly first class, that kind of thing.
So everybody should have the ability to do
that. But anyway, so I really hope that helps. Guys, if you have any questions,
thoughts, comments, put them in the comments section below the video,
I'll come straight back to you and lend a hand. I made this
video just to help you guys inspire. You guys add some value.
And hopefully, if just one of you goes on to do
this and make 1020 30 40 month, then I'll have
done my job. And again, if you need any help with that book in a
call with me, I'll jump on and lend a hand and make
the money that you deserve to make. Because life is too short to be broke.
Life is too short to not achieve your goals
and your dreams. So cheesy, but true.
I'll wrap it up here guys, and I'll see you in the next next video
soon.