And so right now, I have $2 billion paths. What's the worst case
scenario if you do anything that damages your reputation is irreversible, because you only get
one reputation, and you literally can't bankrupt yourself out. Fuck it.
One of the hardest decisions in entrepreneurship is deciding which path
to follow, especially when you have two or multiple good paths. I'm at
a point in my career where I do have a very large decision that I
need commit to for multiple years, and I've been spending basically every waking
hour trying to gather more data to make the right decision. One of my favorite
things to do when I do have big decisions is to change my environment,
and I think it happens multiple times. My favorite place to think is actually on
planes. I often have very few distractions when I'm on planes, and I
quite literally get perspective. Like, I'm flying up and I'm looking down
at the Earth. I feel like I always make really good decisions when I'm in
the air. And it's actually something that, like, really look forward to,
you know what I've been waiting for since I've been married? Going to Chili's.
We've gone to Chili's. I had, like, a seizure. Honestly, I would
go because I don't mind. I don't care about the style of the restaurant,
but I do not like their food. I think they have amazing chips, great salsa,
and the Fajitas are strong. I hate that you go hard on this in front
of people, because then behind the closed doors, you're like, yeah, it's not that good.
If there's any time, like, in the fine establishments that I go to that we've
gone to now, like, five times, we'll go. And she'll be like, it sucks,
right? It sucks. Say it. Say it. It's not as good as
the finest dining in the world. Just say it. I'll be like, yes, it's not
as good. She's like, see? And then that's it for the rest of my life.
Your chili's chin, you get, like, a stomachache from it. And then you're like,
who are you talking about here? Who are we talking about?
I think you're telling me your story. So we just landed in San
Diego, and we are going to reels event,
which is a big publicly traded brokerage for real estate agents.
Our really close friend, Sharon Srivatsa is the president of the company.
He invited us out. We're probably going to have dinner with him. We're going to
speak there tomorrow. I will be making a presentation to help real estate
agents sell more houses. But it will not be about real estate. It'll either
suck or be great or somewhere in between. Leila's like, I'm just,
how do I stop doing all these routines? I'm like, I can't even start.
I, like, tried to smoke cigarettes to get addicted to them, and I was like,
it was too hard. It was just too hard to stick with it. It's like
every morning, it's like what I forgot.
The hardest part about growth is that the better you get, the bigger
you get, the bigger the opportunities are and the better they are. I think the
easiest litmus test is to determine how big of an opportunity is
worth your attention. So right now, ten X is kind of my litmus test.
Like, we're at 100. It's got to be a billion or more for it to
be something that I want to dedicate time to. And so right now, I have
what I would consider to be $2 billion paths. They're very different.
Relatively irreversible. One has potentially more upside but more
risk. The other one is more certain but has lower upside. There's lots of things
that can make a decision irreversible if it's a certain percentage of your net
worth or capital. I don't like making those kinds of bets. This is a quote
from Sean Sarvata, budy of mine. He said, never want to bet the Empire for
a pot of gold. You bet what you have and need for something you don't
have and don't need. It's never a good bet. Anything that damages your reputation is
irreversible because you only get one reputation. And you literally can't bankrupt yourself out of
a bad reputation. You can't take reputational risk where
there's only downside. Now, if I were to say, like, I want to support this
cause, I might piss off some people, but it'll move me towards a different
group of people. So then in that case, that's a trade off more than it's
a risk. And so that's different than what I'm talking about here.
And then you just have time that you can't get back.
Every moment you spend always has the opportunity cost of what you could have done
with that time to get a higher return. I think the number one presentation I
have on YouTube is about that concept is the only base thing we
have is time, and we make trades for
stuff. And so the people who are better at trading it for more stuff get
more stuff. There was this story that Tony Robbins told that. I really liked that.
Just kind of illustrated this image is that rich people make bets
where they can't lose on either way. So there's this guy who knows that nickels
nowadays are made with nickel or whatever. The material they make nickel with is
more valuable than the cost of a nickel. This billionaire knows has taken the nickel.
He's putting it in storage as an investment, because the day that they change or
remove that nickel from currency, because it makes no sense, he'll melt it
and get 40% on his money. But there are investments that are high
return, low risk. You want to find those bets. How's it going?
You're good, man. What's up? I'm a Treasury founder.
We just find banks in the US that literally pay the highest rates on cash.
Well, give me your card. I don't have a card. Here, take a picture of
me and message me. And then the guy who managed my LinkedIn will get it.
There you go. Oh, we got to get a good lighting. There it is.
Do it right now so I can tell him. Yeah, if we can get more
return on our cash, we're in a hot zone. A hot zone of recognition.
What's all, like, entrepreneurial people? Looks like it. Let's let this gentleman
know. Half measures. That's right. He knows. I'll tell you that story,
man. We're running gym launch, making a lot of money. I got asked to speak
at this personal trainer conference, and I was like, yeah, sure, I'll talk.
I wasn't being asked to speak. I wasn't making content like this. It wasn't like
a normal. I was like, sure, I'll come talk. And I was like, so what
do you want to do? He's like, well, I figure you just give a lot
of value, and then you can present your thing or whatever. And I was like,
okay, cool. I made this really long presentation that was just like,
very, very good. And then at the end, I had the full presentation webinar of
how to sell it that I used to sell it before. And I was like,
you guys probably don't need to see all this stuff, right? Like, okay, you get
it. It's important. You got to know how to sell,
got to understand the systems. At the end, I was like, yeah, and here's the
price. And I dropped it. And I was like, I just went as fast as
I could through it, and I said it like I'm saying it right now.
I didn't actually say it. And so then I revealed the price,
and so I did what would have been a 90 minutes presentation pitch in like
15 minutes after giving 3 hours plus of value. So I was like, this should
make sense. I gave a shitload of value, and then I'll just soft toss it,
right? And I got so much resistance from the crowd. It was
the biggest flop of a presentation I've ever given my entire life. I think I
made two sales like it was nothing right now. I had done a half measure.
And so it's either sell or don't sell. Don't be in between. You either give
value or you sell shit. Don't try and mix them. If we want to make
commitments in anything, or you're trying to go all in on a decision, one of
the best ways to do that is to eliminate the possibility of going back on
it. A lot of people will spend most of their lives being half in,
half out, which to me is just not in at all. It just gives them
an excuse to feel like they're making progress when they really aren't. There's a lot
of books that talk about going pro, going all in, burning the boats. And I
think they all kind of go along the same point, which is that sometimes you
have to make a bet and be willing to be wrong, knowing that if you
make no bet, you're guaranteed to be wrong. But, yeah, for tomorrow,
everybody there knows more about selling houses than I do. And my proof point of
that is that they have all sold more houses than I have. So what am
I going to teach them about selling houses? Right? I think it would be silly
for me to try and compete on that, because there's other speakers who've both done
it and been there more than me. So I feel like that'd be a terrible
position to take. What I am going to do is say, if I were
to start here, is how I would win. But if selling houses means winning,
it'll apply. Michael,
nice to meet you. Sorry, my hands are cold. I appreciate it. Dude,
you're killing the game, man.
Nice to meet you, too. Riley, right? See you guys. When I was
in high school, I read this book called how to Make Friends that influence people.
And I think the second chapter or something is call people by their name,
their favorite word in the whole language. And I was like, oh, that's interesting.
Your favorite word, it in the entire language is your own name. So you love
hearing that word more than any other word. Well, I should say that a lot
of times if somebody likes that word, think about this from a leverage perspective.
If you haven't seen somebody in a year, and then you show up at
a conference and you're like Steve, and he doesn't remember your name.
He loses all leverage. You're the good guy. And so
you have so much more leverage in the conversation for remembering. Thank you for calling
reservation center. I got to see if I can get in there with
a tank top and water sandals. Thank you for calling Steakhouse.
Amy speaking. How can we help you? Amy, how are you today?
Hello, Amy. Okay. How are you? I'm good. Quick question for you.
I have reservation at 730. What's the dress
code? We don't turn anyone away unless you're wearing the following
board shorts, swimsuits, and tank tops.
Well, if you've never turned anyone away before, then I might just have to risk
it because I can't go back to my hotel in time.
Okay. I'm going to say Amy said it was okay. Yeah, no problem.
I'll get that sent over, Though, and let them know you should be okay.
Thank you so much, Amy. You're a lifesaver. Thank you. Like that with the ice
cream. So we're on our way to an ice cream shop, and it's closing.
Like, at the time we're about to get there. Layla, she was like, we should
call to make sure that we can get in. And I was
like, hey, how's it going? And my wife needs ice cream
or I'm going to be in the dog house. I was like, what are the
chances, one in a million that you guys can stay up in five minutes later
so I get some ice cream. I was like, I'll be in and out.
I'll be the fastest ice cream man you've ever seen. And they were like,
okay, but you just can't tell anyone. I was like, I will take you to
the grave except for this content that I'm making right now.
And she let us in and we got the Sundays. I've done of
phone sales, and I've done a lot of in person sales. And there's a lot
of mini skills that you learn in sales that are useful in every other
environment where you need to get people to do something that you want them to
do. The ideal way of doing is getting them to want to do the thing
that you want them to do rather than having them feel like they are doing
you a favor. The way that you ask, the tone that you ask, the laughs
that you make, the jokes that you make, all of those micro things,
I do those things so that the person on the other end feels
like if they see me in person. It will be a positive experience,
and they want to have that reward. And so they are willing
to push or bend the rules a little bit so that I can do whatever
it is that I'm trying to do or get in or restaurant or dessert or
whatever it is. People do nice things when they're in nice moods.
So it's like, get them in a good mood first, then ask for the nice
thing.
You made half the presentation last night. Yeah, I kind of have this process
that sort of works. I'll outline what I'm going to say
far in advance, and then the day before, I'll change half of it.
We get the VIP entrance. Okay.
And then we noticed that your presentation. 300 plus slides. Yeah,
I finished it, like, 20 minutes ago. Yeah, it looks good. Looks good? Yeah.
And if it doesn't, I'll survive. Okay.
Usually I get more of my adrenaline now, and by the time I get on
stage, it's like I'm done with it, kind of thing. It's always directly proportional to
the prep. Yeah. This will be the first time I've talked about any of this
stuff that I'm talking about in a keynote.
I love this tall boy. Dude, this is great. Get a little
bit of sugar, a little bit of caffeine, a little bit of
delicious, and a little bit of bucket.
How many people? 350.
I had 100 sides.
I have 300. Oh, my God. 300 slides. I'm looking forward to it.
Oh, thank you. You ever done a real estate audience? No, I don't think so.
I don't talk to real estate agents. It's going to be useless for them.
They'll be like, what a waste of an hour from
my friend Alex.
Hormones already
know how to win because you know how to lose, so flip it. You guys
know how to win better than I could ever tell you. You measure your success
by whether you completed the actions that would make it unreasonable that you
will not fail, and then you succeed by default. And everyone here has
things that they've written down from many of the talks of things that you want
to do or want to think about or whatever. I would encourage you to make
that a list of things that you will do. And then when you go
back to the same condition, your same home, your same house, your same market,
your same whatever, you change your behavior, and then that will show that
you learned and you took one step to becoming the person that you ultimately want
to be.
This step is all top of mind in terms of making actions that
would make it unreasonable that I fail with a billion dollar decision just because that's
actually a decision I'm making right now. I'm at a point in my career where
I have enough what I would consider singles, doubles,
triples, that I have decided to take a
bigger swing. I'll either win or I'll learn, same as you.
So from the bottom of our heart, Alex, you impacted our life. Thank you,
man. We appreciate you. Thank you, guys. Thank you. Thank you.
All I want to do.
Dude, you can be 100 X you. Stop it. Thank you, Alex.
You're good. Chris, very nice to meet you. Appreciate you,
Katie. Appreciate you. Photo with you and Katie? Yeah, sure.
Rat bro. Since you had about 50,000
subscribers. Yeah. In fact, here to see you.
I'm going to earn that hat. I'll go wear it someday.
Thank God. I love seeing Mosi Nation in the wild.
I love the hustle. I love everyone coming up and sharing their
stories. That always makes my day. I would say, though, do it in a place
where you won't get put in handcuffs for sneaking in.
Come up when you see me in public if you can. I'm happy to say
hi, take pictures, whatever. Don't go into areas where you're not supposed to go in
order to try and hang out, because it usually just doesn't end well.
The crowd is loving you. Very nice to meet you. Thank you so much.
Appreciate it. So that was great. I did my keynote earlier in the day.
I think people liked it. They may not have. I think they
sat through it regardless. And I think we're probably going to have the afternoon,
probably a couple of hours. Probably walk around, and then we'll head back to Las
Vegas. Kinisi Sitas,
see Asimo's content.
Yep. Everyone.
Back in the day when I had one on ones, there was a one
guy who I was like, so what have you done for
personal improvement? Have you done? He's like, yeah,
it was so crazy. I realized if I don't watch Netflix
as much while I'm working, I get so much more done.
I was like, there's so many things wrong with that statement. You were telling me.
Probably just like, just. Level one of idiocy.
Level two of idiocy is that you mentioned that you
were watching Netflix in general while you were working .3 Is
that you didn't actually say you were going to stop. You just said that you
cut back on how much Netflix
you were watching while you were working. And I was just like, there's so many
stupidities interwoven into so few words. I was flabbergasted
so you're more productive when you don't watch Netflix movies?
Not as much. Yeah. As much as many shows in
a row while you're being paid at your job.
Yeah, it's been great.
That's pretty. That is pretty. Oh, damn.
So if you're at the crossroads between one decision
that you're trying to choose between two different paths, if it's the first go round,
I would encourage you to take the lower risk
path that has a higher chance of success. If it's a business, there are
stories of just unbelievable entrepreneurs. But what you don't hear is the tens
of thousands of entrepreneurs who make that massive bet and then lose
everything and lose five, eight years of their lives. If you are
going to make the big swing, and kudos to you, it's an absolutely personal decision,
burn the boats, go all in, fully commit, eliminate alternatives. No half
measures. Because what I can guarantee you is that if
you are going after the big swing, the way to guarantee that
it does not work is to go half in. So if
you're going to win, make it unreasonable that anything that was in your
control was not controlled for, and then only lose for things
that were not under your control. What do you think? Top five for me,
I'd go Matrix all time. I'd be willing to put Dark Knight as number two.
It's just like he's such a good villain. It's just like he was
just the perfect villain. The intro scene is just like one of the all time
best scenes ever. I really like an oldie,
but I do like Gladiator Russell Crowe. You have one
that's not, like, action heavy. Probably my favorite comedy. Fuck.
Not too hard. 40 old virgin Wedding Crashers. Super bad.
And surprise bridesmaids.
I cried during bridesmaids. It's like I couldn't breathe. I was dying.
Yeah, I mean, I went because a buddy of mine at the job that I
was at was like, let's go see it. And I was like, bye. So I
had a couple of drinks and went to the movie theater, and I was hyperventilating
because I couldn't fucking stop laughing.