I went undercover for 24 hours to try and make as much money as possible
just by editing. I created fake profiles on the most popular
websites for finding editing jobs, all in an attempt to prove that
anyone, no matter who you are, can make money editing.
How much, though? I'll let you find out. Yeah. Damn, dude, I just
got paid. I just wrote. Yeah, like you.
It's time to go. Let's do this. First thing I'm going to do is start
up a new account on Discord. Discord is one of the platforms
that we're going to be using a lot of because I know that there are
a lot of editing servers that offer jobs. So let's make an account on
Discord. This meant logging out of my Finzar account and beginning the brainstorming
process for a new username. I wanted to go for something that was unique enough
to catch an eye, but also generic enough to seem trustworthy,
which is a tough balance to create with just a name. Now, I'd thought about
many names, but only one stood out to me. One that was still boring,
but kept catching my eye. Darren.
Now all I had to do was create his last bopper.
No, no, it's gotta be professional. Darren.
Darren.
What's like a cool job? What's like a cool job? That, like a blacksmith.
Darren Smith. Smith. Darren Smith. With Darren Smith
as my new alias, I now had to brand this new metahuman
and give him a face. And believe me, ladies and fins, in the early stages
of selling Darren as an editor, a lot of the success will come down to
the way I do this branding. So I went into Photoshop, where I
then used the new generative fill AI feature to create a
face for Darren Smith.
Look at this guy. This is a really important step.
We need to make it look like he's a real person and not like a
stock image. I don't know, man. Like, who is that? Oh,
that is up. Oh, no, I can't say that. And after a couple minutes skimming
through options, I finally found him. That is Darren
Smith. And with Darren Smith created, I then went on to make him a discord
profile. He needed some meat on his skinny little bones, and what better
way to do that than to make him a show reel? Something to show off
his editing skills and catch the attention of some clients. Looking pretty good for
time, I jumped into Premiere Pro and began making the show reel using
my animation preset pack. Baby. They come with these PNG images, which I'm
going to animate quickly. I'm just going to literally just use my preset pack.
This whole pack is actually dedicated to animating PNGs like this. Doing this
kind of thing is actually very desirable on YouTube, and I'm hoping that someone will
see this and think, I want that done. I've been looking for
someone to do this for my videos for ages, so I think it's pretty desirable.
And after only 15 minutes of editing, I had finished the animations that
I wanted to put in the show reel, and this is what they look like.
Wa There is a reason that
I'm going to spend a while doing this, and it's because this really matters.
When it comes to showcasing your work and getting a job. People want to see
that you can do audio well. People want to see that you can do their
transitions well. It's all about making people feel like they can just totally trust you
and what you're doing. And after 1 hour and 40 minutes of editing,
I had completed the animations, transitions,
subtitles, and audio design, and it was looking good using my nice transitions
pack. It's pretty cool. Man, that did not look good. Oh, and I did
use voiceover for this show reel, which I feel gives it some more personality
and trustworthiness. And thank you to my cameraman for doing that,
even if he sounded a little bit like a robot. Hi, guys. My name's Darren
Smith, and this is my show reel. These are some of the transitions
that I could do for you. With the show reel complete and with 2 hours
eaten away, it was time to upload my material and begin spreading myself around like
the bubonic plague. That's right, baby. I was going low to
the far depths of low. The lowest I'd ever gone. I was dming
every single person, posting jobs that I could see. Not only that,
but copy and pasting the same message to every single one. No wonder
this happened. I want to look for more jobs, but the
thing is, Discord is limiting me from applying to jobs because I haven't
had an account for over a day, so it's slowing down every single DM I
sent. So with my spamming on Discord, I had been stopped in my tracks.
I also set up a quick Twitter account to search for jobs, but also ended
up hitting the same obstacle there. It turned out that being too keen of
an editor on the first day was a bad thing. So all I could do
now was wait for something to come back to me.
And at 525 3 hours and 25 minutes into
my time doing this challenge, I received the first promising message of the
day. Yo, yo. Someone might be one of them. To say I was excited would
be an understatement. Hello, beautiful editing. It's nice to meet you. I know.
I mean, no. Oh my God. Hey,
thanks so much. Nice to meet you.
Play cool. Play cool. Play cool. We might have a job. We might have a
job. Maybe. This is actually quite exciting. My morale.
Morale. Bump it up. I myself edit as well.
I just can't really find much motivational time to do it. And since I'm
distracted and supposed to be editing right now, I'm on Discord. And after even that
little bit of chat, I was suddenly skeptical. Where's this going?
Maybe they just want a little chitchat. So instead of wasting time, I asked
for work. And while I waited for a response, I checked out the channel to
see what I might be up against. Let's watch one of his videos. Whatever color
I spin, be void. Whoever touches the forbidden color,
which is the videos on his channel, were roughly 15 to 20 minutes each with
moderate editing, including subtitles, zooms,
memes, meme sound effects, and slide transitions. Now, all that,
for me, is actually fine. As an experienced editor, I know that the most
grueling part of editing is cutting up and pacing the video, which takes
the longest to do and requires the most motivation. This kid wants me to finish
all of that shit. And so, feeling like a 20 minutes video
with all of that editing might be a bit too much of a task to
take on. With only 20 hours left, I decided to look around some more
and see my other options. And whilst I was looking, I received quite a few
more messages from this guy Ori. And at this point, just kind of seemed like
maybe he wanted to chat. He's just having a chat. And Darren, being the gruff
editor that he is, has no time to waste. So amidst the
chitchat, I ask him how much he'll pay. His answer is, first, a bit confusing,
but promising nonetheless. He's willing to pay $30 to $35
per hour of work. Now, to me, that's a really good deal.
But there is that part in my brain which actually thinks that he's willing to
pay that much per hour of footage, which, if it's a 20
minutes video, would only give me $10. And that's not good enough.
It's nearly 06:00, which means that we've been editing for almost
4 hours straight. So now I'm just going to let this breathe for a minute.
Because I've been applying for a lot of jobs. Hopefully we're going to get at
least one response whilst we're away. And then prepare for another 20
hours of this. All right.
While Finn searches for a job. I'm going to go get us some pizza.
And I guess I'm paying for it because Finn can't afford anything right
now. Because he still hasn't made any money.
Hang on. Thanks, cameraman. Let's hope
that discord has got some treats for us when we get back.
We got nothing. We didn't get any messages back.
And so it begins. I accepted the job with Ori and downloaded
the files immediately. First job on the DL download
time was 717. And Darren was roughly 5 hours into
his editing challenge. Ori has sent his footage. And I finally had something
to dig my editing teeth into. Having received a few notes from Ori
and a snippet of the editing style he wanted. I got on with cutting up
the raw footage. Now, as I kind of pre warned you earlier.
I know that the most grueling part of editing is cutting up and pasting
the video. Cutting up that raw footage is the most boring part of the whole
Process and the most time consuming. So let me make this a little bit more
fun for you to watch and summarize the next 14 hours for you nice and
quick with a list of the major things that happened. 753 I
received an exciting message request. Hey Darren. I've come across some of your work
and thought it was really good. Definitely do with your skill set on team.
Let me know. Thank you. Which then turned out to be a complete dud.
836 Ori requests to see progress clips.
840 Give me some chocolate. My cameraman fed me chocolate.
918 Ori prods me again for clips.
927 I went for a quick walk.
1015 Darren gets his first subscriber on YouTube.
And we made the mistake of looking at the subscribers channel.
You want to see it done. But you got to give Darren time.
Okay. 1138 and I shit you not. Ore has asked for another preview.
Yep. I think I'm going to ignore this. 111 48 Master
Chief steps in. What do I do? Chief Finzar.
You are editing really well. Do not give up. But also your
ass stinks. Wait. What? Your butt. It stinks. What do
you mean? You need to hurry up and edit. That's what I'm. You need to
do it faster. That's what I'm doing. I'm getting bored. Edit faster.
Finn. But how? Fine. Put me on your head and
he'll show you. Okay? All right. But I don't know if I'm going to be
able to see that well out of. Just shut up and put me on already.
He's a little bit rude, but here we go.
Ow.
1228 I finished cutting up the project and start adding zooms.
I finished cutting up the project. Now I'm going to add zooms for
the whole 15 minutes.
1230. My cameraman goes to bed. Good night.
Cameraman. You go to bed. You go sleep well. Okay? And I'm all alone.
I'll be okay.
For the next 2 hours, I edited nonstop until the zooms
were done. And I was happy with the pacing. And at 230, I stopped for
the night. It's 238. It's time for me to retire. I'm tired.
Look at that. Yeah. I got to go to sleep now and
actually save myself so that I can work well tomorrow. Right?
Good night.
For 5 hours, I slept as good as humanly possible. A blEssing,
really, but also a curse. Think I might have overslept.
Yep. Indeed I did. So I hurried myself up and got straight back
into the office. No breakfast, no shower, nothing.
Pretty grim stuff, guys. My cameraman
arose too, and within ten minutes of waking up, I was off again.
I hate to be this guy, man. Hate, hate to be that guy. Bunny a
cough. I go where I'm making the money here.
I began with sound effects, which was as simple as doing all of the transitions
with whooshes, highlighting funny character moments with cartoon sound effects
and a few too many bras. Bra. I don't know why, I just
thought it was Wieners. Bra. 1030 by this point, I'd been
roughly editing for 14 hours straight, minus sleep
and breaks. The thought of seeing the finish line at this point felt extremely
motivational to me. But even still, with over 3 hours left,
I was struggling. I had to channel the inner editing Beast and Power
on. Got to keep going. There is absolutely no way that I'm coming out of
this with no cash. Even if it's less than I hope for. I have to
finish this project. 1138. I started the subtitles.
Luckily, I wouldn't have to do much as the intro has already been edited by
Ori, which is where the main bulk of subtitles would be needed. All I
had to do was cover up the bits that were unintelligible and where it's most
comedic. You have to. For the next 2 hours. I polished,
scrubbed, wiped, and cleaned up that timeline like never before.
It was like that Disney movie Soul Darren had completely taken over
me and I was in the zone. As the time came
to an end, I managed to finish the video within half an hour of the
time limit. Okay, video is finished, and we got half an
hour left. I got to actually start rendering, otherwise I might miss it. I slapped
it on Render as soon as I could, and now all I could do was
wait.
Rendered. With the video rendered quickly, I uploaded it onto Google Drive to
center. Ori, look at the time limit. We got 32 minutes left.
You can't make that up. You cannot make that up. All right. I think by
this standard, we're going to hit it just in
time. And with the video uploading, just with enough time to make it, Ori finally
gave me a solid answer on how much he was going to pay me.
He wants to pay me $33. This challenge isn't over
just yet. I think he means per hour of footage,
which is annoying. Essentially, Ori had planned to pay me for
every hour of footage that he sent me.
He sent me about 50 minutes worth of footage, so in his eyes,
it was worth $30. But Darren isn't going to give up that easy.
I pushed for a better price, and I got $50 for the whole thing.
It wasn't much of a bump, but it was something. $50 for 9
hours of work? Nine and a half. 50 divided by 9.5.
About $6 an hour. It's not as good as $30 an hour, but it's
something. This is just the reality of editing. When you start up on the first
day, I mean, I wasn't expecting to find a $500 job.
It's just how it be. If I was Darren Smith and
I hadn't started a YouTube channel, I haven't done anything. I had zero
experience, and I just got $50 for, like, 9 hours of work.
It's not great. I don't know, man. It's $50. I can't be unhappy with $50.
It pays for the pizza. Pays for the pizza and the Discord membership.
And we got, like, a little bit of spending money left over. The tiniest bit.
And with that wrapped up, the upload to drive had finished. Time to send it
to Ori, and by 02:00 exactly, I'd completed the challenge.
The timing really was immaculate, and we managed to just about squeeze
everything into the 24 hours. But what's even stranger is that
I got paid exactly at 02:00. $51 from
Ori. I just got paid at 02:00.
Honestly, I don't think you could get a better ending than that. Damn, dude,
I just got paid. Are you getting. Tell him your fins are. Yeah, we got
paid. Let's go spend this money.
I don't know on what, though. Will he, A, buy another pizza, B,
buy a medieval foam sword, or C, match the monies that you made on this
challenge and donate that to charity.
Get out of here. Go away now.
Bye. Shake just a little bit faster.
No competitIon.
Shake just a little bit faster.