See this? This is what dropshipping gurus
like to call a winning product. A hundred thousand dollars in sales
in one month, and almost $200,000 in total. I'm going to
show you how I did it so you can do it as well. So pay
attention. What is this product and how did I find it? I don't know if
I can say it on YouTube, but it's a roller for your Zar,
your cheese, your grass, your dunk,
your Wakita back. And the way
I found it was with my TikTok Banner account. For those of you who don't
know, you can force TikTok to literally show you whatever you want. So what
I did was I made a new TikTok account and I only searched for
dropshipping products. So now, anytime I go on that account,
all I see is dropshipping products.
And at the beginning of this year, this account called copper roller was
blowing up. If you had a banner account, you would have seen that product.
But for some reason, there weren't that many accounts running it. So I looked
into it and I found out why at the time, if you search for it
on Aliexpress, you wouldn't be able to find it. And if you are a beginner
at that point, you give up because you think there's no way you can actually
source it. So because of that, and. Cause it was too controversial,
like, I didn't test it, but like, three months later, my winning products
were starting to die out and I was getting desperate. And I also found
out that you can just give your supplier an Alibaba link, or even the
TikTok video link, and they might be able to source the product. So I ordered
it and I made two new TikTok accounts. Zawheel.
This is a UK account. It has a UK SIM in it and
the Zarwheel Co. This is a US account.
And for the first four videos, I literally just copied the copper roller guys
videos, filmed twice edited, twice posted on both
phones. And the videos were already starting to show potential, like 40K
views, 40K views, 20K views. But nothing was going viral. So in
that case, usually what I do is try and add a slight twist to the
video. So I use my banner account to make a fake
comment. That ain't no broccoli roller. So the whole angle was that
I was using broccoli and cheese to hint what the product was actually for
without actually saying it. And you know how there's always that one person that just
ruins the surprise and admits what it is? Yeah. So I was trying
to play off that and spark some emotion. And this is
what I came up with. You people, if this video gets demonetized, it's your fault.
You'll see. That ain't no broccoli roller. Sir, I have no
idea what you're talking about. This device is strictly for cooking
broccoli rolls in the oven. There is literally no other purpose.
So anyways, I made a few of those videos, and the third one started
picking up on the US account. It went from forty K to fifty K
to seventy K to one hundred to two hundred K. And at that
point, I was at 300 followers. I already made the Shopify website.
So I just typed my website link in the description.
This was June 23, and from 200K
views, I got almost $500 in sales. That's just from
people going out of their way and typing the website link in their browser,
not even just clicking a link. And the next day, just before the video hit
1 million views, I reached 1000 followers. So I was able to put my
link in there. And that day, I got three K in sales.
This one video got to 3.6 million views and it brought $18,000
in sales. That is crazy. Usually I get like
one to two K in sales per million views. This is what happens when
you have a product that is super controversial and that people
really want. It goes viral quick, and the sales are just crazy.
But it also comes with plenty problems. The first problem,
community guideline strike. Yeah, you can't promote these videos
on TikTok. So they took down the video, and on the 27th, you can see
the sales dropped like crazy. The second problem,
account ban. See this TikTok is wicked.
They'll wait for you to start to see some small success, and then they'll
just start banning, banning, banning, banning, banning all your videos one by one by
one. And I think after about seven or eight banned videos, they will just
shut down the entire account. And that's what happened to the US account. And that's
why I'm showing you screenshots for it. But the UK account is still there.
So anyways, that was June. This was the first week
in July. What happened here,
Mikey? How did you do that? Well, let me
tell you. Look, you guys, you don't listen. I keep telling you, Instagram Reels
reupload your TikToks to Instagram Reels. I know a lot of
you guys have this problem where you try to make a new Instagram account and
you instantly get banned. I think I might have a solution.
It's not properly tested, but I tried it on two iPhones and two Androids
and it worked. So you guys can try it. So log out of all your
Instagram accounts except one. That one account should have some
views on it already. Then on the login page, go to the settings and
delete every account except that one. Then go
to your phone settings, general storage, Instagram,
then offload app, then delete app. It's the same for Android.
Just clear the cache and delete the app. Then reinstall it and
make a new account. But choose the complete sign up option.
Then add a profile picture, share as post,
and that's it. Please don't come for me if it doesn't work, but still
try it. It should work. So as I was saying,
Instagram Reels look eigth July.
33 million views. Seven K
in a day. 20K in a day.
14K in a day. Ten K in a day. Shopify payment
hold in a day. So Shopify held my funds
and put it under review, not because the product was controversial,
but because the sales came so quickly. So it was just like a standard review.
But the thing is, the product could have been considered paraphernalia
on Shopify payments, which is not allowed. So I asked my mentor,
Michael Benstein about it, and he was actually concerned. And if you know Michael,
you know he's never worried about anything ever. So the fact that he was telling
me to actually take it seriously, it puts me on higher list. Because apparently
if one big payment processor bans you, you can be blacklisted
from all the other major processors. PayPal, Shopify,
stripe, all of them for like five years. It's not a joke.
So if you are running these kind of controversial products, don't use Shopify payments
or PayPal or any of the major ones. Check if they allow this stuff.
Me, I immediately turned off PayPAl because I didn't want any problems. But I
had to keep Shopify payments on because I didn't have any other alternative. So for
almost like two weeks, I was going back and forth, back and forth
with every single high risk payment processor that exists
in this world. Most of them didn't even reply. Most of them disqualified me
because I don't have a US business. I wasn't getting anyone to take me on
until my friend recommended me. This one called we transact.
They saved my life. But the catch is that because it's high risk,
they take 10% of the sales and hold it for
six months just in case you decide to do some shady stuff and not fulfill
the orders or something, but it's fine. I'd rather that than to be
banned from Shopify. Shopify. Please, I beg you. It's for broccoli and cheese.
Also, this is not sponsored by Wetransact by the way. So anyways,
now I found my new winning products, so now it was time to scale.
And usually what I do is just make new accounts and just post more,
post more volume, volume, volume. But for I don't even know how long.
Michael just kept telling me, telling me to hire people to film
for me instead of me doing all the work. If I would be a one
man show, I wouldn't be able to sleep at night. I see how
much money you will lose by not having another person in your team. You have
no clue how much money you're leaving on the table. If you
double the output, you're going to get double the resUlt.
So if you have a person who replicates what you're doing, you're going to make
double the money. This guy is trying to make me spend the money that I've
suffered to end. Anyways, so I mentioned I was hiring in one of
my previous videos and some of you guys signed up and I started working with
like three or four of you. So now, on top of me posting TikToks,
the plan was to manage creators. Every day I had to give them
two video ideas for them to film, edit and upload. And I was paying each
person $1,200 a month, so I had to
make it work. But for almost an entire month, like nothing was working.
A couple of the creators crossed 100K view videos, but none
of them really went viral. So now, at this point, I lost money on that
investment. But obviously they weren't the problem because they were just doing
what I told them to do and I was just making them copy my old
video ideas over and over and over again. I wasn't really doing anything
different, but one day I remembered this video that I saw a while
ago on TikTok. This is the sapax. Just remember, it's only intended to
be used for aromatherapy. First, I find a pine cone with
a lot of sap on it. I scoop the sap off the scale of the
pine cone and scrape it into my glass jar. I keep scooping
and scraping until my jar is filled with sticky, icky sap. Then I
drill a half inch hole into this stump that I like to meditate at.
I take this glass sculpture I got from a sculpture store and put
it in the hole. I take a big old scoop of sap with the sap
axe and then set it aside for later. Using my creme brulee torch,
I heat up the glass sculpture. I ready the axe while the glass cools
and then dab the sap into the middle of the glass sculpture.
I waft the incense over my face and give thanks. I set the sap
axe aside, contemplate life, and prepare to repeat the process.
This has over 14 million views. When you see a video like this,
you really need to pay attention to understand why it went viral.
Obviously, he was doing the same thing I was doing by pretending it was something
else. So his video didn't get taken down. But the whole vibe of
the video was just different. The pacing was slower, so it kind of
got pushed to an older audience. The background was just beautiful.
His voice was calming, nature sounds, blah, blah, blah.
I don't fully understand it, but like watching the video, you can just feel the
vibe. So I tried to replicate it as closely as I could. I found a
relaxing voice on play Ht. I filmed near some
lake near my area. I slowed down the pacing and I ended up with
this video. This is the zaw wheel. Just remember, it's only
intended to be used for cooking. First I take my
mozzarella and carefully place it into the zaw wheel.
Now I close it and twist so it packs the sticky,
icky cheese evenly. Then I add some baking paper
and twist again until it disappears into the zaw wheel.
Now I can enjoy my tasty mozzarella sticks.
You see how the vibes are kind of similar? I don't know
how to explain it, but you get what I'm trying to say. This video of
mine got 2.2 million views. And that's where the second spike in sales came
from. At the end of July with a ten K day. And because of that,
I ended up doing my 1st 100K month. Crazy,
crazy. So now all I had to do was just get the creators
to replicate the same video. So I made each of them copy the same
video at least five times. It didn't really go viral for the others,
but one of them got almost 10 million views.
And he brought this huge spike in August, which is over $30,000
in sales. So of course we had to have a Zoom call. Yo. Hello.
How are you doing? I'm doing good, I think you, with the
10 million views, brought like 30K in sales. Really?
Yes. Yeah. I put like five creators on it.
I think you were the only one that made the Zawi work.
Okay. And the funny thing is, everyone else had an iPhone and you were the
only one that had an iPhone. Yeah. Be honest. How was
it like working with me? Because you are one of the first
few creators I've had. I mean, for me, it was very
easy. You told me what to do, and I just did it. You pay
good. You're saying I'm the best.
Who's better than you? I don't know.
How long do my videos take you? Like, in a day? In a day?
Maybe like 2 hours. Maybe 2
hours? I'm done. 2 hours and you're done for the whole day.
You don't do anything. It's bad. I was hoping that
it would motivate you guys because you've gotten 10
million views. Doesn't that give you some kind of hype? You've generated 30K
in sales. You have seen that it's possible, so you
should be on it. You do realize
that this is why people don't make it, right? The fact
that you're not putting in the work, you feel lazy. You feel that is
a huge factor. It's not that it doesn't work. It's that people
just don't try. I'll be on it. I'm telling
you now. So, yeah, Noah made me back all the money from the creators.
So it was definitely worth it. I'm not going to lie. It's very hard to
manage creators. But that's the game. So, yeah, June,
July, August, I made $176,000.
And before I show you the total,
quick side note, you guys, I beg you. You guys are making me
an enemy to the black community. I've realized that sometimes when a black person goes
viral on TikTok, some of you will just be commenting. Is this Mikey? Is this
Mikey? Is this Mikey? Don't get me wrong, I think it'sick that you guys even
know who I am. But when you do that, the videos get
pushed to other dropshippers. And because of that, they don't make much money
from their viral videos. So I beg you, please stop. Also stop replicating
the silent basketball videos. Yes, it was me. And even if you go viral
with those kind of videos, you won't get sales. So anyways, in total, almost $200,000
in sales. I don't know the profit right now, but I'll put all the maths
on the screen. Please don't just watch my videos and do nothing after.
Go and film TikToks. Please. Good night.