How you going? You know what's always annoyed me about being Australian, and everyone around
the world keeps making fun of us for it. That we don't have
the ability to shoot fast projectiles out of a moving vehicle.
But today I finally can, as Clash of clans asked me to make this
expo from the game that can shoot a two kilo arrow
over 600ft, all while moving on top of my car.
Alright, it turns out I'm not the first to do a sponsorship for Clash of
clans. And ancient civilizations like the Romans and French copied
the expos from the game and made them out of wood using primitive technology.
But they had a funny way of pronouncing expos. They called them
blisters. And I was going to copy their designs, but as far as
I can tell, they were really, really tiny and I want
something bigger and more impressive. Also, I've decided I'm not going to copy
anything about their designs, as the Romans were all idiots. And I've
got something they didn't access to spearfishing stores that
stock overpowered rubber bands made in factories in Shenzhen.
The Romans did, however, have access to beards and massive
parties, which I don't. So we'll find out if that affects its performance.
So this is the plan. The rubbers will run along the side of this square
tube, and I'll have some bearings on the front which the rubbers will come over
and then get pulled to the back with a winch which has a quick release,
which I made in my last video. Now, the point of these bearings on the
front is that if I just had the rubbers tied to the front of the
expo, they would only start providing pull force to the arrow here.
But with the bearings, you can pretension the rubbers and allow them to speed
up the arrow until the very end of the muzzle. So we should get
more power. But I also don't know. So the first thing I did
was turn down this big block of aluminium in the lathe and cut it
into these housings for the bearings, which are less comfortable
than the houses they are used to living in. But now the bearings nicely fit
the rubbers. Then I just put them onto the side of the rail. Next,
I attached the winch on the back and I went for a hand winch
as it feels more historically accurate, and I like the noise it
makes and being able to feel the tension of the rubbers getting harder and
harder to pull back, and the suspense of each click bringing me
closer to the rubbers snapping and taking out my eye,
which I just wouldn't get with an electric winch. And you've probably noticed
that the frame is already painted and you haven't actually seen me
weld anything together or make anything. I'm just re welding
over welds. And, you know, in that previous shot of me turning down
the housing for the bearings in the lathe, that was a lie as well.
And it was actually just a can of beans in my lathe.
And I just lied to you. Again, it wasn't even beans. It was actually a
can of tomatoes. But why do I keep lying to you?
And you might be thinking, I'm doing this because I don't want to show you
the horrible conditions that the three children that actually made this
frame work in. But that's not it either. It's because making stuff like
this always takes so long and is relatively boring. So my mate
and I actually made all of this and just didn't record it.
And now, in an attempt to make this whole video longer and show the process
on camera, I'm just doing extra unnecessary work.
So next, I just pretended to do some more welds, and now comes the
really hard part where I need to pretend to make the whole bottom half of
my frame that attaches to my car, which my mate Rowan already made.
And now it's done. Well, functionally done. It needs to look more like
the expo from Clash of Clans. But first, I really wanted to do some
test shots to find out if this even works in my yard in the
middle of a populated suburban city. And for anyone that's about to write a comment
getting angry at me that I'm testing a ballista in a populated area, let me
just remind you that I have a ballista that may or may not
work. So we decided to test it first with one rubber
in an attempt to build up suspense. But first, to build up even
more suspense, I'm going to tell you a little bit more about the sponsor of
the video. Clash of Clans. An ongoing event, Clash for nature.
Clash of Clans is a super fun strategy game where you build defenses, upgrade your
base, and attack other players. And since I announced that I'm in the event,
everyone has been raiding my base non stop,
who keeps killing all my guys, and I
keep losing, and people keep raiding me. Clash of Clans has an
ongoing event named Clash for Nature, which is almost reaching the
end and will be having a significant update coming up right after the
release of Town Hall 16. In Clash for nature, there are two teams. The charity's
team trees or Team seas. And if you see my last video, you'll know I'm
on Team trees. All your ingame actions during the event will lead to planting
trees and removing trash from the ocean in real life. Any of you can join
the event right now, even if you haven't played Clash of Clans before, you just
scan my QR code, and then you get gold through multiplayer battles and
looting other players'bases. Just don't loot my base,
please. And whichever creator and community that loots the most gold will win
a Tesla and other prizes. And I'm currently ranked fourth in the Clash for nature
event. And if we win, I'll get a bunch of prizes I can give to
you guys. Also, I just want to stop Papa Plate from winning,
so go download Clash of Clans now. Okay, back to the test of the expo
with one rubber.
Ready? Three, two,
one.
That sucks. And that was not very impressive.
So we put on another rubber, and I also forgot how to do countdowns.
Much harder to pull back.
3232,
how was that? And that looks significantly quicker, which is good,
as it's going to be even faster with a third rubber. So we put that
on and also attempted to shoot it through the chronograph so we can get some
speed readings and then compare it to the Romans. And we can also compare it
to the speed of the Expo and Clash of Clans, which looks like it's going
very fast.
Oh, you need to turn the chronograph on.
Hold on. Yeah, point it.
Turn it on. Ready?
Three, two.
And that was way slower than I was expecting. The maximum speed we got
was 22 meters a second. And apparently the Roman ballisters could
shoot a 400 grams bolt at 90 meters a second. The bolt
that we're shooting weighs two kilos, though. So I cut it down. So it
weighed 400 grams and gave it another go, which might make it five times
faster.
One,
three.
2136.6.
And my first shot was 36 meters a second, but I think I know how
to make it faster. You know what I said earlier about Romans having an advantage
because they have beards and engage in other activities? So I
thought my mate Rowan should have a shot.
Put your face shield down.
Thank you.
And Rowan's was suspiciously faster than my shot at 38 meters or
130ft/second and that's not 90 meters a
second fast like the Romans. But it's still pretty good considering
the Roman ballistas that achieved those speeds had a draw weight
of 5000 pounds, while our Expo's draw weight is only around
500 pounds. Don't ask me how that's possible. I really don't know.
But then I realized something. How did the Romans know how fast they were shooting?
They didn't have chronographs or Gavin from the slow Mo guys,
so I think all the Romans were lying. And the same with the French.
Especially the French. Okay, now it's time to
make this look like the level ten Expo from Clash of clans, which we
did by covering it in foam. And this may surprise some of you because you're
stupid, but these limbs here don't do anything. Neither does this foam on the front
or this aesthetic string.
Sorry. That does. And now you're probably looking at this and thinking,
Alex, which is my name? This looks a bit like the level ten
Expo from Clash of clans, but how is it going to shoot magical bolts and
auto lock onto targets and then auto reload, like in the game?
Well, it's not. That wasn't in my budget. And also, that's impossible. And you were
just going to have to play the game to see that happen. It will hopefully
still shoot and look really cool, though. Okay. I think
my neighbors are preparing for siege warfare, so it's time to take it out to
Hamilton's farm and do some real tests. Also, this is
obvious, but anyone watching, especially people living in syracuse
in the fourth century BC, don't put an expo on your car or
try any of this at home. And we're going to do a couple of different
tests, like a penetration test on this car door that I stole from an undercover
cop car. And also shoot this historically accurate Spartan suit of
armor.
And this armor is a good test. As in the game, the expo can be
used against troops like Pekka, this giant guy in a suit of
armor. Then we'll have a distance test and an accuracy test,
and then finally a drive by test, and whoever gets the most
points wins. Something I haven't decided yet.
Ron, do you think we should do a range test first?
Yeah. See? Distance. Yeah. Okay. It's a good way to lose a bolt.
Yeah, but then at least. And then we only have to shoot two. Yeah.
Perfect. It's great. And also, if we do a destruction test first, we might up
the bolts. We might destroy them.
I was going to say we can have a competition, but it won't really be
a competition, because it's just going to be who can wind it back the furthest
and tilt it at the lowest angle. Exactly. All right,
let's do it. Okay. First, I wanted to know how far it can shoot,
so we loaded up the small bolt to do a distance test.
Face shield. That's what I forgot. I almost brought some fencing helmets.
Maybe I should put this on. I should, then. I can't see. No, you put
it on. No, I'm not putting it on. Okay.
All it's going to keep my face away from it.
God. Three, two.
Holy. Two.
Holy.
That was pretty good. That was pretty good. The Fletching was weird, and that
acted really weirdly in the air with the duct tape fletching
that I put on. And also one of the rubbers snapped, but even with that,
it went over 120 meters or 300ft.
So we put on another rubber and took off the Fletching and tried again.
321211.
Similar distance. And I thought that flew a similar
distance, but it turns out it flew a lot further at around 160
meters or 520ft, but that was measured by my
steps and I am slightly biased. And also, the steepest angle
I could get the expo to was, like, 15 degrees because of
how I attached it to the car. So if it was at 45 degrees,
the bolt would go much further. So now we're going to try the expo up
against some targets and see what it does. And Rowan was up
first.
Yeah, it's comfy up here. See, our point system we're going for
here. What's worth the most? So there's three of us shooting.
I think if you pierce the armor, you get
three points. If you just pierce a mannequin, you get one point.
If you miss, you get minus one. And if you get through the car door,
four. Okay, so you can just choose. What were
those points again? Points again. Don't ask me that.
It can't hit me if you aim it down to me right now. Right.
What are you aiming for? I'm going for the door. He's going for the door.
He's a four pointer. Or maybe I want the Roman. I don't know.
There it is.
I have no idea. Three, two,
one.
I missed. And he didn't account for the drop of the heavy
bolts and shot low in between their legs. So he's on zero points.
And next was Alexa. Can you open this door,
Mulaney?
Yes. That's exactly what I wanted.
This feels amazing. Yeah, this feels so good.
And I feel awesome just being at the. Yeah,
I feel so powerful right now. I'm going to go record on this guy.
Don't.
What are you going for? I think Alex,
go. Is it go? No, you go. You can go
more.
You can stop. Three,
two, one.
What? Does that count? As I took his pants off,
I did exactly what I wanted. And somehow Alexa
took the guy's pants off. And I don't even know how many points that is
worth. Probably nine. And now it was my turn, and I
was feeling the pressure to hit something. What angle were you shooting
the Ballista at? Yeah, I'm not telling you.
Work it out. You built the thing. I don't
know what I'm aiming for. It's okay.
Still got it. Springs. Okay.
Can you go furtHer?
Nice. Sorry.
Sabotaging me, Roland. Oh. What, did you lock it in?
Nice. Zero, minus one. Minus one. And two
of the rubbers broke, and it didn't go very far, so I was on minus
one. Okay, so after Rowan and I spent an hour retying
all the rubbers, we moved the car closer and had another shot.
Yeah, I'll go for man. No, I go for the car door. No, I go
for man.
Three, two, one.
Yay. Whoa.
Whoa. What?
It didn't hit right on it.
Just fluid. Yeah, that's going to destroy your windscreen if it flies off.
And that bolt hit sideways and bounced off. And this is all very
hard. I'm starting to think that expos and Ballistas aren't the best
siege weapons or I'm just horrible at making things. And unlike
the game, where the Expo automatically locks onto enemies, we were having
trouble hitting anything. So I moved the car a little bit closer
and took aim at the Spartan guy.
Think that's just going to bounce straight off, actually. Two,
one. Oh.
Whoa. Straight through.
Finally, mate. Alex. Amazing aim.
Thank you. This is all we had from that.
I know.
Oh, my God. Yeah. Don't touch him.
Did you aim for his heart?
And that was pretty impressive damage. It only stopped because the bolt
got wider and it almost went all the way through broadhead into him.
Yeah, it'll absolutely go through that.
Poor guy. So then Hamilton's mate had a shot at the car door.
You winded it all the way.
Three, two,
one. Whoo. Did you get it?
Yeah, it went in maybe.
Oh. Whoa. What? Holy.
Dude, that sliced through so easily.
Look at that. The way I just, like, peeled it up. Peeled it
like a can. Just one. Oh, it must have hit this and
then pushed up.
And now it's Hamilton's turn to shoot the Santa guy.
Drop it lower.
Holy. Oh,
my God. In the heart again.
He's got a spear sticking out.
Okay, now, we know that the bolt would do some serious damage, but we still
don't know how easy it is to use while driving, so I tried
that. Whenever you're ready.
Yeah. Drive slowly next to them. I won't point it at you, boys.
Thank you. Yeah. Go slowly next to them.
Go a bit closer to him.
And that was ridiculously hard to aim, so I tried again.
You can go back.
And we couldn't find the bolt in the long grass, so we formed a search
and rescue line. And besides finding a body that Hamilton had
buried on his farm earlier, we couldn't find the bolt.
But luckily, on the way back, Alexis stepped on it, which is great,
as now Hamilton won't die while mowing his lawn.
Okay. We were getting pretty bored and sunburnt, so we told ourselves that this
was the last attempt.
Here we go. Get him, Alex. Yes.
In the neck. Oh, wait, I don't need to keep driving.
And that was extremely fun to shoot and did some great damage.
And as for which one of us wins my made up competition, probably Alexa for
taking the guy's pants off. And there you go. I think I did a pretty
good job of replicating that expo from Clash of Clans.
And Mayan actually had enough power to even take down armored troops
from the game. So go download Clash of clans right now
and scan my QR code and join the event to not only plant trees,
but also potentially win a Tesla and other prizes. And considering I'm number
four right now, we are pretty close. Also, a hot tip for new and
existing players. You should get the builder package for your town, and that gives you
the advantage of progressing quickly in the early stages of the game.
Good luck in the event. Thank you so much for watching. If you like
that, subscribe and check out some of my other videos.