In the early morning hours of October 7, 2023, the IDF's
930 3rd Nahal Brigade quickly jumped into their
brand new, untested Aton armored fighting vehicles. They raced
off from their quick reaction post in northeastern Israel. The column sped
at the breakneck speed of 120 km/hour
down Israel's Highway Six. Their mission?
Engage Hamas militants that had launched the terror attack
along Zekum Beach. The militants had amphibiously
infiltrated from Gaza in eight separate boats.
Four Hamas boats were destroyed immediately by the nine
16th Patrol Squadron from Ashad Naval Base before they
even reached the shore. However, the four other boats
successfully made it to the beach and started attacking the Kibutz and the Bajad
Four military base in what is now referred to as the
Battle of Zikum. Then the Nahal Brigade, in their atons, rushed to
defend the beachfront. They reportedly got there so quickly they were able
to take out the militants while they were still stuck on the beachhead.
But by 07:00 a.m. That morning, Israel had confirmed reports that
their Bahad four base had been overrun.
The Israeli atons immediately began to clear the nearby villages
on their way to the base. This is one of the main recruit training
stations for combat and noncombat arms for the IDF.
What that means is there was at least 90 Green recruits training
here at the time. Six IDF officers were KIA
trying to protect them during the battle that raged on for hours.
One recruit was KIA in the fight. Then the Aton
started to regain the upper hand thanks to its remote controlled 50 caliber
machine guns, which successfully forced the Hamas militants
to withdraw back into Gaza. An Israeli soldier who
participated in the battle said this we reached the area the
fastest. This is our first advantage. We ran
into terrorist vehicles and didn't feel anything. It's a powerful
tool. We broke through gates and fences. Then we helped
evacuate the wounded and supply the troops. It would
have taken much longer to prepare and move out with tracked
vehicles to respond in this kind of emergency situation.
In fact, the Battle of Zekem beach was the first time that the eight wheeled
vehicle was ever tested in combat, and it's actually still
just in the introductory testing phases at the IDF. The Aton
unit was able to do this without a single casualty. The successful
use of the vehicle prompted the head of the IDF ground forces, Commander Yachty,
to integrate the Aton into plans of the invasion of Gaza
Strip. Critics claimed that the vehicle wasn't scheduled to go into full
service for another entire year until sometime in 2024.
Many opinions started popping up on X Twitter that state that
the vehicle was, quote, prematurely rushed into service.
They claim that the high tech Aton was rushed into battle before they were ready
for the test. But what do some of its capabilities tell us about how it
might perform in urban combat? One Israeli soldier proudly
called it the Tesla of APCs because it's extremely high tech,
gives you a smooth ride. And I think he said it before all that controversy.
I don't know. I don't follow the drama closely. While there may be some truth
to it being rushed out the gate, they actually appear to be functioning well so
far. In fact, this article that I found from breaking Defense from October
4, just three days prior to the attack, shows their
exclusive walkthrough of the Aton Armored unit getting used
to the new system and training on it and running drills.
Photos released by the IDF themselves show the Aton
operating on the ground in Gaza in November 2023.
We can see this giant explosion plume in the background behind the
vehicle. Sometimes we would use an armored vehicle in a rock simply to take
cover in when we exploded unexploded IEDs nearby. Then we'd
jump back out. But the interesting thing that jumps out from this photo is
that the Aton appears to have been outfitted with Spike antitank guided
missiles and a 50 caliber machine gun. But those spike missiles
aren't going to be engaging enemy tanks. What they're designed for
in Gaza is to strike entrenched Hamas positions that
are behind concrete. Its 18 pound missile has a new penetration
blast fragmentation that's used to destroy enemy behind
cover. You might be surprised to learn that the 50 caliber machine gun can have
difficulty cutting through concrete. The second photo from the IDF in
Gaza shows us something interesting. We see a dismounted fire team of
IDF soldiers taking cover behind the Aton inside Gaza.
This is a common tactic used by mechanized infantry where they
advance alongside the firepower and protection of the vehicle
while dismounted. In the background, we can actually see what looks like the
turret of a Merkava main battle tank. The ATON is
specifically designed to operate alongside the Mercava tank using
their digital network system together, and the two are likely
protecting each other's flanks here in a 360 degree security
zone. Very important in urban warfare. One of the advantages of
this system is that it's reported to have a 1000 kilometer range,
or about 620 miles, before needing to be refueled,
which is about 120 miles greater distance than similar counterpart
vehicles. This allows you to stay in the fight for a longer period of
time. Sustaining operations in Gaza is difficult for
Israel because extending these logistics lines, even just a
few miles into hostile territory, is a tough job.
This is a classic quick reaction force mission,
and it's exactly the kind of response these relatively new
vehicles were designed for. The key characteristics of a quick
reaction force are speed, flexibility, and readiness.
What this means is that these vehicles cannot afford the luxury of being
a high maintenance vehicle. Part of the reason why the Aton was effective in
this mission is because it can carry twelve soldiers, including nine
dismounted infantry, a full squad that can rush out, and three
vehicle crew that stay on the vehicle to maintain a support by fire
position. The Aton vehicle is uniquely well suited for Israel
because it's designed to traverse mountainous terrain, environments that are
found in the Golan Heights. The reason wheels work in its favor
is because tracked vehicles on tanks tear up normal roads.
And ironically, they wear out much faster on a typical highway
than it would on an offroad terrain. This is why anytime
we see tracked vehicles deployed over long distances,
they're often loaded onto truck beds or trains. But that's
a slow and cumbersome process and doesn't bode well if
you need to respond to immediate threats along your border, like bringing
supplies to the front lines. And they're also great for evacuating
wounded troops. Quickly back to the rear. The new Iron Fist
active protection system found on the Aton armor could be
used as a screening force to knock down incoming RPGs and
clear a path for heavier tanks. The Hebrew name Aton
actually means steadfast or strong, which gives us some
insight into what type of capabilities they want to project with this armored
vehicle. But looking at the Aton, you might think to yourself, wait a
second. Isn't that just an Israeli version of the striker
or Boxer? Isn't that just a ripoff of the LAV?
Wait a second. Actually, why do all of those different vehicles look the
same? It can be tough to classify a vehicle like the atom,
but most people call it an armored fighting vehicle, as opposed
to an infantry fighting vehicle classification or armored personnel
carrier. All of these different things can be similar,
but they're usually distinguished based on its level of firepower.
But the visual aesthetics is where most of the similarities end.
Like the rest of their armored fleet, the Israeli Defense Force has
a unique set of requirements that set this vehicle apart from its
counterparts. But before we answer that. So the animations,
video editing, and research in this video was only made possible thanks
to this episode's sponsor, goat guns. But before you ask
me, no, they don't fire. Can you even imagine the lawsuits
if they did? I mean, just think about that for a second. But history and
military buffs, former soldiers and gun nuts alike, love getting
these one third scale mini model goat guns as a gift.
The thing that really blew me away was the working dummy rounds
that you can actually load into the magazines and the bolts that slide back just
like the real thing. Every detail has been faithfully recreated
to deliver an authentic experience. If you're looking for the perfect gift
this holiday season, look no further. From the iconic AR 15
to the classic AK 47, these miniaturized masterpieces aren't
just for display, they're interactive, allowing you to assemble and
disassemble these models, providing a handson understanding of firearms,
goat guns make a unique and impressive addition to any collection.
Click the link in the description or the pinned comment below to get yours
today. So why do all those vehicles look the same? The development of
the Aton incorporates decades of experience in hybrid
urban warfare that resulted in the most heavily armored
and technologically advanced wheeled Afe in the world. The Aton
was first announced in 2016, and then it was field tested until 2018.
I noticed something interesting about the interior here, so I had to interrupt myself
real quick. The floorboards on the bottom are much higher than on
the striker that I deployed with. It's clear that Israel has put
a lot of armor on the underbelly underneath the soldier.
Back to you, Chris. It took about five years to develop,
and it was only in 2022 that Israel selected the United
States based Oshkosh Defense to produce the hulls.
These were created at the Merkava factory at Tel
Hashmeh in central Israel. Although the production
is an international effort, since over 1 million individual parts
need to be manufactured and assembled, and 34 computers
need to be installed for a final product.
Currently, production of the Aton is spread across 60 separate
locations across Israel, so as not to put all their eggs in
one basket. All of its capabilities and design
features can be traced directly to problems with the one one three. In 1972,
through a material aid package, the United States donated massive numbers of
their old M One one three tracked armored personnel carriers to the
IDF. The Israeli Defense Forces determined that its operational
requirements were not met by the American APC.
This is because the IDF relies on a very aggressive strategy of
maneuver warfare. That means dozens of M One one three s found
themselves decisively engaged against the enemy. Now,
decisively engaged is a military term that means your military
force is fully committed to a battle with the intent of
achieving a decisive outcome or victory. It's the military
version of maximum effort. The problem is the one one three was
really only meant for a support role in the rear and was
often wiped out when it found itself in direct combat. The decision
to develop the Atom was based on one of the lessons learned
from an incident from the invasion of Gaza in Operation Protective
Edge in 2014. At the time, a one one three had a technical
error that deadlined it, so it was stuck. Militants took
advantage and fired an RPG at the downed vehicle.
Six IDF troops were KIA as a result of the catastrophic
vehicle loss. To remedy this, the IDF began creating a
series of armored personnel carriers, eventually culminating in
the creation of the Namair super Heavy APC. But tracked
vehicles are like getting a degree in interpretive dance. It only
gets you so far in life. While the Namair is a fantastically
protected and capable platform, they're mechanically complex and most
importantly, they're slow to deploy. So the IDF started to
evaluate fast moving, quick reaction force vehicles like the
American wheeled striker platform. Israel determined that the striker
was a cheap, knock off, off the shelf solution. The striker
was quickly rejected, with Internet rumors stating that one
IDF commander called the thing a piece of junk. Now, as someone who spent
a ton of time on strikers, that hurts.
But he's not wrong. But it still hurts. Even though the increased speed
of the striker was a notable advantage, Israel knew that urban warfare
would be their primary concern. The thin skinned armor of the striker
simply would not be enough protection in an aggressive, asymmetric urban
fight. Troop protection has to be the number one priority,
even at the cost of other capabilities. Enter the Aton.
Initial funding and loose requirements had been established in 2011,
but budgetary restrictions kept development in limbo.
Finally, increased funding and personnel was allocated by Israel's
Ministry of Defense. Development of the concept was handed to Raphael advanced
defense systems. That's Israel's largest national military R D
conglomerate. Raphael would do the developing, while the
Tank and APC administration would provide government oversight.
There is one thing that thankfully still has zero government oversight today,
and that's whether or not you choose to like this video. That's between you,
your family, and your God. The base level armor plating is made
up of ceramic and titanium steel composite, which provides protection
against 14.5 millimeter machine gun fire. Higher up
armor packages stop kinetic penetrator sabo rounds.
It can stop 30 millimeter cannons. More importantly,
though, it can stop dual purpose shape charges from RPG fire
that Hamas really prefers. The armor is classified specifically
as Neera, or non explosive reactive armor.
This means it consists of a combination of three metallic and non metallic
materials. Materials like rubber can diffuse the impact of a shockwave
from an explosion. This effectively spreads out the generated force
instead of trying to stop the round entirely. This gives the armor
excellent multi hit capability. This is the Iron Fist active
protection system. This was actually designed by Elbit Systems,
an Israel domestic company, in tandem with the Aeton Armored Project.
It has new capabilities compared to the old trophy system
because the Iron fist, crazy name aside,
contains a more robust and capable radar system that
more accurately detects where, and most importantly, what type of
round was fired at your vehicle. It now has two
launchers and four sensors that are linked to a
radar and electro optics that can even shoot down incoming tank
rounds. The new countermeasure computer solution has an improved 70%
success intercept rate and can even target drones in
the sky now, which is a brand new feature. In total, there's ten cameras
nested around the hull with both day and night sensors.
This gets me especially excited because it means we're just one step away from video
game style third person viewing. The Aton is
noticeably larger than older designs like the striker LAV.
It's a full two extra feet length and 3ft width.
Much of that increased length comes from the size of its massive armored sponsor
boxes that you can see in the rear of the vehicle. They serve as extra
storage space, which is very important, and it serves as kind of like an armored
cover for the troops as they dismount out the back. In our strikers, we couldn't
fit our personal salt packs on the vehicle, inside the vehicle, or on the
roof. So what we would do is we would throw them in the space between
the hull and the armor. On the exterior,
it was pretty ghetto. Eight tons also weighed nearly double that
of the American striker counterpart, with base weights of 35 tons.
And it costs roughly $3 million each to produce at
the current rate, about the same as the Namir cousin.
Part of this increased cost could, of course, come down to the fact that the
scale of which it was ordered. While the Aton is an Israeli homegrown
design, roughly half of its components actually come from foreign
sources. This was done in an effort to keep research costs low.
The V shaped hulk can allegedly withstand the blast of over 20 pounds of
TNT. It's like 60 sticks of dynamite, and it would create
a crater 10ft big. This hole shape redirects
that blast away from the hull to the sides of the vehicle. And that's why
they've installed the Mobius blast absorbing seats. It's finally morbing
time for real. It cleverly collapses and redirects the soldier's
inertia down as the hole is forced upward from an explosion.
So it can actually navigate 60% vertical slopes and 30%
horizontal slopes. It can even cross a six foot trench or forward up
to 4ft in water. But the big news is that the future models
of the Aton will serve in a more infantry fighting vehicle
role. This version is still being tested, but it's going to have a 30 millimeter.
It's a massive unmanned cannon turret controlled from inside
by the gunner, so it's probably not going to face off against enemy armor.
So why do you need this giant turret? It would be useful for getting
enemy forces out from hiding behind concrete. Actually, three variants
in total are planned for production. You got your standard APC model,
it's lightly armed. You got a command and control model which trades troop
carrying capacity for radio carrying capacity, and you got
your IFV heavily armed turret model. These different versions
fit into what's known as the IDF's two war strategy.
The IDF expects to fight one type of war.
That's the conventional border invasions. This would involve crossing
large open terrain against actual enemy armor. This means
you would need larger caliber cannons. Then there's that second war that
they fight. That's the unconventional hybrid urban warfare,
the kind we're seeing in Gaza right now. As international tensions and
conflict began to rise over the past few years, the IDF made
the decision in January of 2023 to outsource the entire
whole production to the United States. The 100 million dollar contract
was negotiated by American Oshkosh Defense Company,
which manufactures and produces a number of the military vehicles for
the DoD, such as the new JLTV. This decision was made prior to
the most recent attacks, and this will likely be expediated
to quickly replace vehicles lost in the invasion of Gaza.
Overall, the introduction of the Aiton is, and many would agree,
overdue, and brings what was already one of the world's most capable
fighting forces to a level of performance and capability that will fit
the strategic needs that they have for decades. For more updates follow
me at Capiamy on Instagram and check out one of these videos if you
have another minute. Thank you for watching Spare Parts army if you found this video
valuable in any way, please hit the like and subscribe button and I'll see you
again in a couple of days.