Who were the five nicest celebrities and who were the five meanest?
I can tell you who. The meanest one I ever met. Uh oh. Her name
is Ellen DeGeneres. But while all the evidence points to Ellen
being awful, Adam Sandler is always highlighted as being
incredibly kind. Take for example the time he was refused a table
at IHOP after the server failed to realize it was Adam Sandler asking.
Embarrassed, the server shared the CCTV to TikTok,
prompting Adam Sandler to meet with the waitress personally while joking about the
rejection by stating, for the record, I only left the IHOP because the nice
woman told me the all you can eat deal didn't apply to the milkshakes.
Although fans were impressed for a slightly different reason, it's very humble
of him to not assert that he's a celebrity and ask for special treatment.
He acted just like a regular customer and didn't challenge anyone. I respect
him for that, with his humble attitude extending to wedding photo bombs
and that time he randomly appeared for some chicken. Hi guys.
No way. No way.
You're joking. He filmed a good chunk of Mr. Deeds in my hometown and
he was simply the nicest man ever. He would come out to sign autographs
after a full 14 plus hour day of shooting. Didn't matter how
long the line was, he made sure every single person got to
say hello. He had time for photographs and chats with everyone in
town, frequented all the local coffee shops, and posed with employees.
He seemed to really care and know how excited we all were to have a
movie happening and always had a smile. Although Adam's fans are the only
people to talk very highly of him. You guys love
each other. Is that fair to say? For sure,
yeah. I hear each of you individually talking about the other
in such fond terminology. Yeah. After Pete Davidson worked with
Adam Sandler on Saturday Night Live, Pete went on to state, he's just such a
cool, nice guy. I can't explain how wonderful of a person he is.
Just like caring and sweet and not full of crap, which is very rare to
find. But while Adam SanDler's happy onscreen mood clearly
extends to his personal life, Mike Myers from Austin Powers is
apparently much different. When the cameras aren't rolling, Twitter users
expose Mike Myers as an absolute nightmare to work with.
The article referred to a tweet reading, Mike Myers had me fight off the set
of the Love Guru because I made eye contact with him and
I was there as his bodyguard. The tweet had been posted by a
person named Jay Brody, who then expanded on the incident in a podcast,
you'll be basically guarding Mike Myers'trailer. They're like,
here's the catch. Can't look at him. But I realized I can't let just anyone
into the trailer. So I look up, I catch his eye for a
second, I give him a nod to let him know I'm cool, and then I
look away and within an hour I get a phone call letting me know
that I'm fired and I have to get off set, prompting others to give their
own anecdotes about Mike Meyer's terrible attitude. I was
an extra in Love Guru and remember being told we can't make eye contact
with Mike. When I tell people this, they don't believe me. Thanks for confirming.
People always wonder why there weren't more Austin Powers movies, but never realize
how many stories there are like this about him. Basically, no one wants to
work with the guy with one of these other stories coming from the set of
the cat in the hat where Mike's co star Amy Hill stated his
area was all covered with tenting because he didn't want anybody seeing him.
It was so weird. It was just the worst. I was miserable.
Hill also revealed how diva Myers selfishly kept everyone waiting
for hours, overruled the director, and even had someone standing by just
holding his personal chocolates in a dish. It was just a horrible,
nightmarish experience, although people have only ever said the opposite
about Steve Buscemi. Buscemi worked as a New York firefighter before
quitting to pursue acting, although when the Twin Towers were destroyed
on September 11, Bushemi walked into his old fire department to
volunteer, working 12 hours a day for a week straight
in the hopes of finding survivors. He called his old firehouse, then,
receiving no reply, headed to the site where he found his form engine
company. I asked if I could join them, he said, adding, I could tell they
were a little suspicious at first, but I worked with them that day.
It was a privilege to be able to do it. It was great to connect
with the firehouse I used to work with and with some of the guys I
worked alongside. Note this was in 2001, after he was
already extremely famous from movies such as Fargo.
Yet according to an independent article on his volunteering,
very few photographs and no interviews exist because he declined them.
He wasn't there for publicity. Wouldn't you think you were hallucinating if
Steve Buscemi helped you out of the rubble? What a great humble guy.
With a Reddit comment, then offering a slightly more personal story.
I used to serve him all the time and he never once was a diva.
Always had a smile on his face. And, I mean, I Don't even think he
once had a complicated order. He always ordered the most simple thing on
the menu and always tipped 20 plus percent. Not to mention,
Bushemi gets extra credit for being close friends with Adam Sandler.
However, it seems Jerry Seinfeld was left out of the party. Given every
clip of him I've seen outside of his shows is just him being an unlikable
douche with an ego the size of a small country. This sentiment
began with a Larry King interview from 2007. I went off
the air. I was the number one show on television. Larry, you were off.
You know who I am? 75 million viewers.
Last episoDe. What? Don't take it so bad.
Well, that's the big difference between being canceled and
being number one. Okay, I'm sorry. B movie resume
in here for me. Although this attitude extends
into other moments, like the time he rejected Kesha. I love you so
much. Oh, thanks. No, thanks. Please. No, thanks. A little
one? YEAH. No, thanks.
That was a nice moment. I DON'T KnOW WHO THAT WAS. Kesha.
OKAY. Jerry then offered no apology for rejecting her. I don't hug
a total stranger. I have to meet someone.
Say hello. I need to know who are you? And she
was very nice about it. We laughed about it. Did you? Yeah. Did you hug
her afterwards? No. Leading Kesha to change her
mind about him for pretty obvious reasons. What happened
with Jerry Seinfeld? Oh, my God.
Are you friends with him? I am not. Okay. Where it goes, it was,
like, the saddest moment of my life. Jerry also has a reputation for
destroying the paparazzi. The worst place, like your bomb. I'm sure comics go
through all the time. Another very weak, weak question. And after Lady
Gaga was moved to his luxury basketball box for acting rudely
at a game, he had this to say. This woman's a jerk.
I hate her. I can't believe they put her in my box, which I
paid for. This is what you give people the finger and you get upgraded?
Is that the world we're living in now? Hysterical. I love
him. Jerry Seinfeld's meanness definitely has a charisma to it.
However, if you're wanting a more humble type of charisma, then we have to
talk about Post Malone. With entire compilations dedicated to him treating
other people kindly, there are almost too many wholesome moments to
choose from. Did you draw this? This is awesome.
Thank you. There was that time he went out of
his way to greet a 21 year old having his first beer. Or that time
he gave his $5,000 guitar to a fan after a concert.
You want a guitar, it's like a $5,000 guitar.
So you have to promise me, you got to promise me that you're going to
take care of it.
Post Malone treats paparazzi in the opposite way to Jerry Seinfeld.
Boss, I want you to know that I really like your music. Thank you so
much, man. Thank you so much. Yeah, that means, can you say hello to Nicole?
Hi, Nicole. Love you guys. And when this fan somehow made it
past security, Post Malone hugs the guy and treats him respectfully before
he's taken off the stage. In a different instance, Post Malone let a fan
come on stage to play the guitar part in stay. And it's therefore no
surprise that fans have told anecdotal stories. Such as, someone in
a similar thread said post moved into his brother's street and went and introduced himself
to all his new neighbors and invited them for a barbecue. Genuinely sounds
like an awesome guy. I believe this 100%. He had a party
in an Airbnb or something a few houses down from my group's Airbnb,
and he legit went around the cul de sac himself, inviting everyone
to the party. He also spent the entire night moving between groups,
chatting, and generally being a phenomenal host and ensuring everyone had a blast.
Ten out of ten, dude. But while nobody has anything negative
to say about post Malone, it seems nobody has anything positive
to say about Chevy Chase. Remember when Pete Davidson
praised Adam Sandler earlier in the video? Well, Pete had the opposite to say
about Chevy Chase, stating, he's a fucking douchebag. I hate
that dude. He's just a genuinely bad, racist person and I don't like
him. Chevy Chase was fired from community after calling Donald Glover the N
word. Not to mention before the firing, Chase was simply difficult to work
with. He was someone that did not want to be there for the hours that
we were keeping. He sometimes could be in not great moods. Earlier in his career,
Chevy Chase had gotten into a fistfight with Bill Murray. And while interviewing
Robert Downey Jr. Chase stated, didn't your father used to be a successful director?
Whatever happened to him? Boy, he sure died, you know? He sure went to hell.
It's therefore no surprise that even Will Ferrell stated the worst host
was Chevy Chase. Yet Chevy Chase foolishly claims that all criticism
is just jealousy. Did you just say that writers writing anything negative
is jealousy? Yeah, I did. What kind of jealousy? I'm funnier than them.
Yeah, I guess maybe I'm considered good looking. Yeah, there you have it. It seems
Chevy Chase needs a lesson on humility. And who better to teach it than
Shaquille O'Neill? Got to humble yourself. It's all about humility.
And that's why I am where I am now. I humbled mysElf. I don't look
down on people because they're lesser. Back in 2011,
Shaq had hit rock bottom. He'd retired from basketball, divorced from his
wife, and had no idea where his life was going next. All's lost.
76,000 square foot house by yourself. No kids. Go to
the gym. Nobody's playing in the gym. You go to their room,
nobody's there. It was during this period that Shaq's mom, Lucille, gave him some advice.
And then the queen, Dr. Lucille O'Neill, said, hey, man, I don't know you no
more. You need to humble yourself. And when Mama talk, true man listens.
After which, Shaq began working on becoming a better person. It state
the day I killed the narcissist. Shaq is the day my kids texted me,
hey, Daddy, I miss you, bro. When I got one of those texts, man,
I actually cried. Then. I didn't know what to say. After I got that love
from them, I said, you know what? I'm not going to be the asshole Shaq
no more. Because I was an asshole. And I lost everything the day I
released all that. Me. Me, Shaq. Shaq. Shaq. Shaq is the day the
blessings opened up. As a result, Shaq's been trying to create a
fairly unique legacy. Talk about legacies. I want mine to be
one sentence. Shaq was a nice guy, which has been aided by his random
acts of kindness, purchasing bikes, shoes, and laptops for less fortunate
children. It seems the only people Shaq won't give money to are his own kids.
Because I believe in respectable nepotism. You get all A's this next
semester. You can get whatever you want. So he gets all A's. And I was
like, go to the dealership and pick one. Then I get a call from Tesla.
I said, man, you better take your ass across the street to Honda.
But Walshack is an obvious choice as a nice celebrity. Someone you
might not expect to be rude is Bill Nye, the science guy. I met Bill
Nye as a kid, and he was the biggest asshole I've ever met. It was
a huge letdown. After watching his show so often in class. My science
teacher from 7th grade told us she had an explanation for why she
tried to show us as few Bill Nye videos as possible. I believe she said
she attended either a science workshop or an event for teachers where Bill Nye
was there and he was completely rude to her and dismissed her the whole time.
Bill's dark side becomes pretty obvious when he debates other scientists.
However, it seems he becomes the meanest when talking to his most popular demographic,
kids Bill Nye came to visit my university. I was sorely disappointed.
Bill Nye relied on sexist jokes to relate to the crowd. He kept
complimenting women's legs and saying weird stuff about how sexy women
are. He was trying to be relatable, but was sorely mistaken as he faced
a crowd of driven female engineers and scientists. He went on about climate change
and basically insinuated that we could be the policy changes while
the real scientists did the real work. I couldn't believe how much my views of
him were falling apart as I watched him pander to students he clearly didn't
care about. I later heard that he wouldn't speak with students, only professors,
with this anecdote, following the very common theme of Bill Nye was my
hero until I heard him talk. Although thankfully Keanu Reeves is
the perfect balance between good and evil. While filming the
second two Matrix movies, Keanu Reeves chose to give up 75
million worth of his movie earnings, instead redirecting the money to
the special effects team, who he said deserved it more. Even then,
this might not have been his most charitable act whilst filming. As a Reddit user
stated, a family friend Builds movie sets, doesn't design,
is one of the poor dudes that just builds. Anyways, he worked on the set
for the Matrix and Keanu heard about family trouble he was having and gave him
a $20,000 Christmas bonus to help him out. Although money isn't the
only thing that Keanu has given up. In 2011, he was candidly
filmed giving up his seat on the New York subway, and three years later in
2014, he waited patiently for 20 minutes in the
rain outside the rap party of his own film Daughter of God.
After a mix up because he didn't want to cause a scene, he didn't
say hey, I'm Keanu Reeves or Yo man, this is my party. Once to
the bouncer and the owner of the club was horrified when he found out afterwards
that the actor was standing in the rain. It's therefore no surprise that there's an
extremely popular subreddit dedicated to Keanu Reeves being awesome.
Although if there's one person who could offset this kindness with meanness,
it's definitely Ellen DeGeneres right now, we all need
a little kindness. You know, like Ellen DeGeneres always talks about,
she's also notoriously one of the meanest people alive. Respond to
this with the most insane stories you've heard about Ellen being mean,
and I'll match everyone with $2 to LA Food Bank. This was the tweet that
started her downfall, as nobody could have expected how bad the
responses would be. When I was 15, the Ellen show was doing a contest.
A fan's making a bust of her and sending it to her. I worked so
hard on this and even wrote her a letter. Weeks later. She used it as
a prop in a game and gave it away to a random person with $500
attached to the bottom. Working for her, I was instructed that I can't look her
in the eye and never, ever say hi to her first. But don't worry,
she definitely won't be saying hi to you in the first place. She creates the
most toxic environment for her staff. I worked at real food daily,
served her and Portia at brunch. She wrote a letter to the owner and complained
about my chipped nail polish. Not that it was on her plate, but just that
it was on my hand. I'd worked till closing the night before,
and this was the next morning. Almost got me fired. Chris Pontier
stated on Steve O's podcast that he wasn't surprised to hear these anecdotes.
It's crazy that all this stuff's come out, like, about Ellen being mean,
because when I met her, I thought she was really mean. And she's like,
so what do I got to do? And she's just pissed to be there.
And then she comes out on stage and she's like all like, funny, nice Ellen,
the person that they think she is. And appareNtly, neither were the ten employees
who came forward four months later to expose her terrible working
environment. Toxic. Phony. Hypocrite. Liar. That's what
she is. We were told from the very beginning, don't talk to Ellen.
Don't do this. You can't go into her office. It was very nerve wracking,
very stressful. We all walked on eggshells all the time. As a result,
Ellen took a 14 week hiatus, returning with a pretty standard apology.
Sometimes I get sad, I get mad, I get anxious,
I get frustrated, I get impatient, and I am working on
all of that. However, this failed to ensure a returning audience,
as in May 2022, and show was canceled completely.