What's the range of revenue all this does? Over 600 million
a year. Yeah.
Basement. Meet Larry Janetsky, the blue collar billionaire. He has
built one of the largest and most successful basement repair companies in
America. He's invented revolutionary products that millions use
across their home. He has a portfolio of blue collar businesses making
$650,000,000 a year. And he's
achieved this all while working less than the average CEO.
If you have to work 70 hours a week, you're doing it wrong. So today
we're finding out what it takes to build a billion dollar blue collar empire.
You've been running this for 40 years? Well, I started when I was 17.
And how much did you make your first year? I made $18,000
maybe, I don't know. I got a call when I was 18 years old.
Can you build a house for me? Yeah, but I'm 18
years old, so if that's a problem,
let me know in six weeks. Me, my friend who was 17 years
old, and my younger brother who was 14 years old on summer vacation,
the three of us, you can't make this up. We built the house, and then
when we were done, the guy next door comes over says, can you build mine?
And then we built his, and the guy on the other side comes over,
can you build mine? And that's it. I was off to the races. How does
it feel when I say the phrase blue collar billionaires? It might be
surprising to you, but hello,
before whatever, 1990, we didn't
have computers and there were people that did well before then.
Okay, so tech isn't the only way to make money. Okay?
You go to the store, you buy groceries, you go to a
mall, and you have all this retail. But the cool thing is about working
with your hands is that you can never be replaced
by AI. Amazon's not going to take over. Your job is
not going to be offshored to India or anywhere else. Right?
Nobody can go in to a homeowner
and fix their basement from Amazon
or from India or. No robot is ever
going to fix a crawl space. It's just not going to happen. Right.
We need guys who are willing to get dirty.
They know how to do what to do and why theY're there,
and that's what we do. These guys are real men,
okay? You would see what these guys do. You would not believe it.
You would not believe what these guys do. What do you mean? The work
that they do, how hard work it is. Crawl space work. We go into crawl
spaces that are this high and they got dead mice. And snake
skins and bugs, and it's all mud under there.
And they crawl in there. And when they leave, the end of the day,
the customer could crawl in their pajamas and slide around.
And these guys go into these very difficult environments
every single day. And they make an
incredibly, almost impossible job look
easy. And we pay them very, very well.
What's the range of salary? These guys make over $100,000
a year because they earn it. It's hard to see this here, but he who
works with his hands is a laborer. He who works with his hands and his
head is a craftsman. He who works with his hands,
his head and his heart is an artist. From making
$18,000 building homes to owning a 600 million dollar
a year business, I had to find out what Larry's secret is.
That's a big jump from here to $600 million a year.
You started. Hey, I'm just going to do basements.
And just the demand was there. It's been 40 years,
okay, come on. We didn't make a big jump. We made
a lot of little ones. There's a lot of business. People are looking for the
quick hit. Right? I'm going to start this business. I'm going to
sell it in three years. Right. You're going in it with the wrong mindset.
To begin with, my doctor energy saver business, I went five
and a half million dollars in the hole with no end to
the losses in sight. And then my partner quit and sued me.
So what do I do? Do I quit? No. I kept going. Eleven years
later, I made $1. Today it's very profitable.
We're making houses more comfortable, more energy efficient.
They burn less fossil fuels and electricity, and they're
less expensive to own. I've had a great, positive environmental impact
on the world because I didn't quit. Do you have regrets about working too
much? And was all this worth that?
I'm glad you asked, because I don't want people to think that I was
the classic story of the busy business guy who was married
to his business and worked so much and ignored his family.
That is not the issue. And I haven't worked the weekend in 30 years.
If you have to work 70 hours a week, you're doing
it wrong. You cannot ignore your family. You cannot ignore
having some fun in the beginning. You think it's about making money.
You think it's about making a lot of money, right? I think that a lot
of business owners don't stick with it long enough to realize what it's really
about. And it's not about the money. I don't get my self
esteem from how much money I make. I get it from those people,
from them looking at me and saying, I trust you.
At your funeral, nobody's going to say, oh, we had so much money,
they don't care. It's the relationships and the good that you've
done the footprint. Did you leave the world better than when you found it?
That's what it's about. I've been working hard on my upcoming book,
Million Dollar Weekend, which is coming out early 2024. Stay tuned. Looking through
my notes, I found a lost chapter that is not in the final book.
Very mysterious. It reveals things like how to double your income
without any new customers, how to create complementary
products to generate more income. One solopreneur did this and made an extra
$340,000. How to optimize Pricing Strategy
and maximize profits and more. The Lost chapter is not
online or Amazon or anywhere else. It is only for people on my
list like you. You can download it for free@Noahkagan.com.
Slash lost. That's Noahkagan.com Slash lost.
It's also below in the description. Alright, back to the video. A huge part
of Larry's success that he downplayed in his early career was how serious
he took having a positive mindset. You got a lot of your education
through motivational tapes. You got a lot of your learnings early on. I discovered
Nightingale Conan audio programs when I was 19 and it
changed my life. And I would listen to cassette tapes driving around in my truck
and my friends would make fun of me,
listen to all that motivational crap and stuff.
So I kind of hid it from them for a long time.
But I wear those things out. Yeah.
Brian Tracy and Earl Nightingale, he's like
father to me. And now it comes full circle as
Larry has created his own motivational tapes to inspire others on their
journey. Some people say I can't be successful
because I'm not talented.
Really,
I don't believe that. Now it was time for Larry to give me
a tour of his $13 million office. And as he was taking me
through, we met a few of his employees and I was blown away by how
loyal they are to Larry. Michael, how long you've been here?
Nine years November. All right. Nine years, November 14.
Sue, how long you been here? Almost 20 years.
Yeah. How long have you been here? 16 years. 16 years.
How long you have been here? Going to be 21 years.
What makes you want to stay? The people.
Just the whole atmosphere of the company, the thing I
don't understand, Larry. How are you so calm?
There's a saying flows uphill. All the problems that
no one else could solve go up to the leader. I don't get those problems.
My phone doesn't ring, and it's on right now. I didn't turn it off because
I have good people. So you need to create
a great team of people who stay. If you
have continual turnover, nobody gets good at
what they're doing. Right? And then you're constantly rebuilding your
company. If you turn everybody over, every 24 months,
you have a brand new company. Every 24 months, you can never
get traction. You're going to go for a ride in the world's slowest elevator.
No, come on. How did you learn your initial skills? I went
to a technical high school. A regional vocational technical
high school. I chose carpentry. Yeah. So I wasn't afraid
to cut wood and nail it together. So this
is marketing. So they generate 15,000 leads
a year. If Fatima gets a
lead from the Internet, she's calling within 60 seconds. I just want
to see the Google reviews. This is just so gooD. This is, like, so well
run. Let's see what the customers say. Three days ago, five stars added
a full bathroom to my basement. Tech professionals came on time.
High quality work. They put in a basement to make dehumidifier
system. So all this is displays
of different products that we either manufacture
or distribute to our
dealers. I invented most of our key products.
We're basement waterproofing and crawl spaces. I have 32 patents.
Can you show us some of those products? Yeah. This is a
dehumidifier that my son designed. This is the most efficient,
high performance dehumidifier in the world. My son also developed the
world's best air purifier. He built this room that
we would fill with smoke and watch it clear the air.
And we have videos on it to prove that
this is the world's best air purifier. We'd set up lasers in
here so you could see the smoke. And we put
every competitive air purifier in here and did the
same test, and you could see the smoke go right through it with
your own eyes. So this is boomtown. This is an 1880s
mining town theme. So this is the boomtown mine, and this is what
the miners would have been going after here.
Plus, this is your stuff, too. Now, this is foam.
Yeah. So I sprayed the foam and pushed them in. So we
built all this, designed and built the whole thing. We're contractors,
right? I'm so over tech.
This tech company sucks, dude. I'm being dirty hands
messy. So this is a vintage industrial space,
and all the desks are, like 100 year old oak desks.
And all this stuff is most of all this stuff, including light
fixtures, is from old factories and stuff. This is
a sculpture of the business machine model. All my dealers walk in here,
they know what that is, and it actually operates.
This was from Grand Central Station. Literally mailboxes
from Grand Central Station. This year, when someone says
blue collar, how does that make you feel? Or what do you think when you
hear that? For me, I've always been blue collar. I don't
think of it that way. I don't think that white collar is any better.
I mean, you could have a guy who's a billionaire, but if
his. His foundation's messed up. Who are you going to call now?
Buddy, if you like
this video, you are going to love this video. Right up here, where I talk
to five millionaires over the age of 80 and ask them if the money
was worth all the sacrifices they made. Make sure you
subscribe to the channel if you are not already. We have some exciting billionaire interviews
coming soon. Uncle Noah loves you, and I'll see you out there. Pew.