Three, two, one, go.
Oh, my God. Wow.
This is amazing. This is so
gorgeous. No, I'm studying like a Millie rocket skin,
clear silicon Andy Miller. Knock his money in my pocket. Don't call
me a money pocket. And you can get to rocket. It's not like a thunder
racket. Good morning. Good morning. Good morning.
What is up, everyone? Today is a big day. Okay. So this
video has taken me three months to make. As you can see behind
me, this is my brand new car collection.
And after three months, it's finally here.
Oh, my God. This is literally like a dream.
Guys, this is the last time you're ever going to see them like this,
okay? This could be the best decision of my life. Or the worst decision.
So the cars have officially left the house. They're on the way to the garage.
When you wrap one car, it's fine, but when you wrap five,
there's no going back. Hello. Hello,
my bro. Bro, good to see you. Good to see.
Foilers, my passion. We're going to do something crazy for you.
Okay, guys, so right now, we just made it to my friend's place. It's time
to see what we're going to do. It's one of the biggest projects I've done
in the last five years. We got a Ferrari, two Bentleys,
Rollsroyce, SLS. What's the last car? I forgot all
my cars. What can we do? I want something crazy. So we
have this four tone. It's got a purple, it's got a green, it's got a
red, orange, everything. I mean, do you want to do something like this? So this
car changes color. It's like chameleon color.
Keeps changing. Wow. But do you want to do this? Do you have different colors?
Okay. Matte black. What about this, bro? But again, every Tom,
Dick, and Harry does this. All right, let's go look at
some colors. Okay. Oh, my God.
All right, Aziz, where do we start? So we've got a lot
of colors over here. More than 100 colors. It's confusing me. I like the
purples. I like the pink. How about a green? This is nice. How about this,
bro? Carbon fiber. One of a kind I did on
a Lamborghini hurricane. Wow. How about this? And this?
I think I like that. Oh, my God, guYs. Or do you want to
do some design? I think we need something different.
Hey, guys. So it's been about an hour, and I think we finally decided.
I am shocked. The color, what you've selected is going to be crazy,
bro. Crazy. All right, let's do it.
Oh, my God.
Yo, this is insane.
Welcome to my new car collection.
Okay, guys, so right now, we just made it here. Do you see this?
This is crazy, guys. Yo, they're all
purple. Let's go through the freaking cars. Let's go through them.
So, since we're here, obviously there's not just my car collection.
We also have my mom's Rollsroyce. Mommy, come. My mom is just
a show. Oh, my God. What do you think? Very nice.
Actually, she's my mom, too. Yeah. Mommy.
Mommy. Guys, see, Mommy? Mom's car is now part
of the collection. It could be pink, but this is honestly
more nicer. Mommy, have you seen the
rose? Yes. Purple.
This is crazy. I don't know what to say, bro. Thank you, thank you,
thank you. This is crazy, guys. I'm sweating
right now. I don't even know what to say, bro. How so? Guys, this is
one of a kind. The purple wrap majern. This is a premium purple.
If you see the grains and the effect of the purple wrap,
it's so beautiful. But this is crazy. Yeah, it is. And you are the first
one I'm applying it on. This is the first time you do this color.
I'm using this color and this brand. It's not a vinyl. It's not a plastic.
Damn. This is crazy, bro. Hey, Mo, I've got a surprise for
you. You have another surprise? Can you read this?
No. This glows in the dark. They have my
name on the brakes of this car. That's sick.
That's insane. Glows in the dark. It glows in the dark.
Yeah, bro. Bro. Alan, what do you think, bro? Next level, man. A whole nother
level, bro. We're taking things to the next level. I promise you, bro. Alan,
this is wild. This is my car collection. This is it? Maybe.
What else do I say? We're gonna quickly rearrange the cars. I need to take
some photos for Instagram. That's what I need to do, bro. I think we got
a new driver, bro. We got a new driver on the Ferrari. I think he's
six, but, I mean, if he can drive, he can drive.
Matching keys to the card. Yo,
this is wild, guys. Have you ever seen a purple key before?
The key matches the car.
It works. See? As is my brother. Thank you
again. Yeah.
One of you got a whole left side. Yeah.
There you go. Guys, it's time to get my sister and see her reaction.
What's happening? Lana, are you ready? For what? To see
our new car collection. Not again. Yeah. Oh,
my God. What is going on?
Bro, like, why are the cars covered?
It's time. Who does that? Damn, bro. Red carpet wipes,
man. I don't know what's behind that. What color is it? I have a surprise
for you, too. What is it? I got you a car. No, you didn't.
What car is that?
Broken BMW? Exactly. My fake beat up. What is
it? You think I'm Mr. Beast? Bro. Bro. Mr.
Beast. Seriously? All the
cars? Yep. Every single one. Like, did you just grab
all the cars and just decide? Like, let me just change them up.
Yep, exactly. Does mom have any idea about this? Yep. You're the
only one that didn't know. This is the whole collection.
Okay. Three, two, one, go.
Oh, my God. Wow.
This is amazing. This is so
gorgeous, bro. You killed it,
right? I had no idea, Mo. Like, you should
have done my car, too. I didn't know.
Damn, bro. And all of them, like, this looks
so badass. Wow. Oh, my God. Let me step
back for a second. Isn't this crazy? I am in love with
this. It's going to look so crazy on the road. I feel like people are
just gonna like, what? So there you go. That is the car collection.
Now it's time for the best part. Driving them. Let's take them to the road.
Let's go. All right, switch it on. Here's the Ferrari. Can I drive
the SLS? You want the SLS? You can. Here,
I'm allowed. Yep. It's okay? Yeah. All right.
I'm going to drive the SLS. All right. Let's go.
Wow.
Okay. Why is that? With these doors,
bro, you can't close it. Is it normal?
Yeah. Why did you guys come?
High doors. I need a button for this. Can you customize it? No.
Okay, come on. Close the doors.
Oh, my God. All right, guys, I got lie. Today's a
good day. It's time to go to the road. You did not put petrol in
this car. Really? It says fuel reserve. Oh, no.
All right. I guess we just have to do what we got to do.
You don't.