You. On 13 August 2016,
a mysterious auction appeared on the web,
claiming that anyone who wanted could purchase national level
cybersecurity weapons that had been produced by none other than the American
NSA and specifically an elite hacking unit
known as the equation Group. However, the auction's
rules were so strange that nobody wanted to bid. The sellers,
who called themselves the Shadow Brokers, only attached a
bitcoin wallet address and stated that everyone who lost the
auction wouldn't get their money back. Because of these strange
rules and the password protected files, the biggest bid
was only about $9,000. The mysterious
auction was a complete failure. However, these mysterious
files wouldn't just disappear from the web. But before
we continue, I'd like to introduce you to today's sponsor,
Proton. Your email provider knows all about
you. Your name, birthday, address,
phone number, workplace things you purchased, trips you went
on, your passport copy. That's your data,
right? Wrong. That data is being sold to advertisers.
The more data you give away, the more valuable you are.
Like a product. Then they profile you and target
you with ads. What could possibly go wrong?
In 2016, Yahoo confirmed that emails
of all 3 billion users were leaked. Everyone's data
was up for grabs and could be used for identity theft and
fraud. You don't want your life details to be in the hands
of advertisers or hackers. So what can you do?
Switch to Proton. Proton Mail protects your emails
with an end to end encryption, so no one, not even Proton,
can read your emails. Proton blocks marketing trackers
and malware, so nobody knows if you've opened their email.
Say goodbye to spam, phishing attacks and spoofing.
Proton is based in Switzerland, so you're protected by strong privacy
laws. You can easily migrate your existing emails with just a
couple of clicks. With EasySwitch, be one of 100
million users who have already chosen privacy.
Get Started for free at Proton Me
thinker sponsors like Proton help the channel immensely
and we couldn't be more thankful for them. So if you support us
and want your emails to be safe, please check them out and
let's get back to the video. A group calling themselves the
Shadow brokers claim that they've hacked the NSA.
Mysteriously, a cache of NSA hacking
tools was released online. The Shadow brokers
sparked fears of a new group of previously unknown zero day
exploits. We were trying to answer essentially one big
question. How could a group since August of 2016
offer for sale samples of what clearly was
code used inside the National Security Agency to
break into foreign computer systems? The NSA and FBI have taken
this breach extremely seriously. But their inability to actually
find the root cause is deeply problematic.
It's the middle of the night when one of the employees of Telephonica
notices something weird on his computer screen. He quickly grabs
his phone and dials his supervisor. Hey,
Juan, we've got a massive problem. Minutes later,
a nurse working for the United Kingdom's National Health Services reported
that her computer stopped working, a major cyberattack
forcing hospitals across the UK to turn away patients.
Ambulances were diverted to other hospitals. Operations canceled
as malicious software paralyzed 16 hospital computer
systems across England. Heart patient Anthony Bret was
told his operation was on hold. I was supposed to have a stent
put in over the weekend. I can't do it now because
of all this computer egging. But this was only the beginning.
A massive cyber hack hits countries around the world, crippling tens
of thousands of computers. On Friday, the so called ransomware attack
locks people out of their computers and demands money.
Experts are calling the WannaCry virus the
largest cyberattack in history. This virus has impacted Germany's
national rail system as well as FedEx. Here in the United States,
at least five Australian businesses have been hit. Today, we learned of an auto assembly
line suddenly stopped because computers had shut down. South Korea
is among the 150 countries that have been affected by
Friday's unprecedented malware attack, which has
infected more than 200,000 computers worldwide.
The attack used a loophole exposed when stolen NSA
documents were posted online with that information.
Any idea who is behind the attack? I don't think we
have any real idea of that.
As the mysterious ransomware was wrecking havoc on the global
economy, a cybersecurity expert called Marcus Hutchins
decided to jump into the action and analyze the virus.
As he roamed through the malware's code, he discovered that
before the malware began its encryption process, it tried to connect
to a strange URL. However, this connection
failed every time, and once it didn't connect,
the virus began to encrypt the infected system. It turned
out that this URL was an unregistered domain.
Curious about the reason for this URL's existence, Hutchins decided
to risk it all by buying and registering the domain.
The ransomware that affected 99 countries and an estimated
75,000 individual computers was stopped
in its tracks by accident. He actually probably saved lives on
accident just by registering this one website name in
his name. I've had people sort of inundating me messages thanking me, saying that I'm
a hero. I mean, I sort of just registered this domain for tracking. And I
didn't intend for it to sort of blow up and me to be all over
the media. I was just sort of doing my job, and I don't really think
that I'm a hero at all.
It turns out that WannaCry was a complex worm that had been
inserted into the digital world with only one objective,
to hunt for vulnerable SMB ports. An SMB
port is basically a protocol that every Microsoft computer
uses to send information packs from computers to printers or
other machines connected on a network. And since this information is
always moving around, the worm could access this flow of information
and then insert itself into the communication protocol.
Once inside, the worm was able to use the communication
protocol's data traffic to infect the first machine.
AfteR infiltrating the machine, it created a backdoor to
execute its malware and replicated itself. These new
copies would go on to infect the network the machine was connected
to in order to search for more vulnerable machines.
And because big businesses usually have a network in which
every machine is connected, it was able to quickly infect everything
in their networks. The two main tools used by
the worm were eternal blue and double pulsar,
which had been developed by the NSA and were in fact
some of the exploits that had been leaked by the Shadow brokers a few
weeks earlier. However, inside of this complex mesh of
code, researchers working for the FBI also discovered several
notes which often contained data about the computer that
created them. By using this data, they found that the original
computer contained the file FCharset
129, which is the file name for the Korean alphabet.
Furthermore, the time zone set for the hackers computers
was UTC plus 9 hours, which is the time zone
used in Korea. Everything seemed to point to the
Korean Peninsula, and since South Korea is a close U.
S. Ally, suspicions quickly fell upon North
Korea. Traces of the attack were connected to a person who
went by Kim Hyo Wu. And surprisingly,
all of his digital footprints pointed towards the Chinese town
of Dalyan. And as the team continued to stitch together the different
pieces of evidence, they slowly revealed the true scope
of Kim's activity.
He wasn't only connected to the origins of WannaCry,
but also played a major role in the 2014 Sony
attack, the 2016 Bangladeshi bank
heist, and even attacks on the US weapons manufacturer Lockheed
Martin. Whoever Keem was, he was part
of a massive web of devastating cyberattacks.
But he was a complete mystery.
However, one night, one of the FBI researchers found
an email that would change everything. This email
didn't belong to Keem, but to a gaming developer called Pak
Jin yuk, who had uploaded a zip file containing malicious files
and granted shared access to several of Keem's emails.
The connections finally culminated when they discovered that PAc was
in Dalyan at the same time Kim was perpetrating his attacks.
From there, the FBI concluded that Keem was in
fact PAC's online persona, and as the authorities
slowly located the precise location of his activities,
they all pointed to the same place, a gaming company
known as Chosen Expo. The authorities quickly investigated
Chosen Expo, and to their surprise, they had contracted with
a gaming developer who was none other than Pac Jin Yuk.
Furthermore, he specialized in the programming language
Visual C, the language used to
create the WannaCry malware. Chosen Expo's accounts
would quickly enter the picture. When the investigators found that not only
were pox'accounts connected to cybercrime, but that most
of the company's accounts were being used to carry out cyber attacks,
the entire company seemed to be a front for some unknown
elite cybercrime group, and as the investigations into
Chosen Expo continued, it allowed investigators to finally put
the pieces of the puzzle together. The group
that operated from Chosen Expo would be identified as North Korea's
top hacking department, called Lab 110, a secretive
group whose members or front companies had never been revealed before.
But it seemed that Lab 100 and ten's main operations in Chosen
Expo had concluded around 2014, when Pock
and several others traveled back to North Korea. Even Stranger
is that pock and his team hadn't been seen since then,
and most likely had been sent on another top secret mission with new
identities. Nonetheless, the discovery of Lab 110
was a major win for the international cybercrime community,
who finally got insights into North Korean cybercrime activity.
But almost nothing is known about them, since they are in fact,
a top secret department of a highly paranoid country.
This is because their operations are known only by a handful
of people, mainly the group itself and the leadership of Bureau
121, the faction that oversees North Korea's
special hacking operations. In addition to this,
they have an extremely harsh selection process that was revealed
by a North Korean defector in 2013. Bureau 121
is always searching for young children that display extraordinary talent
in math, and once they find them, they send them to the Kim
Ilsung University and Kim Czech universities
of Technology, where they learn everything about hacking.
But this is only the first step in their education.
Every year, the ten best students are enlisted in a
top secret education program that sends them to a special
university in India to become lethal cyber soldiers.
After years of training, only the best of the best get recruited
by Bureau 121. Which then gives them
new identities and designates them to specific teams,
such as Lab 110. Once they're assigned to their team,
they are given contracts in secret North Korean front companies
all around the world. Several of these fronts have been identified
in Chinese border towns, but others have been located in Belarus,
Malaysia, India, and Russia, where they can hide in the
local online traffic and mask any connections to the
North Korean mainland. And even though Bureau 120
one's teams are small, the US estimates
that since 2010, the department has grown from a few hundred
elite hackers to over 6000 in 2020.
However, how many of these have really gone through? The complete training
is unknown. Nonetheless, with over 6000
members and five people per group, there should be around
1200 different cyberhacking cells all
around the world. And to this date, only six of these
cells have been identified. So even though
North Korea is often displayed as a laughingstock because of their
senseless threats, it seems that they are indeed becoming a
major player in the depths of the cyber world.
If you want to check out another wild story, check out
this video right here. Video narrated
by Eric Peabody.