I wanted to take this opportunity to thank each and every one of you for
your support. Over the last four years, we've grown into
an international team of 15 people. We have loved producing
battle map animations for you and we love hearing how much you enjoy them.
We do our absolute best to offer accurate and unbiased recreations
of the most important battles and operations of the 20th and 21st centuries.
I hope we've done a relatively good job at this. However,
you may have also been following the recent changes in YouTube monetization rules
that is often demonetizing our videos. With a team of
people relying on this monetization, this has become a major challenge for us.
Shorts now take up valuable space on the YouTube homepage that would ordinarily
be used to recommend our long form content. We are
also censored from covering certain topics. As just one example,
certain conflicts involving certain militant groups in
certain Middle Eastern places over the last 20 years get demonetized,
preventing us from covering major events in recent military history.
When videos are demonetized, it's YouTube policy to specifically not tell
us the reason in case we don't do that thing again or something.
With that in mind, this video is sponsored by our new and updated
Patreon. We've got lots of exciting new benefits and are creating a community
where we can interact with you more directly. We're uploading all
videos completely ad and sponsor free. We've launched a new Q
A series on the Intel Report, where Patreons can directly ask
the follow up questions to the operations room on the intel report videos.
We'll be featuring your reactions and comments to early releases on
the videos themselves when they later upload to YouTube. You'll also
gain access to Patreon only events, competitions and giveaways.
We'll continue to commit to our YouTube release schedule as is,
but we will also be able to release videos on censored topics
and videos that have been demonetized on Patreon.
Absolutely no pressure at all. But if you would like to support us, it would
be amazing. Please take a look at the link in the description and pinned comment
below. No problem at all. If not, we appreciate all of your support.
Since April 20,
1914 B
52 H Stratofortress Strategic bombers begin rolling
down the runway at RAF Fairfords in the United Kingdom at just
before 01:00 p.m. Local time on 21 March 2003.
The crews of the aircraft queuing on the taxiway wave small American
flags out their windows before joining the main runway,
drawing tears from the ground. Crews the B 52s are
on their way to their target, Baghdad. There they will join coalition
aircraft to bring shock and awe to Saddam Hussein's military.
Four B Two Spirit stealth bombers and a further 14
B 52s also take off from the British base at Diego
Garcia in the Indian Ocean. Like the B 52s flying
from the U. K, these aircraft are en route to the operational area
aboard the aircraft carrier USS Constellation. Captain Mark Fox
has briefed the pilots of Carrier Wing Two, whose 20 FA
18 C Hornet strike aircraft are part of the first wave heading
into Baghdad. Due to press reporters listening in on the
briefings, box and his subordinates are careful not to disclose
sensitive information while also giving their men a clear picture
of what to expect before sending them to their aircraft.
The liftoff from the carrier's flight deck is smooth and the Hornets climb
to 18,000ft en routes to meet their tankers over
northern Saudi Arabia. Meanwhile, strike aircraft,
strategic bombers, wild weasels, tankers, electronic warfare
aircraft, recon aircraft and drones begin launching from air
bases across the Middle east and from five aircraft carriers
in the Persian Gulf. By the end of the first day,
1700 sorties will have been launched against Iraq,
about 60% of the number during the first day of the air War of Desert
Storm. The first wave is to launch a coordinated
attack into Baghdad at 09:00 p.m. Local time each hour.
Hundreds of strike aircraft will then immediately join the aerial
assault across Iraq, hitting Iraqi army and Republican
Guard targets, SAM sites and military infrastructure.
This operation was originally intended to mark the official start
of Operation Iraqi Freedom, with the ground invasion following on
the morning of 22nd. Instead, US Fifth
Corps and the first Marine Expeditionary Force have crossed the Iraqi border
24 hours early after concern that Saddam Hussein's government would
wage a scorched earth campaign. Saddam's generals
are caught off guard by this strategy. They had been expecting another
long and sustained aerial barrage similar to the one they had faced
in the five weeks before the land defensive of Operation Desert
Storm. With the Iraqi military knocked back on
its heels, the leader of Central Command, General Tommy Franks,
and the Air War commander, Major General Buz Mosley,
decide to proceed with the first day of the planned air offensive. A day
the objective is to clear out enemy air defenses and decisively
cripple the barfist regime. Unlike at the beginning
of Desert Storm, the coalition has already won air superiority
over Iraq with months of preparatory airstrikes.
When planning for Iraqi freedom began, General Mosley estimated
that his air forces would need ten to 14 days to pummel
Saddam's air defenses before the invasion could start.
General Franks was unhappy with this. He believed the Lightning war
on the ground should be supported by a lightning war in the sky.
Instead, Operation Southern Focus was authorized. In 2002,
Royal Air Force and United States Air Force aircraft methodically bomb
Iraqi air defenses over the no fly zone below the 33rd parallel.
Between March and December 2002, the number of bombs
dropped by the RAF and USAF on Iraq increased
by 300%. The suppression missions
became so routine that ref Tornado pilots began
referring to them as recreational bombing.
However, not all enemy air defenses have been suppressed.
The air defenses in the area of central Iraq did not fall under
either the northern or southern no fly zones established during Desert
Storm and have not been targeted by interwar strikes.
Coalition intelligence has identified over 200 threats within this
area, including Sovietbuilt SA Two, SA three,
and SA six launches, French made Rolands, and even an
American produced Hawk SAm Battery, which was captured by the Iraqi
army during the invasion of Kuwait in 1991.
A main objective for Airwall Commander General Mosley will
be the elimination of AA capability in this area, which has
been named the supermissile Engagement Zone, or supermeVs.
While the strike aircraft are assembling, General Franks addresses
his subordinates by video call from his headquarters in Qatar,
telling them shock will be introduced at 2100.
You're all doing great. At General Mosley's
command post in Saudi Arabia and aboard the US Navy carriers
in the Persian Gulf, air controllers are closely monitoring the strike groups.
The mission planners have created threedimensional highways in the
sky to minimize any midair collisions or friendly fire.
These highways require incoming aircraft to fly on the right hand
side, while egressing aircraft fly to the left.
These paths are to be strictly followed by the aviators as
they fly into enemy airspace. An aerial innovation
will help the coalition improve over its performance from Desert Storm.
Both the United States and United Kingdom have since built fleets
of UAVs, which can provide valuable intelligence without putting
their operators in danger. A year earlier,
the US Air Force unsuccessfully attempted to shoot down an Iraqi
MiG 25 using a predator drone. But the episode spooked
Iraqi High Command into ceasing aerial patrols.
In preparation for a day, unarmed Predator drones have been loitering
above Baghdad to document enemy air defenses.
At just before 09:00 p.m. Navy Special Mission C 130s
drop three fire B target drones and peel away. While the drones continue
on a predictable heading towards Baghdad. These drones
are to act as decoys and draw the attention of Iraqi air defenses
away from the incoming raids.
Arriving on station simultaneously, the B 52s
from the UK and from Diego Garcia fulfill a similar task
to their first actions during Desert Storm. The Strata
Fortresses launch 100 AGM 86 C cruise
missiles from both the northwest and southeast of Iraq, the largest
air launched cruise missile attack in history.
The strata fortresses turn for home while the US Navy warships
in the Persian Gulf launch Tomahawk missiles. A day
will see 504 cruise missile strikes against regime targets.
The first strike on Baghdad will come in three waves and attack over 100
targets in the capital. While the fire B target drones
distract the antiaircraft batteries around the city. The cruise missiles will
strike Barthis targets and Republican Guard command posts
to further draw Iraqi antiaircraft fire.
They will then be followed by twelve F 117 Nighthawks supported
by ten EA six B Prowlers, which will jam enemy radars.
If the Prowlers detect Iraqi fire control radars, eight F
16 CJ Wild weasels will be vectored to destroy
the enemy with radar seeking harm missiles.
Four B, two stealth bombers, 20 FA, eighteen S,
eight F, fourteen S and eight F fifteen E's will
follow in to hit targets in the city after the Iraqi air defenses have
been exhausted. Immediately following the initial attack in
Baghdad, hundreds of strike aircraft will execute their planned
missions to attack military installations across the country.
The B One B Lancers will act as socalled roving linebackers,
patrolling Iraqi airspace and awaiting the order to unleash their
munitions on targets of opportunity.
More airstrikes by RAF Tornadoes and B One B's will
simultaneously target what remains of Iraq's air force and
SAM capabilities around the Supermez.
Altogether, the A day strike aircraft will carry out
more than 1700 sorties against Saddam's regime.
The Fire B target drones launched earlier arrive over Baghdad
and have their intended effect. Iraqi radar teams
take the bait and switch on their radar sets to lock onto the drones.
Antiaircraft fire erupts wildly into the night sky.
Once the drones are within the city limits, they release aluminium chaff strips.
Scrambling Iraqi radar sets even further.
At exactly 09:00 p.m.. H hour, the first AGMs and
Tomahawks scream into Baghdad. Just as
planned, the Iraqi defenders open fire with all the weapons at their disposal.
Like in 1991, news organizations have trained
their cameras on the city and broadcast the opening salvo
of the air offensive live to the world.
This time, none of the bridges over the Euphrates or Tigris
rivers are bombed, as the American forces will soon need these crossings.
In their drive northwest. With new
intelligence on the dire state of Iraqi infrastructure,
electricity and water systems will also be spared.
Thus, those watching at home are treated to the strange sight
of downtown Baghdad being hit by cruise missiles while
the city is still fully lit.
The night before, the Bush administration removed over 500 targets
from the strike list, worried that Saddam's government might collapse too
quickly and leave the country in anarchy.
While the cruise missiles are pummeling Baghdad, the F 117s
have encountered a problem because of
the large number of aircraft involved in the operation. All KC
Ten, KC 130 and KC 135 tankers
are swamped by refueling missions, and nine of the twelve nighthawks
have been unable to tank on schedule. Only the three remaining F
117s have continued to bag down.
Once the city is in sight, they split up and prepare to execute.
Their attack runs from different directions to dilute enemy AA
fire. Colonel Matthew McKeown, Major Stephen
Anchorstar, and Captain Brent Blake seek out their target.
Anchorstar is flying in from the northeast and locates his first target,
an Iraqi army communications array to the north of Baghdad.
At 917 pm, he drops a single bomb on the complex,
which detonates right on target. The F 117 continues
south to the city itself, which is now covered in smoke.
Following the cruise missile strikes, he then drops a GBU 27
earth penetrating bomb on a four way intersection rumored
to have a military tunnel running beneath it. He egresses south
as his aircraft avoids inaccurate antiaircraft fire and SAM
launches the oncepaunted air defenses around
the Iraqi capital. Do not score a single hit.
Colonel McKeown spots his target, the massive dome of the
Bath Party national headquarters. He drops a single
2000 pound bomb, which penetrates the building and explodes,
collapsing the dome. McKeown heads
north and drops another bomb on the same communications array. Anchors star struck
earlier before turning for home.
Finally, Captain Blake drops both his bombs on another regime target
in downtown Baghdad before also turning south,
obliging General Frank's order that the air forces should keep the heat on.
The B two Spirit stealth bombers arrive to continue the barrage.
As the F 117s are departing,
the stealth bombers quickly get to work. A B two drops
two 4700 pound GBU 37 satellite
guided bunker busters on an Iraqi communications tower.
The base of the tower explodes in a massive fireball and
the entire structure collapses. The B two can carry up
to 16 JDAM precision guided bombs, 16 JSAO glide
bombs, or eight GBU 37 bunker buster bombs.
All of these weapons are deployed on this night. Saddam's lavish
palaces in the Iraqi capital are systematically reduced to rubble by the
B two S at 11:00 p.m. Local time
the remaining conventional strike fighters in the Baghdad force move
in to hit their targets. It is also at this time that the conventional
strike fighters and strategic bombers that are now flooding into Iraq to
hit military targets across the country also begin their mass assault.
With Iraqi military command isolated and in chaos, the F
16 CJ Vipers begin the dirty work of suppression
of enemy air defenses or seed. Seed missions
are among the most demanding. Faced by pilots known as
wild weasels, the seed aircraft must fly in close coordination
with the strike aircraft and remain constantly vigilant in monitoring
enemy radar activity. These exhausting
flights can last anywhere between six to 12 hours and require
as many as ten midair refuelings to remain on station over the area
of operations. However, the United States
Air Force employs the most modern seed tactics along with the
feared harm missiles. Once an enemy radar set is
detected, the F 16s engage the target with harms missiles
which lock onto the radar emissions themselves.
With Iraqi radar sites continuing to try to illuminate American aircraft
over Baghdad, the environment is target rich for the F
wild weasel pilot later brags, the Iraqis knew for sure
that if they came on the air they were going to get a face full
of harm. With the skies clear
of enemy aircraft and the Vipers destroying any Iraqi
radar that illuminates, Captain Fox leads a flight of four FA
eighteen s to their target, an enemy surface to surface missile
site just outside Baghdad's southern suburbs.
While en route to the objective, Fox watches the aerial fireworks
from the cockpit of his Hornet as SAM and tracer rounds arc through the
night sky above the city, which is still fully lit.
He later recalled Baghdad's light and the building crescendo
of explosions were almost too bright to view through night vision goggles.
Each Hornet in the flight is carrying three AGM 154
Joint standoff weapons, or JSOs. These fire and forget glide
bombs are the perfect weapon to knock out the Iraqi missiles.
When the four Hornets reach the JSOW launch point, each AGM
154 releases from the underside of the aircraft with a thunk
sound. Guided by sophisticated avionics using
GPS tracking, the JSOWS glide towards their targets.
Within a minute, all twelve explode and demolish the missile launchers.
The Hornets bank to the right as Captain Fox is treated to
a unique sight. Below him, he spots a sea of sparkles,
almost as if there are people taking flash photographs from the ground.
He realizes that it is actually hundreds of Iraqi soldiers firing
AKS straight up into the air at his aircraft.
Fox later remarks, I thought to myself this would be a bad
night to go low. As the flight egresses south,
he looks back one more time to take in the spectacle of the air campaign.
The Iraqi defenses were spectacular but ineffective.
Another flight of four Hornets, including two from Marine Squadron
323 from the USS Constellation, are about to reach their targets
in the town of Kabala. However,
this mission is facing difficulty, as the four Vipers tasked
with defending the Hornets are late.
Commander Mark Hubbard and the rest of the flight are circling to wait for
them when he also learns that the Prowler electronic jamming aircraft
is also missing. Running out of fuel,
Hubbard knows he must abort if his support aircraft cannot arrive on time
yet. With less than two minutes to spare, the Vipers arrive,
and Hubbard gives the go ahead to continue the mission.
Two Marine Hornets split off to bomb a communications array just to the
west, while Hubbard and his wingman head for their target, a barracks
complex in Kabbalah, which is a training complex for Saddam Hussein's personal
bodyguards. Ribbons of Iraqi antiaircraft
tracers lace through the sky and bracket the two Hornets, who continue undeterred
at the release point. They each drop 2000 pound JDAMs before
turning for the Persian Gulf. Their munitions explode
right on target. Despite the heavy AA fire, none of
the Hornets in the flight have taken any battle damage.
Meanwhile, RAF Tornadoes join the fray.
Four Tornado GR Four S of nine squadron are screaming towards the
Iraqi city of Al Qut. On a seed mission,
Flight Lieutenant Andy Robbins and his weapon system officer,
Lieutenant Dave Williams, are the second aircraft in the formation.
Each tornado is carrying a single aim nine L sidewinder,
a chaff countermeasure pod, 600 gallon drop tanks, and five alarm
antiradar missiles. Robbins and Williams
receive a warning telling them that their aircraft's avionics cooling system has
failed, followed quickly by another, informing the men that the radar
homing and warning receiver has also malfunctioned.
Despite the cascading failures, Robbins closes up to the lead aircraft
to effectively share their warning receiver. They detect a
Roland SAM fire control radar set lighting up to search for targets,
and the Tornado achieves lock with the alarm missiles.
Four of the five missiles launch while the aircraft egresses south.
The alarms smash the radar, and there is little anti aircraft fire
as they return to base, Robbins is in awe of the columns
of Coalition ground forces below them advancing north.
He watches them through his night vision goggles and later recalls,
every road into Iraq was simply rammed with green dots.
At the same time, two pairs of Tornadoes from six one
seven squadron are about to showcase their MBDA Storm Shadow cruise
missiles for the first time an Anglo
French bunker busting cruise missile, the storm Shadow can be air launched
by Tornadoes, delivering 450 high explosive
warheads up to 350 miles and through the roofs of hardened
aircraft shelters and bunkers. Nine Squadron,
the same unit which sank the German battleship turpits with six one
seven squadron 60 years earlier, launched their missiles at hardened
Iraqi Air Defense Command bunkers in Taji and Tikrit.
They follow with alarm missiles against radar sites across the
country. The B one B Lancer
strategic bombers orbit the airspace, each aircraft armed with a
payload of 24 JDAMs.
When given the signal by the air controllers, the Lancers pounce on
targets of opportunity. The supersonic bombers
face little to no antiaircraft fire.
However, they do not hit many Iraqi aircraft, which are conspicuously
absent from their airfields. It is later
discovered that the Iraqis buried much of their remaining MiGs and mirages in
the desert to keep them from being destroyed in the initial attack.
This is also because Saddam believes the coalition will fail to depose
him, and he hopes to reactivate his air force once they have withdrawn.
Four F 15 E Strike Eagles from the 336 Tactical Fighter
Squadron are tasked with dealing a personal blow to the Iraqi dictator.
Nicknamed the Rocketeers, the Strike Eagles are approaching Baghdad
to attack Saddam Hussein's Yacht Club. At the same
time, four strike Eagles from the 330 5th Tactical Fighter Squadron.
The chiefs are en route to destroy the Republican Guard Barracks at
Saddam International Airport. These attacks
are intended to make it harder for Saddam to flee the country before he can
be captured. However, the mission is
already not going according to plan. One of the 330
5th Strike Eagles suffered an air to ground missile failure while
still on the ground, leaving only three to complete the mission.
When the F 15 E's are in range of the airport, another one of
the AGMs fails to launch. Two of the
strike Eagles manage to launch their missiles, but one explodes
only seconds after leaving the aircraft. Only one AGM 130
impacts the target but causes only minor damage.
The rocketeers fare even worse. None of the AGM missiles hit
the yacht club due to a data link problem.
The failure of these missions will lead to increased scrutiny of the AGM
130, which has gained a reputation for being unreliable.
Not that Saddam's yacht collection will mind.
Two F 14 D Tomcats of VF two and a pair of FA
18 C Hornets from VFA 137 are approaching
their target. The Iraqi Ministry of Defense's radio relay transmitter
at Salman Pack, a heavily defended town southeast of
Baghdad. The missions over Baghdad tonight are
the first non stealth attacks against a target in the Baghdad area since
the ill fated package Q debacle in the first Gulf War.
Lieutenant Commander Kurt Frankenberger is piloting the lead
Tomcat and immediately loses count of the number of SAM launches
against the formation, recalling we had to trust our systems and
visually confirm that each missile did not appear to be tracking,
then disregard it and evaluate the next one.
Four F 16 wild weasels are covering the strike formation and
launch their arms from behind them, knocking out enemy SAMs when they
dare to illuminate their fire control radars.
The enemy fire intensifies as the Tomcats and Hornets draw closer
to the radio transmitter. However, the radio intercept officer
in the other F 14 is unbothered by the heavy AA fire and is filming
the entire bombing run with a home camcorder.
Frankenberger remembers he took some great video footage
documenting the target ingress as if he was going to Disneyland.
Once they reach the release point, the Hornets and Tomcats release their
J dams and turn to leave the area. The radio
transmitter is destroyed and Frankenberger and three others will be awarded
the Distinguished Flying Cross for their excellent performance.
This is also the first time an F 14 Tomcat has dropped a JDam
in combat. One section
of F 14 DS from VF Two is diving in on
the heavily defended Al Takadum Air Base to the west of Baghdad.
The TomCats drop five JDAMs, which crater the runway,
making the base inoperable to the enemy.
Two more of the F two F 14s are tasked with providing air cover
for the other Tomcats, but the Iraqi Air Force continues to
remain on the ground. The bombing continues throughout the night
and into the early morning hours of the 22 March 4
FA 18 C's and two F 14s from the USS
Abraham Lincoln strike a missile production facility in Kabala.
The ToMCAts dive in fast, releasing four 2000
pound JDAMs. Three minutes later, the Hornets follow
and drop a mix of JDAMs and Mark 84 bombs.
The Iraqis launch several SAMs at the aircraft, but none track
and they make it back to the Abraham Lincoln without further incident.
Two wings of Tornadoes from RAF twelve Squadron are
heading straight into the teeth of the Supermez.
The first wing of eight Tornadoes smash Iraqi radar sites
near the northern city of Mosul with their alarm missiles, losing no
aircraft in the process. The second wing of
seven Tornadoes is commanded by Squadron Leader Kev Rumans.
Their task is to destroy the Republican Guard barracks in the heavily
defended town at Sarabadi, 30 miles southwest of
Baghdad, to minimize exposure to Iraqi antiaircraft
systems. Rumans lead the Tornadoes in line abreast so they
can each fire two alarm missiles once enemy SAM radars light up
while simultaneously dropping Paveway two laser guided bombs on the
barracks. With the sun starting to appear on the horizon,
the Tornadoes launch their alarms while unleashing all 21 of their
paveways on the target within a two second window.
With so many missiles and bombs in the air, rumors later says,
I remember thinking to myself that it looked like a scene out of the movie
Armageddon. The Tornadoes beat a hasty retreat to
avoid SAM launches, but satellite imagery later confirms the
Paveways have scored 21 direct hits on the Republican Guard barracks.
With the sun now rising over Baghdad, the first night of a Day is
over and the remaining strike aircraft egress back to their bases.
They are soon replaced by Hornets and a ten Warthogs, along with US Marine
and RAF Harriers, which arrive to provide close air support for
the ground forces advancing further into Iraq.
Much like its predecessor twelve years earlier, the first night of the
air war over Iraq is a success in some respects.
It is an operational improvement as no coalition aircraft
are shot down. This is mostly due to weaker than expected
Iraqi resistance. Furthermore,
major Iraqi airfields are rendered unusable by JDAM and
Storm shadow strikes, knocking the Iraqi Air Force out of the war
in the first few hours. In contrast to the Desert Storm
air War, the Iraqi Air Force does not take to the skies during the
entire campaign. When asked by the press why the Iraqi
Air Force will not come out to fight, General Mosley responds,
I believe that he has not flown because in their mind they've made a calculation
that they will not survive for the rest of Operation Iraqi
Freedom. The main focus of the coalition's air power will be to
provide close air support to ground troops as they advance northwest,
Michael Knights, a British defense analyst, will later observe.
In contrast to the beginning of Operation Desert Storm, which had been a triumph
of orchestration, the opening of Operation Iraqi Freedom would prove
to be a triumph of improvisation.
Despite radical changes made to the plan in the hours before the
attack, the air offensive smashes Iraqi defenses to bits.
A day is such a complete success in neutralizing enemy
air defenses that the non stealth B One B bombers are able
to fly daytime missions over the Supermez. By the third day of
the campaign, the Coalition ground forces will
enjoy unrivaled air superiority as they advance northwest.
However, the air campaign does not deliver a strategic knockout blow
as hoped. The decision to remove key regime targets
from the list at the last minute spares much of Saddam's military capability.
Unlike Desert Storm. His forces will continue to fight hard
against the advancing coalition forces.
Thanks again to our patrons who helped to make these videos possible.
Your support is the reason we can produce series like this. Welcome to
all our new Patrons this month, and special thanks to our patron of the week,
Sean Heidrick, who's been a longtime supporter of the channel. Each week
we select our favorite Patreon reactions to shout out.
This week, our favorite patron comment is from Rob Crocker, who says
it would be a bad night to go low. Now that's what we call foreshadowing.
If you'd like to join our Patreon and get access to exclusive benefits such as
early access to videos, ad, and sponsor free, we would love to have you
as part of our community.