Part of this video was sponsored by SquareSpace.
This is the Hilde. It was the Dutch currency for hundreds
of years. Then it disappeared.
This was a shame. Not the euro, but the death
of the design. Its colors outdid every dollar.
Its lighthouse stood above all buildings and its port. Schwitz embarrassed
the queen. Some say even killed her. The Hilda
changed the face of cash forever. I believe it's the
best paper money ever made. But why?
Why was Dutch money so different? Why does it look so strange?
Nostates who are ASIC member yet to see them? Phoenix,
Ocha, Oksanar was different. He designed government
issued stamps with dramatic, playful colors.
Then he used brand new techniques, like computer generated graphics,
to create complicated geometrical patterns. In the 60s,
he made the air flatters, a series of five portrait banknotes
from the Vondel, a writer, huls, a painter, sveling,
a composer, the router, a naval commander, and,
of course, Spinoza. Together they all look kind
of OD. Oksenar's faces look more like they belong in
a comic than on a banknote. Dutch notes are very distinctive.
They are unlike any other central bank's notes that I'm
aware of. Visually very striking. But I can imagine that not everybody likes
them. When you think of money, you think of value.
A medium for you to exchange one thing for another.
But money is also branding. There are millions of
tiny billboards spread across an entire country.
It's a place where a nation shows what it stands for, a canvas to
display national heroes and icons. So why do
Uxenars feel like he's making a joke? The notes had to
have portraits on them of famous historical figures,
which would not create any political problems. Portraits are the most used
images on currency, and they can be a bit touchy.
For some, a nation is nothing more than the sum of its people.
We use portraits to hold some up as lessons and inspiration.
For others, though, portraits can lift up people whose value
system is out of date. Maybe even threatening statues,
intentional or not, can be monuments, colonizers, slave owners and
authoritarians. Maybe the same could be said of the faces we put on
currency. Should Andrew Jackson, a president and also slave owner,
be replaced by Harriet Tubman, a slave emancipator?
Should we avoid figures entirely?
The genius of Uxenar's designs is that it didn't matter.
He neither avoided people entirely or kept
them. He caricatured them. This is George
Washington. Fuck yeah, President.
And this is mean.
Okay? If you live in a country whose banknotes
scream, take me seriously, keeping or removing a portrait
will always be a controversy. If you have banknotes
that play the fool, well, then there's not much of a throne to fight
over. The air flatters
changed portrait currency, but it's Oxenar's second series that turned
it on its head. He was asked to replace the 100 hilda and
add a 50 and 250 banknote.
For the 100, he replaces the naval commander not with
someone else, but with a bird. This was
crazy. A snipe doesn't have ties to citizenship.
It's a bird found in marshy land. That happens to be in the Netherlands,
but it is by no means the Netherlands. For hundreds
of years, money was intimately tied to the faces of rulers,
earth changing scientists, and artists. Ulksenar played
a joke on them all. He made the Holnit Hilda,
the first banknote in the Western world to no longer be a
portrait, just a bird.
With the 50 Hilda banknote, he changed it up again.
He proposes a sunflower, another object with
no clear ties to a nation, but still an indirect homage to
Vancouch. The glue had made the bee fall off from the
top onto the flower, as though it flew there.
The 50 mark is horizontal. Some of its text is vertical.
This tempts the owner to turn the bill around. You hand the cashier
not money, but a flower. Finally,
there's the lighthouse, Olksanar's last and probably most
beautiful banknote in Bedbong Viet daughter
Hale Klein Letterchish VEricchEon
OLa Kust Plots hello?
Where am I? Why, hello there. You're in a squarespace ad.
What is this? Who are you? SquarespAce is the best website builder on the market.
It's the 21st century. You need a personal website. What are
you even talking? That's actually a fair point. With Squarespace's flexible
website templates and its new, fluid engine, it's never
been easier for anyone to unlock unbreakable creativity.
When it comes to designing your own website. Launch a business
and use Squarespace's analytics to build a marketing strategy
so you can make more money. Launch a blog and use Squarespace's
blogging tools to share your stories, photos, videos,
and updates. Check out squarespace.com for
a free trial, and when you're ready to launch, go to squarespace.com
Hoog to save 10% off your first purchase of a
website or domain,
Oksanar wanted to make currency that symbolized the Netherlands
without being a cliche. No windmills, clogs,
cows, or tulips. Instead of projecting what the Dutch are
loudly, Okseenar intentionally chose symbols that were a bit more normal.
He then took it a step further by converting these symbols into security
features. Banknotes need to be secured against
forgery. That's why banks will issue paper money with watermarks,
so the bills are harder to copy. Oksanar also
designed watermarks, but they were different. Instead of
heads or angels, Oksanar chose animals for
the 100. The watermark is the head of a snipe.
On the flower it's a bee, and on the lighthouse,
a dune. Rabbit and
Donkey ginjette, Lichter and Donker don
the rest. On a papill. You can look through the note and you see
a watermark. That is a rabbit. It was a rabbit belonging
to my girlfriend. Everybody has to walk around with my rabbit
in their pocket. I like that. Kaki is long as yet in a
Z and focal T. Is it in his hallexter, that is imply. But Eric
Bestandai Trey. The four account is the helaft, and articulant is
of the helaft, and for his whole extra and as she does now taken it.
Lift out downward and aim complete plighty on the ten
Hilde bill and on the Spinoza are fingerprints. I put
something personal into this. My fingerprint in the hair of one of the world's most
important philosophers. Spinoza. Very unholy of me.
Not very nice. The smudge of a finger is so sloppy that
no serious artist would dare to include it.
Uxenar did it anyway. By the time that the
Dutch National bank realized what they were, it was too late.
A joke in the pockets of an entire population. That is the nice
part of making banknotes. You can make monuments by the millions.
He did the same for the lighthouse. In the beacon,
he hid three women's names, his granddaughter,
girlfriend, and friend. The engraver had
included these names, also completely unknown to the
Dutch National Bank. The combination of security features
and Oksenar's personal humor was a reoccurring theme.
The smallest lettering that you see in that white square, well, this is meant so
that when you are sitting somewhere in a private place, like the toilet or somewhere
like that, you have something to read. Another counterfeiting technique
is microprinting. Banks will put tiny design printed
features onto a banknote. This makes it difficult for
counterfeiters to reprint it accurately with a standard photocopying
machine. This can be done by printing small lines of text,
but that's kind of boring. It's a security feature that's just
kind of slapped on to the design. The artist comes along, hands over
his sketches, his ideas. And then they tell him the design
had to be changed. That's our job. We are responsible for security.
This is to regarding.
It's one way of doing it, treating a banknote design and its security feature
as separate jobs. But there is also another way.
You make the security features an integral part of the design.
I said, I have to have unrestricted access to every
detail, to every technique, to every secret. Otherwise I cannot make a
good design. I must know what the techniques are. The bank accepted this.
You can add a bunch of small thin lines because it makes the banknote
secure, or you can add a bunch of small thin lines
because it's necessary for it to look good.
Alchangsproon Bay at on verper Fundamental bank Billet
Mustang and Danas article
and Danas Octarado under
a bill yet in the field it is neat.
Soma Optel Som Vanufactur it is a follow,
fan and verb concept for the 100, 250,
and 50 Hilda. Each had their own simple primitive
in the background where you could find hundreds of micro lines changing
and adjusting to different areas in a grid.
Were these necessary for the design or for the security?
The beauty is that you can't tell. For alobang Briete, there's needling.
Ferrari felt,
normal technique,
long sum over top
down Vulyudarin dick inked
lanes did obrose.
I chose very elementary colors because it was a small series
of only five values instead of single colors or muted
ones. Oksinar fought for vibrant reds, blues, yellows, and greens.
When I made my first banknote, the printers maintained that more color was
an impossibility. They said when you use a green, it must be very dark and
blackish green. Otherwise it's not safe. I discovered
that this was not true. I just had to keep on asking and asking.
Oksanar's banknotes did not only stand out next to single colored banknotes,
but they also stood out among the colored ones. It's almost
as though Oksinar's banknotes were like monopoly money,
which is, well, exactly what they were. The only money I
had seen, which was as clear as I wanted money to be, was monopoly money.
That was nice money in my eyes, so I hope that
my own work looks a little bit like that. You don't need to look at
the number on monopoly money to recognize its value.
The design is clear, the layout standardized, and the topography loud.
With the hilde, it was the same. At a moment's notice,
the faintest glimpse you could identify exactly which banknote it
was. The specific colors that were chosen were
almost nearly perfect. The primary colors, blue, red, and yellow,
are the most visually clear for the human eye. Oksinar believed
the notes which were used the most should also reflect that
when the value of the money was higher, only then would you find the secondary
colors a dignified green or a royal violet.
If you were colorblind, you're probably not getting this video,
but you could also still determine the Hilda's value from large,
legible letters. The objective was to use very
clear typography so that when you folded up the note you could see what
the value of the banknote was at least four times.
Uchsenar's designs were influential for the euro.
They didn't consider using separate colors until the Dutch National bank submitted
a proposal based on his designs. He changed the rules
for what a banknote could and should look like it
is. The deep in Nadalando's arms break as she
flagged by the Kustwantestitson Merkering spun and Valerien
Spoon to survive and Landhill
moi symbolis and Hill had Ken by a
fornatel on or so lavender tank.