How is it possible that the best performing stock of the last 30 years isn't
a tech company? While companies like Amazon, Apple, and Nvidia have
created billions of dollars worth of value by bringing new, innovative tech
to enterprise and consumer audiences, they still aren't number one.
In fact, the best performing company of the last 30 years does one simple
thing extremely well. They sell caffeinated sugar water.
That slims your options down. But it isn't Coca Cola or Pepsi. It's Monster
Energy. Since their IPO in 1990, Monster has grown by almost
200,000%. To put this into perspective, if you invested $10,000
into Monster, you would have made 19.2 million. On the flip side,
if you were to put $10,000 into Amazon, you'd get $1.4
million less. Now, of course, Monster started as a penny stock,
so insane metrics like this are easy to hack. But this type of
sustained success over a 30 year time frame is no fluke. How is this
possible? Monster isn't just another Cinderella story for business owners
to gawk at. In fact, there are four key lessons that, when implemented correctly,
will amplify the momentum of your business. How does a company perform
so well and get so little time in the spotlight? The news cycle is constantly
dominated by titans of industry like Jeff Bezos, Mark Zuckerberg, and Elon Musk.
Yet we never hear about the founder of Monster. And while we're at it,
who the hell even is the founder of Monster? Morgan and Morgan law firm
is set to file more than 100 lawsuits against the makers of drinks
like Monster. Tonight, a lawsuit alleges one of those energy drinks
could be linked to a death. Beyond the spreadsheets and stock market,
the birth of Monster is an amazing story of shrewd marketing efforts,
endless controversy, fierce competition, and, of course,
sleepless nights. This is the secret history of monster energy.
The monster we know today exists because of the iron will of one man.
That man is Rodney Sachs. Now, if you've never heard of Rodney Sachs,
don't be shocked. He keeps a relatively low profile and stays out of
the news. He doesn't even have social media. It's nearly impossible to find any information
on the 73 year old billionaire. He's never taken an interview about his
life and keeps a laser focus on building the monster brand,
not his own personal brand. But once you do the research, you'll find that his
story should be studied by every wouldbe entrepreneur. Rodney was born in 1949
in Johannesburg, South Africa, to Jewish Lithuanian immigrants.
Rodney had a typical South African upbringing and didn't really show any
particular signs of being a future billionaire. He didn't go to fancy schools
like Harvard or Stanford. Instead, he stayed in South Africa and studied law at
a local university. But it was when he began his career, his true trajectory began
to show itself. After graduation, he took a job at South Africa's largest
corporate law firm and rose through the ranks like a rocket. During his tenure,
he became the youngest person ever to be promoted to partner. He stayed for
20 years and eventually became a senior partner of the firm, where many
would ride off into the sunset of their career. But not Rodney.
Rodney had been to the top of the Big Law Mountain. He'd achieved a
level of prestige that law students spend their lives dreaming of. He then realized
it wasn't for him. As Peter Thiel said, big law is a strange
place. After years of devotion to his craft, Rodney had come to
the same conclusion. He wanted to start fresh. So, like many entrepreneurs, he packed
up his belongings, his family, and his career, and moved to Southern California.
The year is 1989. Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade is one
of the top movies of the year. The 49 ers defeated the Bengals to win
Super Bowl 23, and most importantly, the Berlin Wall
fell, signaling the end of communism in continental Europe. Countries that
once had barren grocery stores are now seeing rapid amounts of growth and
new, globally produced products. Quickly, one big winner starts dominating the
fray. Red Bull gives you wings Red Bull was the model of global success.
The original Red Bull was named Krating Dang. It was a working class staple
in Thailand. After some ingredient adaptations, carbonation,
and intense marketing efforts, Red Bull became Europe's favorite
drink. Clubs from Manchester to Munich stocked the beverage, and it
fueled a vibrant party scene. While it wasn't until 1996 and 1997
that Red Bull would sell its first can in America and South Africa,
respectively, Rodney had noticed the trend, and it piqued his interest.
But Rodney was convinced his opportunities lay in another product category,
Smoothies. At the time, smoothies were huge in the US.
Jamba Juice was one of the hottest brands in the country, and lines were
down the block. Rodney saw the chance to produce bottled smoothies that could be sold
anywhere and everywhere. Gyms, convenience stores, swimming pools,
and health stores. This would be his big catch. Only one issue stood
in his way. Rodney owned nothing in the United States. So he
did what any first time entrepreneur would do and started raising money. Rodney and
an associate went to their friends and family and raised $6 million
to acquire a publicly traded shell company. This shell company
would serve as a vessel to raise even more money. And acquire an existing
player. If Rodney wanted to bring a new smoothie product to market,
he would need one thing and one thing only, distribution on his own.
He couldn't pull all the pieces together. There had to be a business
out there that had a killer distribution network but found itself on
hard times. Rodney's big opportunity came to him through an introduction
by an investment banker. The missing puzzle piece would be a business named Hanson's.
Hanson's was a staple of old Hollywood. Established in 1935,
Hanson's got their start providing juices to movie sets. The business
was a family affair and as a result, never became more than a regional success.
They built more manufacturing facilities to get into different verticals like
foods and sodas, but never quite reached nationwide popularity.
In 1988, after a period of aggressive overexpansion,
Hanson's had to file for bankruptcy. They sold off their manufacturing
capabilities to Tropicana to pay off some of the debts and had their
name acquired by the California Copackers Corporation. While many
would see Hanson's as a dead company, Rodney saw a diamond in the rough.
It had the one thing he needed, distribution. Hansen's pre existing independent
distribution network would give him a proper foundation to build his Smoothie
empire. All he needed to do was turn around the operation and launch the smoothie
line. From there, it would be smooth sailing, or so he thought.
So, in 1992, with his heart set on Hanson's, Rodney and his partner
purchased the business for a grand total of 14 and a half million dollars.
Now, that's almost double the amount that Rodney and his associate raised. So how'd
they get access to 14.5 million so quickly? The most likely answer
is that the investment banker that they were working with set up an LBO,
or leveraged buyout. Working with the bank, Rodney and Co. Took out debt to
finance the acquisition. Remember how Elon worked with Goldman Sachs and J. P. Morgan Chase
to purchase Twitter? Same principle before the ink dried. They were
losing money by the minute and only had twelve employees. The first four
years of his time as CEO include consolidating costs to put Hanson's on
the road to profitability. The launch of the smoothie line shortened the gap towards profitability.
In the first nine months of sales. In 1995, the smoothie line brought in
one third of the company's revenue. The next year, Hanson's was able to report a
profit of $375,000. The very next year,
Red Bull launched in the US and quickly became the number one player
in the category, a title they still hold today. What had only
slightly caught Rodney's attention before was now knocking on his door. The Hanson's executive
team was excited about this new category, and they quickly launched their
own product. With minimal branding and a little bit of work in the lab.
Rodney launched Hansen's energy with a skinny 8.4
fluid ounce can in 1997. To some fanfare. But it wasn't
a slam dunk. Success like Red Bull was. Over the course of the next couple
of years, Hansen's energy spawned new flavors and energy blends.
They tested out Taurine, ginseng, and even creatine, which you've probably seen
in modern energy drinks like bang. While Hansen's energy was a moderate success,
it was being targeted to the wrong audience. Drinks were touted
as functional beverages with near medicinal benefits. The drinks would
supposedly fight aging or give consumers stamina. The company focused too much
on the herbs and additives in their drinks and by association,
resonated with the health conscious market. What Red Bull knew
was that the real money was in the 18 to 25 year old male market.
Energy drinks struck the biggest chord with them, and they would
become almost like missionaries for the brand. After years of average performance
with Hansen's energy, Rodney went back to the drawing board and started thinking
of ways to really compete with Red Bull. They needed a total makeover.
Rodney and his team upped the caffeine content, increased the sugar,
and hired a killer brand designer to give them something extreme.
The result is the original Monster.
As opposed to the 8.4 ounce can Red Bull used.
Monster sold 16 ounce cans. The Insight was simple. This is America.
Bigger the better. You can't have a dainty little can and expect to win
the 18 to 25 year old male market. You need something with some heft.
Additionally, Hanson's offered retailers the same wholesale price as
Red Bull, so they would sell for the same price on the shelf. As a
consumer, you could either have the 8.4 fluid ounce European Red Bull,
or you could have nearly double the size with the 16 ounce American monster
for the same exact price. It was a no brainer. Alongside more
value to the consumer, Monster began an all out marketing blitz. On the retail
front, Monster had amazing retail displays. These displays spoke
to the extreme ethos of the brand and included elements like NASCAR,
dirt bikes, and later on, video games. The brand also made specialty coolers
exclusively for storing monster products at scale. These types of activations
add up, and Monster soon found themselves with great footing in
retail. Monster was flying off the shelves. One business owner loved working
with the brand so much that he commissioned a custom built metal display rack for
his gas station. But their efforts went beyond retail. Monster copied Red Bull's
Ambassador network and launched it on college campuses across the country.
You couldn't go to class without an ambassador giving you a can of the new
drink. However, the cornerstone of their strategy was in the form of
promotions. The early marketing thesis for Monster was simple. If an 18 year
old guy in the 90s thought it was cool, then Monster would sponsor it.
On the extreme sports side, Monster put their logos on all sorts of equipment.
Dirt bikes, skateboards, snowboards. Then they jumped into music.
Acts like suicidal tendencies and corn were given wristbands with
the Monster logo and were paid to drink out of monster cans on stage.
But more often than not, they weren't even drinking Monster. They were drinking water
just out of monster cans. It was a great branding move.
Monster became a massive part of the late 90s early 2000s cultural
zeitgeist, and their revenue reflected that. Going into the mid 2000s,
Monster entered a period of rapid growth. The Beast was finally unleashed.
Hey, diecast, want to pick me up? After the launch of
Monster in 2002, Hansen's sales more than doubled and profits quadrupled.
From that point forward, it was grind time for Rodney and the team. The most
important objective, building out the sales and marketing team to move more product.
At the time of the launch of Monster, Hanson's employed 108 total employees,
with the marketing and sales department housing about 66 employees.
In 2005, that number jumped to 293 total
employees, with 217 employees in marketing and sales,
just a huge amount of salespeople that increased headcount came
with increased growth. In 2005, Monster had captured 18%
of the total energy drink market. And while Hanson's was still in Red Bull
shadow, they were on the path to eclipsing them with a growth rate of three
X more. Now was the time to put the pedal to the metal. Hanson's began
experimenting with other flavors and brands to drive more revenue.
Products like Joker, Mad Energy, Roomba, Samba, Tango, and Lost Energy
hit shelves across the nation, but delivered mild results.
Joker was nearly identical to Monster with two changes. One, there was a
slight variation in taste. And two, it was only sold in Circle K
convenience stores. Joker was more of a success for Circle K than it was
for Monster. So the brand was sold off to the convenience store chain in
2010. But that wasn't the only fat being trimmed. In 2010,
after years of low sales, Monster discontinued the product line. And Roomba,
Samba, and Tango were no More. Lost Energy was discontinued
the same year. The problem with all these beverages was that they weren't standout
hits like the original Monster. Hanson's had spent a fortune building
brand equity with their Monster name, so why not use It? The only way to
launch new and successful products was to stay under the brand.
Umbrella drinks like Monsters Zero Sugar and Monster Zero Carb were aimed at
the health conscious crowd that were originally captivated by Hanson's energy.
Monster Java and Monster Rehab took notes from Roomba.
Samba and Tango released coffee and tea blends to become part of
consumers'morning routines. The executive team realized they didn't have to
rely on other brands like Lost to sell their product.
Monster had the brand that moved the product. They stuck
to the Monster brand. And now all of these products are successful and still
around today. In a final changing of the guard in 2011, the business
ditched the Hanson's name and became Monster Energy. They found something that
worked, and they were going to stick to it. More shelf space for Monster turned
into more lines of revenue, and Monster was entering its heyday.
But that success came at a cost. We've all heard it before. The energy
drinks were the best thing for your health. But now some say they may
be killing you. Is there a consideration to putting an age
restriction on energy drinks? Absolutely. We're looking at the
possibility of defining it as 18 or older,
or 19 or older. The number of people who go to the emergency room
after drinking energy drinks has doubled.
Monster was thrust into a big controversy. As public health concerns began
to dominate the airwaves. Regulators and the media were going for their
throats. It wasn't long before Rodney Sachs found himself in a congressional hearing explaining
the safety of his beverages to bureaucrats. But this regulatory attention only played
into Monster's hand. Monster became edgy. All of a sudden,
Monster was the drink your parents, your teachers, and your congressional representatives didn't
want you drinking. Monster's target demo loved that. They liked being part of
something that felt countercultural. But Monster was only getting started. After the hearing,
the FDA issued a letter stating that they would not be taking any action against
Monster or any other energy drink brands.
Monster's shares surged 13% upward. Without the regulators
on their back, Monster began to mature and grow as a brand. In 2014,
Monster had finally reached full maturity, and Coca Cola signed
a deal to acquire a 16.7% stake in
Monster for a total sum of 2.15 billion and become
Monster's primary distributor. This wasn't a defensive move
against regulators, but rather an offensive move to keep increasing Monster's growth
in the world of beverages. Coke has the single best distribution network
ever. The saying used to be all roads lead to Rome.
But today it's more like all roads lead to a Coke distributor. This move embedded
Monster into Coke's international distribution system in a way
that would pour gasoline on MonsTer's international growth.
In other words, Monster now had the tools to take on Red Bull around the
world, all thanks to coke. Monster isn't just another Cinderella story
for business owners to gawk at. In fact, there are four key lessons that,
when implemented correctly, will amplify the momentum of your business. The first
lesson is brand adherence. Branding is a big deal. Imagine this
scenario if Nike announced they were going to open a hotel.
You'd have a clear idea of what that would look like. There would be an
awesome gym, a massive sports memorabilia museum, and expert
taught fitness classes available around the clock. That's the power
of a real brand. Now imagine if Hyatt Hotels said
they were going to make a shoe. I couldn't even tell you what color the
shoe would be in this situation. Hanson's was Hyatt
and Monster was Nike. Remember back to the launch of Hanson's natural
energy? While the energy drink market was wide open for opportunity,
Hansen's energy just didn't speak to the target consumer. The product
landed flat on its face. Now, remember when Monster launched their first new products
outside of the original Monster? Those weird brands you'd never heard
of, like Tango and Samba. Similar to Hansen's, Natural energy,
the branding didn't entice target consumers enough and the products were
a flop. Develop a damn good brand and stick to it. Lesson number
two, distribution is as, if not more important than product.
At every turning point in Monster's history, there was a clear focus on distribution.
Think back to when Rodney was looking to acquire a business. He didn't
buy Hanson's because the name sounded nice or he was interested in the history of
the company. He bought Hanson's because they had everything he needed to build
a successful smoothie brand, a solid distribution network.
Then, with the launch of Monster, distributors made sure to set up eye
catching retail displays and price Monster competitively with Red
Bull. That launch was a sink or swim moment, and the distributors were like a
life preserver for the brand. Now, with Monster as a mature brand,
they're partnering with Coke, the world's best beverage distributor,
to take a swing at the number one energy brand. Third lesson, go where
your customers are. Monster's early successes partially stemmed from its
elite marketing. But their process wasn't very complicated.
If anything, it was ultra simple. Monster built its entire brand and marketing
strategy around its customers. While Red Bull had mastered what European 18
to 25 year old males liked. They didn't have an intimate understanding of
the US consumer like Monster did. Monster was sponsoring everything an 18
year old in the 90s would think was cool. Working backwards, Monster identified their
target customer, 18 to 25 year old males, and then asked themselves,
what does this demographic like and where do they hang out from there? They spent
money making sure that there wouldn't be any 18 to 25 year olds who didn't
know what Monster was. By focusing so intently on their
customers, Monster built more than a drink brand. They built a cultural force,
deciding what was and wasn't cool. But there's a big question of
how. How did Rodney know what would resonate with 18 to 25 year old
American males? When Rodney bought Hanson's in 92, he was
a 42 year old lawyer from South Africa. He wasn't
some snowboarding, skateboarding, BMX riding rock star.
He was just a guy who practiced corporate tax law, arguably one
of the most uncool areas for someone to work in. How did he know what
would be cool? How did he build Monster into a cultural arbiter?
This brings us to our fourth and final lesson, the importance of an open culture.
Rodney rarely gives interviews. In fact, finding any information
about him online is a massive struggle. As I said before,
Rodney keeps a very low profile. He has no social media accounts.
But in 2011, Rodney gave BeverageIndustry.com
a Tellall and went no holds barred. In it, he gives away
the secret of Monster success. He says, everyone is able to
share their views and make recommendations from the most junior guys up.
We think everybody should be able to express their views and they should be respected.
When people say, how do you come up with new products? We listen
to the younger guys. A lot of them are internal. What are they doing?
What do they like? When we test our packaging and promotions,
we run it by the younger guys. The key to finding the right product
or packaging for the right demographic is hearing what they say and
understanding them in their own environment, as opposed to trying to figure out
what an artificial focus panel says. But that's not the end if
we stop there. The story is that Rodney built monster into a
powerhouse brand, partnered with Coca Cola, and then rode off
into the sunset. While fitting for a novel, that's just not the reality.
The last couple of years have seen heightened competition in the energy driven market from
all directions. Red Bull is still the dominant player in the arena with 42.5%
market share in the US. While new entrants are springing up by the
day, the new kid on the block to watch is Celsius focused on serving
fitness enthusiasts. Their drink provides more caffeine than a
monster, while at a fraction of the calories. Celsius is owned by PepsiCo,
so they're directly at ODS. With Monster, however, Rodney has a plan.
He's going to take the market by force, starting with Bang Energy.
Now, if you're unfamiliar with Bang, they serve the same customer segment
as Celsius, but with more aggressive marketing and more caffeine.
Basically an updated and modernized monster. Their branding is
loud and out there, and the caffeine content of one can of Bang
is equivalent to two cans of monster. But what sets them apart from
the rest of the market is their heavy investment in influencer promotions.
In 2022, Bang Energy spent the most on YouTube, brand partnerships
of any company in the food and beverage category. But their focus isn't
just on YouTube, they're also crushing TikTok. The company's official hashtag,
Bang Energy, has close to 20 billion views.
Leading the company is Jack O'Walk, who is the brand personified. He wears gaudy
patterned shirts paired with large bang logo chains and
is always stirring up controversy. Remember, folks,
if you ain't training, you ain't gaining.
If you ain't banging, you ain't hanging. Does this say yes to the
dress or say yes to the breast? So if
you have a creatin peptide, you can solve mental
retardation as we age. Now, you don't have to be an expert
in FDA regulation to guess that Jack's statements might cross
a line, but it wasn't regulators that took him to bat over it. It was
Monster. Back in September of 2018, Monster sued Bang Energy,
alleging that the company was intentionally misleading customers and fraudulently
hyping up the benefits of its super creatine. The case was a home
run for Monster, and in September of last year, Bang was forced
to pay $293,000,000 straight to monster.
This may have been a bump in the road if PepsiCo, Bang's former distributor,
wasn't also awarded $115,000,000 settlement from Bang.
The company was in too deep. With all of these settlements adding up,
Bang had to declare chapter eleven bankruptcy. They were in a rough spot,
and they were close to shutting their doors. But this wasn't the end of Bang's
story. Guess who was there to pick up the pieces? Rodney.
In July, a judge gave the green light to the acquisition of Bang Energy
by Monster Energy, allowing Bang to steer clear of chapter Eleven bankruptcy.
Monster now owns one of the hottest names in the market, and they were able
to buy it at discount because of the shrewd legal moves. The stages are set
for Celsius and Bang to clash, but if I were Rodney, I'd be careful.
Do you remember how I said Monster was the best performing stock of the last
30 years? Well, with the help of the PepsiCo acquisition, Celsius is
the best performing stock of the last five years. I'm doing a whole series on
these kinds of businesses, so subscribe if you want to see more, and thanks
for watching.