Rising majestically from one of the busiest cities on Earth, the Shanghai Tower
is an iconic piece of Chinese architecture. With its twisting,
sleek silhouette, this colossal masterpiece stands as a
testament to human ingenuity and takes its rifle place as one of only four skyscrapers
on earth that is classified as mega tall. Today,
we're going to cover everything there is to know about the tallest building in all
of Asia, including the problems faced during construction, how it manages to meld cutting edge
technology with breathtaking design, and the debate about whether or not the
entire project was actually worth it at all.
Now, Shanghai is one of the largest cities in the entire
world, boasting an estimated population in excess of 25 million
people. Near the center of this enormous city lies the Luzhou Financial
District, right on the edge of the Hangpu River. For much of
its modern history, this area was a relatively undeveloped region. But beginning
in the 1980s, the government designated the district as a special
investment zone, and development was rapid.
By the 1990s, city planners had settled on the idea that this area would
feature three noteworthy skyscrapers to create a unique skyline
that would attract tourists and businesses. Two of these skyscrapers were finished by the
early two thousand s. That being the Shanghai World Financial center and the Jing
Mao Tower. These buildings were impressive buildings on their own.
But the third and final skyscraper, the Shanghai Tower, would steal
the show. In 2006, the Shanghai Municipal government began an
international bid for whichever company wanted to head up the project. And right off the
bat, it was clear that the bidders had their work cut out for them.
The designers wanted the tower to be the tallest building in Asia, shooting for taller
than 600 meters. Its style needed to match the feel of its neighboring buildings.
But at the same time, it also needed to stand out from them.
Aesthetics aside, there were dozens of technical issues to solve,
like the foundation, wind resistance, and economic feasibility.
Of the 19 tower proposals, the winning design was from the American architectural
firm Genzler. And after a couple of years planning and preparing construction began
in November of 2008. The first hurdle faced by the team was the soft
soil underneath Shanghai. An ordinary foundation wouldn't suffice here
for a tower that would eventually weigh more than 850,000
tons, as it would be incredibly unstable and especially
prone to seismic activity. Fears of the soil problem intensified just a
few months into construction, when a nearby apartment complex collapsed as
its foundation failed to hold the building steady. During an adjacent construction
project, apparently, digging crews had dug dirt out of one side
and piled it up on the surface, creating a pressure difference that the foundation just
simply couldn't handle. Fortunately, the apartments were empty when this happened.
And so it didn't really make headlines around the world. But a failure in the
Shanghai Tower absolutely would. And with
a building of this size, a collapse would just be nothing short of
super. Gao Garong, a geotechnical expert overseeing
the project, stated that if the proper steps weren't taken to secure the Shanghai
Tower, the damages could be irreparable. It could cause a
power failure, or sinkholes, leading to the sinking of neighboring buildings.
The consequences are unimaginable. There simply can be no
mistakes. The solution to the foundation issue was threefold. First,
the team distributed the weight of the tower across a much wider base of
reinforced concrete to spread out the force that it exerts on the soil.
And second, underneath the main foundation would be concrete pylons,
extending deep into the ground, providing significantly more
strength to the overall structure. About 1000 of these pylons
would ultimately be necessary. Finally, to make absolutely certain
that the building would be stable, the engineers decided that five entire
floors of the building would be undergrounD. To accommodate these five levels,
along with a foundation, the first step of construction was to dig a massive
pit measuring 121 meters across and 33 meters deep.
The concrete for the main portion of the massive foundation was then poured, and all
within three days. And by 2010, everyone was prepared to
begin construction on the main portion of the tower. The first step was to bring
up the core of the skyscraper, made of reinforced concrete. This was
done using what's called a slip forming process, meaning that all the machines
and equipment needed to create a floor are housed within a giant steel
platform weighing 1000 tons, which is then raised, little by
little, moving up after each floor is finished. It took
six whole hours to raise this massive platform to the next level. But it was
worth the wait for the safety and convenience that it provided. A special type of
concrete, called self compacting concrete, used for its high fluidity,
is pumped through a network of pipes up to the platform, where workers
then pour it into place. Throughout the months, the crew worked at an average speed
of one floor every five days, slowly raising themselves up into the clouds,
as the bones of the tower began to emerge into the Shanghai skyline.
Soon enough, it had surpassed the towers next to it, and by June 2014,
the building had reached its final height. And the crown structure was placed
on the very top, followed by the glass facade down its sides.
And then the interior design. Everything was finished,
and the tower opened to the public in February of 2015.
Now, the Shanghai Tower dominates its skyline. Coming in at
632 meters tall, or about 2073ft,
this makes it the tallest building in China, the second tallest building in the world.
And not only is it known for its height, but also for its elegant spiral
design and its glass twisting 120 degrees as it rises.
This look was achieved by dividing the core into nine distinct sections,
each slightly rotated from the previous, giving it its natural twisting appearance.
OriGinally, the designers wanted this spiraling to be even more
dramatic, originally envisioned as more of a whirlpool, but this
was adapted into the current version due to structural concerns. While it does
look impressive, the design isn't just for aesthetic reasons. A V
shaped indent known as a strike soars up the side of the tower,
which, along with the overall shape, reduces the impact of wind by as
much as 25% compared to a rectangular tower, which Genzler
estimates saved them as much as $58 million in construction materials.
Now, one of the most striking features of the tower is the glass facade that's
double paned, with considerable space between the inner and outer layers. This extra
space between the glass panes provides two main benefits. First is environmental.
Most skyscrapers use a single layer of glass, which is highly opaque and reflective,
in order to reduce heat absorption. But by having two layers,
the Shanghai Tower takes away the need for either of them to be reflective,
creating a heat buffer zone that simultaneously allows loads of
natural light to pour into the offices while also reducing the power needed
for air conditioning. In many of these buffer zones, or atria, hanging gardens
have been created. This sustainability, along with others, such as numerous
built in wind turbines and a system for catching and reusing rainwater, has earned the
Shanghai Tower platinum certification from the leadership in Energy and environmental
design, or lead the tallest building to have ever received such
an award. The second benefit from these glass panes is the creation of
public spaces in a glass atrium not already taken up by green space.
One can find restaurants, retail stores, cafes, walking paths and much
more, all accompanied by panoramic views of the city. And aside
from these public spaces, there are many more things for visitors to see and experience.
The first cell encounter are the tower's many elevators, which are the second fastest in
the entire world. Built by Mitsubishi, these elevators can race from the
second basement level to the 119th floor in just 53
seconds. And a fun side note, I've done it, and it's very
quick. They reach a maximum speed of 74.
After you're launched to the upper floors of the tower, you can step out onto
the observation deck, which is tied for highest on the planet at 562 meters
or 1843ft. It's certainly an impressive structure,
and according to one of the lead architects, it paves the way for redefining how
tall buildings are used in big cities. The designers spoke
of envisioning a future where all skyscrapers have these large public spaces
and boost the life of the city, instead of just being a dark
corporate tower. Now, all this sounds wonderful, but whether or not
it's even been achieved in the Shanghai Tower is actually open for debate. And it
all comes down to the immense cost of construction
and maintenance.
Now, the final cost for the Shanghai Tower was estimated at $2.4
billion, quite a hefty price tag, but one that was expected to pay
itself off through an influx of businesses. To the new officers, however,
this anticipated rush of corporations never really happened.
In 2017, the tower management announced they were actually struggling to rent
out the spaces because it had still failed to obtain all the necessary
permits from the fire department. Because of this, prospective tenants stayed away,
and even a large percentage of those that were actively paying for rooms
had yet to move into them. Another problem was that although the spiraling glass facade
certainly makes it look really cool, it had the unintentional effect of creating lots
of floor space, especially odly shaped edges and corners that were
entirely unusable, making companies hesitant to pay for space that they couldn't even
utilize. On top of this, the lead Platinum certification is an architect's dream,
but its increased efficiency also means higher cost for renters,
pushing away even more customers. As of 2019, 50 fire floors
were completely empty, a problem painfully obvious to the world at night,
when more than half of the tower was dark. This problem was only
exacerbated by the worldwide shutdowns a year later. 2020 saw yet another
problem for the building, which was widespread water leaks between the 9th and 60th floors,
damaging carpets, desks and a whole lot of electronics.
This caused many on Chinese social media platforms to add the Shanghai Tower to the
so called Tofu dreg construction projects,
or simply tofu buildings. Tofu buildings are the slang term
the construction of Chinese buildings of incredibly poor quality, often as
a result of speedy work, lackluster materials, or money skimmed by
corrupt officials. Management of the Shanghai Tower was quick to dispel these rumors,
and to point out that many viral videos of ceilings collapsing were actually from a
shopping center across the country from 2016. But the water damage
was real, and inspection teams had to be called in to investigate
the source. And once that had been fixed, there was still untold damage across dozens
of floors, as if they already didn't have an issue attracting
tenants. And so, despite being one of the most impressive buildings
of the 21st century. Having pushed the limits of engineering and innovating
several methods of construction, the Shanghai Tower is often considered by many to
be a failure. Keep in mind that it was originally designed to signify
the exploding success of the Chinese economy. But with its many
empty offices and its many dark floors, perhaps it has become an
ironic symbol of economic shortfalls. As one analyst put
it, no company on earth could afford to fund such a project and never
make their money back. Only large governments have the spare cash for
that, and it doesn't seem that China will be making a significant return
on their investment anytime soon. But the story's not over for the twisting skyscraper.
So in the coming years, if prices change, or if new incentives attract more
companies, the Shanghai Tower could transform into a new financial hub for
China and East Asia as a whole. But only time hotel.