Hello. It is time for this week's. Yeah, yeah, you can relate.
You've cut a cab before, right? You little sobs.
Taxi drivers confess their sins, and we realized
halfway through that it's not actually that relatable because no one catches taxis anymore.
Unless maybe you're a grandma. I don't know. But everyone seems to catch this
new Uber, as it's called. So we also had to do a
rare two for one here. Taxi. Uber drivers confess
their sins and you know, they will be mighty. You know those little
sons of bitches that give you free lollies are going to be. Let's find out
together.
Let's get into it. Very excited to do it for this one. This is
obviously a bunch of stories that we have collected from you that I've never seen
before, so that we all have fun together and make sure
that you put in your comments of what we asked you to
do at the end of this video, which I also can't remember. So we are
going to go into the comments there. Second drive from my first
night driving as an Uber. I didn't know that your soul got
sucked into the app. You're an Uber now.
Picked up a literal goblin from the city.
He was sweaty or excreted. Green liquid.
Was he? Is that humanly possible? I suppose you
would have to be a goblin. Yeah, the story does check out and smelled similar
to what I imagined. The inside of an illegal sperm bank.
This is amazing. It's like the most blue collar jobs
we've done have been the most descriptive. Except mechanics. You were all
a bunch of dumb, but they'd
like that regardless. Quick ten minute drive. I wonder where he
wanted to go. Green Gotch, please. Four minutes in,
he began. Nothing. A quick one out. Jesus, I wonder. He smelled like
a sperm bacon. It couldn't even last five minutes. It's the Simpsons line of
can't you go 5 seconds without jacking up?
How long was that when I asked him what he was doing?
Jesus, you really need those five star reviews,
don't you? Excuse me, I can't help but notice that you're trying to
ejaculate on the back of my head. When I asked him what he was doing,
he just snarled and continued,
confirmed Goblin. Isn't that an amazing response?
When I got to the destination, he moaned,
he's giving you that five star. And just got
out without either of us exchanging any
words. He didn't say any words the whole time.
Glad he didn't ask to sit in the front. Wouldn't have been worth
the $8, but in
the back. Money well earned. I was out driving for Uber
and pull up to this house. Passenger jumps in, chat for a bit.
Taking him to the airport. Now, this is in Rockhampton,
Queensland, and he was very
insistent on getting there ASAP. Anyway,
drop him off, none the wiser. About a week later,
I get a call from the police asking about a customer I had taken
to the airport. Turns out it was Matthew Cox who
murdered his wife and was on the run from the
police. Isn't it amazing that you had
General Chat with Matthew Cox?
What are you talking about? You watch that new serial killer documentary?
No, that stuff's too gory for me. I don't know why we
cut to a photo of him. I could have acted that character out. Look at
him. Identical. Just put up a comparison shot. I should
be one of those guys in the lineup. Turn to your left. I was promised
a coffee. A gaggle of uni girls hopped in the back of my car.
I didn't know that that's what that group was called. There you go. The more
you know they were causing the usual post pre drink ruckus.
Pretty standard. Oh, we're all aware of what that gaggle sounds
like. Turn it up.
Turn it up, driver. I'm getting post
traumatic stress. I never even had your job. All of a sudden,
I heard one of them make a noise akin to a sneeze.
I asked, all good back there? They replied, yeah, she gets
calved. Dropped them off, went to go get the next passengers,
a young couple who had informed me that there was a small vodka cruiser,
bile puddle on
my backseat. She just coughed.
Fuck off. Although it was set up, by the
way. I offered a couple of spot up the front and they're
like, nah, we'll manage, man. How much nicer are
they than the gaggle? It's a 15 minutes drive,
so I think Nothing of it. About five minutes in
to the drive, I hear slurping.
No, I say jokingly, you're not spewing too,
are you? No. Turns out they decide
the best place to give the bloke a
gobby was my vomit soaked back seat.
Well, at least we know there's one man that would approve the goblin from the
first story. This series sucks. All the stories are time,
nothing. To get my rocks up. I told them to stop,
to which the bloke said, oh, come on, man.
It's a horror short story. Your comment
should be sold at Dimmick so a bunch of 15 year olds can
get it from their auntie and go yeah, thanks. I simply said,
would you want to clean up? Come and vomit.
He zipped it up immediately. Brisbane is
fucked. You're right. I've been a terrible backseat passenger.
One time when I was driving Uber for a dude, took out a staple
gun in the back of my car and proceeded to staple his pants
to my car seat. It's a different one, I'll give him that. And I've always
wondered, what the fuck are staples even used for these days? Now we
know. When I called the cops, he just started screaming about
how I was trying to kill him and then demanded
I pull over. And when I did, he jumped out of my car,
leaving the nail gun and a small amount of his pants
and just tore up and stayed in the back of the seat.
Dude. Dude. If I could, I would
put as much effort as I did into interviewing Kevin Rudd for
the first time to just sit him down in an expensive hotel room
just to. So just walk us through that.
What was going on in your head? I wasn't attaching myself to the car.
I was attaching a car to me.
Became the car. Fuck me. And I don't know. No idea
what happened to him, but I pawned off the staple gun for, like, $20.
So that'll help pay for the new seat cushion, I guess.
Yeah. Was $1,500. Now only $1,480.
It's true what they say. Office work saves you money. Don't personally
drive, but I work the phones. Oh, you're like that guy in
that 70s show. That's not called that 70 show,
but is a sitcom. Taxi. Yeah, that's the one. A driver
once got asked to take a guy to a brothel, wait outside and take him
home. I thought that'd be, like 50% affairs. Old mate comes out
about half an hour later, quite pissed off, and demands to be taken to a
better brothel. About $600 worth of driving around to various
establishments with similar results. What a picky,
horny man. He finally drunkenly asked to
be taken home, and when they got there, he tried to pay the
driver another thousand dollars to come inside and stay the night. The driver
was into his 70s.
How do you go to every brothel in the city
and just be like, filth? No good stock in the entire
city.
I talked too soon. I was driving taxis in Adelaide
in 1996 to pay for uni. That's sick. How Ryan
Gosling is that? One of his characters, not him. He has a much better life
than that. I drive to the airport, mostly taxi
driver. Oh, wait, that's already a movie on a Saturday night
slash Sunday morning shift. Yeah, they're fucked hours, aren't they?
No one should be working when literally everyone else on earth is having fun.
Fredley Jordy's discovers the service industry and
laughs at it. Fuck. I had a real YouTuber out
of touch moment then, didn't I? What?
50% of jobs in society propping up the other 50%
of rich having fun? Why would you do that?
I was over at a radio job taking someone from a suburb to
the airport at 04:30 a.m. There's so many of you cabbies,
isn't there? There's so many cabbies on AM radio sitting there.
No, it's a thing.
A radio job is just their radio.
Oh, right.
This is so amazing. I'm so removed from society that I
can't even read comments about people that are in society anymore.
Oh, something I can relate to. A job in the media.
A. What was the starting salary?
5600 grand. Now, where were we?
Is misinterpreting this man's shit
life with a layer of exuberance.
Let's continue, shall we? From the end of the cul de sac, I was
offering my figure over the accept button. Considering whether to
ignore my gut instincts about the job, it was accepted by
another taxi. So I went about my normal Sunday morning,
trawling for drunks in the city.
What a sentence. What a sentence. And what a king.
That's Australia's version of world's deadliest catch. When I got back
to the taxi depot at 06:00 a.m. Shift and the building was crawling with cop
cars, the guy who took the radio job instead of me had been called to
an unoccupied address. Resident away on holiday
was ambushed and shot dead with
a heavy caliber handgun. No robbery
involved. His car and cash apparently
left untucked. What the fuck?
Just a straight up Jesus
Christ. So it wasn't a radio job. The taxi
request was a meticulously planned setup
for what other cabbies presumed to be, or had heard
on the grapevine to have been part of a gang
initiation. Fuck me dead.
Not a good choice of words where a prospective
gang member was required to kill a random person. Or maybe it was
just a thrill kill. He had a wife and kids.
The murder case remains unsolved to this day.
Well, as always, that has been a very
fun edition of Confess your sins this week.
Hey, we just had a thought. We've only been collecting the ones
of people who drive the taxis. And weren't they
just a topsy turvy adventure. Of all the emotions that one could possibly experience.
I'm guessing that you backseat drivers have some stories.
Maybe we can find out who did that. Hey,
probably not, though. But wouldn't it be a video? We'll see you
next, Jesus. Look, man, I'm very glad that you did that,
but ain't going to eat, too. Just clearly
not as bad as you did in 1996. All right, I'll see you next time.
He's gone. So go see his Adelaide show.
Yeah, that place that I want the guy at the end
of this story to come see it.