At base, every military has defensive capabilities.
They're able to protect their homeland from foreign threats.
Iceland's armed forces, for example, comprise four ships, one airplane,
three helicopters, and four radar stations, all operated by the
country's Coast Guard. Beyond a small paramilitary peacekeeping
unit made up of volunteers, the nation has nearly no capabilities
to deploy abroad. In fact, its constitution doesn't even have a
mechanism to declare war. Some militaries build on
their defensive capabilities with limited expeditionary posturing.
Ability to wage a small scale operation abroad. This requires
an expensive mix of training, equipment, and planning.
Whereas domestic capabilities can be permanent and stationary, all expeditionary
capabilities inherently must be designed to be temporary and mobile.
This spans from the ability to fire a missile to the ability to cook up
breakfast, which raises costs and complexity dramatically.
For this reason, large scale expeditionary capabilities are largely
confined to the largest, best funded militaries, like those of France,
Mexico, or Canada. But then there's the
US military. It is in a class of its own.
Whereas most nations can defend at home and some can deploy
abroad, the US military has a rather singular strategic posture.
They have essentially turned the entire world into home
turf. Their goal is complete. It's the ability to fight any sort of
fight, in any location, at any moment.
To an American, that might sound like the inherent function of a military,
but it's a uniquely US approach. Most militaries are merely
designed to respond to relevant regional threats and can scale
up to wage a war abroad if necessary. To be able to fulfill this
all encompassing mission. The US military has a degree of flexibility
and globality unmatched by any other, which incurs
a near endless array of exceptional costs for the force.
They pay to produce their own private label of chicken tenderloins and ship it
all around the world to places like this base in southeastern Turkey. Because they run
a grocery store there. Because they have thousands of service members stationed there.
Because that's where they keep about 50 nuclear warheads in case they decide to use
one in Europe, Africa, the Middle east, or elsewhere. They pay for
professional sports teams to incorporate patriotic ceremonies honoring past and
present service members into their games in order to help boost recruiting to the level
needed to staff all their roles worldwide. They pay to develop an occasionally
viral bipedal humanoid robot because they believe that in the future they can gain
a competitive advantage against other forces by having these robots integrate into their
ranks and fulfill the most dull, dirty, and dangerous tasks.
These costs grow and grow atop each other, then span all
around the world. From a spatial and logistical standpoint,
covering the globe is nothing less than a monumentally challenging and
expensive task. Then there's the temporal component.
Making sure that the right soldiers with the right weapons and technology are in
the right locations requires a predictive approach and proactive
planning and predicting what future warfare looks like. Then preparing
for it, is also an extremely expensive endeavor.
Take, for example, the USS Freedom, a first of its kind electoral
combat ship commissioned in 2008. At just under 400ft,
or 120 meters long. With this ship lacks in size, it more
than makes up for in design complexity and stateoftheart technology.
This ship represents two entire decades of planning and predicting,
researching and developing, contracting and commissioning.
A nearly inconceivable dedication of time and resources,
but one that begins to make sense when considering the expectations.
When conceived of in the 1990s, the latoral combat ship was meant to
lead the American Navy for the next half century.
With the Cold War coming to a close, the US Navy had found itself overindexed
in warships designed to patrol and battle on the high seas.
Suddenly, without a comparable rivAl, the US was the world's single
naval superpower, and its fleet needed to reflect this new order.
Now the new preeminent warrior was pirates, terrorists, and gunrunners
zipping along coasts, requiring something nimble, fast, and flexible
enough to keep pace in the in between. The coastal waters, where threats were
diverse and warfare often asymmetrical to fill the void,
Navy officials presented two ideas. The DD
21, a larger ship capable of holding its own on tight coastal waters,
or what planners called the street fighter. A smaller,
sleeker, and critically cheaper option.
From the jump, these street fighters were more appealing. They'd require
smaller crews. They'd be fast, capable of surprising enemies. They'd be stealthy.
And with the advent of new hull technology, they'd be light enough to push
45 knots while still having oceanwide range and carrying a
payload. If that wasn't enough to futureproof such a concept, they'd be modular,
too, capable of switching weapon systems and kits to fit different missions,
from surface combat to minesweeping. But still, by 2000,
such a Street fighter was just a concept. A concept that
the Navy quickly turned over to private contractors after it proved too difficult
to actualize in house, entering agreements with both General Dynamics
and Lockheed Martin to each produce two ships in two separate models,
the Navy handed the project off to the private sector, assuming the competition
between the two for future LCS contracts would produce a 21st
century mainstay. While the daunting scope had begun to add
to the price tag, the Navy hoped these ships could come in relatively
cheap by shipbuilding standards, somewhere between $150 to $225,000,000
per unit. By 2009, the US had two ships,
one from each contractor, but not four, as budget overrun
on both models was so extreme that the Navy canceled the contracts for the
second of each. What was supposed to be in the 200 millions at
most, had ballooned to about double the price. The issue was,
however, the LCS remained a critical Cog
in the planned New Age Navy fleet, and they needed to buy a lot more
than 256 of them, in fact,
or 82. Or 63, or 55,
or, most recently, 52, depending on their evolving ship force structure
projections. But no matter how many, they needed a lot,
and needed them fast, as LCSs were expected to replace old minesweepers
and outdated frigates. And rather than settling on a single class of
LCS as previously planned, to incentivize competition, they proposed Congress
an alternative, what they called a dual award strategy, offering each
company a tent ship contract over the next five years. All the while,
the problems with the Navy's current LCSs were already beginning
to show. As a general rule in shipbuilding, a ship
can have range, it can have speed, and it can have a heavy payload,
but it can't have all three at once. With speed as a
principal mandate, both General Dynamics and Lockheed Martin had to
get creative and make sacrifices. While both classes are able
to reach an incredible 44 knots, some ten to 15 more than
a typical Navy ship, they made separate design choices to get there.
For the independence class, this meant a unique aluminum trimaran haul.
As for the Freedom class, while Lockheed Martin went with a more conventional steel
Monahaul, it innovated on the drivetrain side, developing a complicated combining
gear that connected the ship's diesel engines with its gas turbines.
Both designs were innovative, but both had problems.
Aluminum hulls, it turns out, are brittle, and at speeds of
higher than just 15 knots, or on rough seas, they may well
crack. As for the combining gear, well, they were hard
to keep running, as the components were buried so deep in the ship that maintenance
staff could hardly reach them. And when they broke down, as they did early and
often, they were so complicated that Navy personnel had to wait around for
Lockheed engineers to diagnose the problem and come up with a solution.
Then there was the issue of survivability. Built as a combat
ship, the LCS was intended to reach level one survivability, the ability
to continue operations after an underwater explosive attack
in 2010, the same year it pushed for the Congressional Greenlight for
20 more of these ships. The Navy conceded that the ships already produced
hadn't reached level one survivability, and still,
it got worse in the rush to get these ships on the
water, no time was taken to ensure that all the ship modules actually worked.
When they did get to testing the modules, it turned out they didn't.
The antisubmarine warfare module proved unreliable because
the ship itself is so loud that the toad sonar can't reliably
pick up any other noise. Similarly, the mine Countermeasures
Mission package, which relies on onboard sensors and an unmanned
influence sweep system, has been plagued with delays, breakdowns, and a
penchant for causing false alarms. What was supposed to be an
endlessly customizable ship, capable for surface combat,
submarine hunting, and minesweeping, has effectively been rendered just a gunship
that can't take a hit. Regardless of
these varying limitations, as of 2023, the US Navy
has purchased 30 LCSs. They've broken
down at sea, they've bumped into walls of the Panama Canal, they've spent
a winter stuck in an iced over St. Lawrence river, they've run a handful of
minor missions, and they've averaged about half a billion per
ship to build. For a ship that was supposed to be the future,
the Latoral combat ship has proved nothing short of a disaster,
a reality the Navy's finally begun to come to grips with by decommissioning,
or working towards decommissioning nine of the vessels.
The LCS, by all metrics, has failed to live up to
its lofty billing, and it has failed publicly and
expensively. But it's far from the only decades long
development project that's fallen on its face. Boeing Sikorsky
won the contract to build the Comanche helicopter in 1991, but after
a decade of work and $7 billion being poured into the project,
only two prototypes ever actually left the ground. As for America's
first stealth destroyer, the Zumwalt, its gun system has yet to
prove the range it's promised. Its missile system can't hit targets consistently,
and its guided shells cost a prohibitive $800,000
per unit. With similarly high hopes as the LCS, the Zoomwalt project
was eventually cut after only three ships were built.
Then, most famously the F 35,
the Joint strike Fighter. Adaptable future forward, state of
the art has seen one technical glitch and one busted budget after the
next. For two whole decades. It's cost ballooning to 89%
over what was initially predicted. And the list goes on with countless
other, smaller, multibillion dollar projects.
To a certain extent, such mistakes and miscalculations make
sense when working to invent the future of warfare expensive swings
and misses are part of the development process. But it wasn't always this
way. And increasingly it seems the swings have
gotten bigger and the misses more frequent. When the
Department of Defense wants a ship or a plane or a weapon system built,
there's a select group of five companies. It typically turns to Lockheed
Martin, Raytheon, Northrop Grumman, Boeing, and General Dynamics.
Excluding Boeing, all these companies earn the majority of
their revenue from US or allied military contracts, which only
happen with the approval of the US. But even excluding foreign defense
revenue, 71% of Lockheed Martin revenue, for example,
comes from the US government. That translates to $47.5
billion a year. Put another way, Lockheed Martin
is given more by the US government each year than NASA,
a major government agency. In fact, if the Defense
contractor was a government agency, it'd be the 24th
largest. It gets more money from the US government than the majority
of government agencies. But unlike agencies,
thanks to this business, Lockheed Martin profits nearly a billion dollars
a month. But war wasn't always such a profitable
venture. Technology was what brought the private sector
to battle. Whereas in centuries past, militaries were primarily defined
by human might, the advent of airplanes marked perhaps the biggest
instance yet of a non military technology that could be
used to gain a militaristic advantage. During and after World War I,
a number of fledgling airspace companies gained modest contracts, with the US
military, contributing to annual overall production counts in the dozens
or hundreds. But then came World War II. Suddenly,
the US and its allies needed as many planes as they could get.
And with that, the US government started awarding colossal contracts
to anyone who could build an aircraft. Lockheed,
Goodyear, McDonald, Douglas, Boeing, Hughes, Grumman, Northrop,
Vought, Conveyor, and more. While all these companies had existed
in some form prior, the war was, for all intents and purposes,
what established them. McDonald, for example, went from 15 employees
to 5000. Hughes went from four to
80,000 as a sum, whereas in the six years leading
up to the war, the US built a mere 20,000 aircraft. During it,
the country's manufacturers produced a massive 300,000.
But then the war ended, and this was bad for business.
Aircraft manufacturers immediately struggled. Some shifted
towards civilian aviation. Others refocused on auto manufacturing. Others still
consolidated, while the US government searched for contracts that could be used to
keep this new industrial sector, which played no small part in the Allied victory,
afloat. Rather quickly, though, a new conflict emerged.
The Cold War. In its early days, rumors arose
that the Soviet Union had produced an inconceivable quantity
of long range bombers. As the world had now entered the
nuclear age. This massively concerned American media, the public,
and ultimately Congress. It was believed that their newfound enemy could straight
up eradicate the US. In response, Eisenhower ordered an
immediate ramp up of American bomber production and agreed to a Lockheed
proposal to develop the U two high altitude surveillance aircraft.
It would fly over the Soviet Union undetected, at least theoretically,
and get a definitive answer to just how formidable their bomber fleet
had become. The answer was not much. It was a mere
fraction of what had been speculated. But Lockheed and other manufacturers
had already cashed their checks, so the answer meant little to them.
A near identical story emerged just a few years later with missiles
the Soviets had launched. Sputnik and the Democrats of the ERA used the event
to propagate a narrative that Eisenhower and his Republican Party were falling
behind Soviet technological development. John F.
Kennedy, in the run up to the 1960 presidential election, latched on
to inflated estimates of Soviet missile capabilities, leaked from the Air force,
and started to make the perceived imbalance a central part of his campaign.
He argued that his political foes were ignoring this threat and the American
public believed him. Even after having received definitive evidence to
refute this fact. He continued the rhetoric. It was just so useful
politically, which contributed to an acceleration of U. S. Missile development.
This was a much needed windfall for U. S. Aerospace companies, given the waning
need for high volume aircraft development. It was this very
incident, in fact, that precipitated the first use of the phrase military
industrial complex in Eisenhower's farewell address, where he warned of
the phenomena's danger. The subsequent escalation
of the Cold War kept the defense industry alive and kicked off an era
of growth as US military spending started to consistently increase.
But then the wall came down with no more
Cold War, the DoD warned contractors of massive
cutbacks in spending. This kicked off a feeding frenzy
of consolidation and acquisition as the industry prepared to weather
what they believed would be the first sustained period of peace in their existence.
Defense spending did decrease, but only slightly,
and only for a moment. 911 and the ensuing wars quickly
returned the US to the historical trend of near perpetual spending build.
And today, with these wars largely wrapped up, the new most
popular justification for military spending is growing. Chinese military
might. Now, many of these supposed threats
may be legitimate, but it's tough to know with confidence because the
defense industry, its lobbyists and politicians are incredibly
effective at shaping public discourse. In fact,
the vast majority of the top think tanks are funded, at least in
part by defense contractors. These same
think tanks are what are used by politicians and the media as supposedly
expert justification for funding to counter new emerging threats.
Ignoring for the moment the more unknowable question of whether warmongering
for the sake of defense industry profits is effective. In practice,
it's undeniable that the incentive structures are certainly
there. But perhaps the best evidence for this phenomena's influence
is the fact that, inflation adjusted, today's military spending
is approaching World War II levels, despite no active
US involvement in any major conflicts.
Of course, one can still debate whether this level of spending
is justified by the present geopolitical landscape. But what's undeniable
is that taxpayers are getting less and less for
their money. There was a time when defense spending had undeniably
massive downstream effects. The US military was a major financial
force behind the development of world changing innovations like nuclear
technology, GPS, and the Internet. In fact, in the 1960s,
a full third of the entire world's research and
development funding came from US defense related spending.
But today that share has shrunk to a mere 3%.
And what was once perhaps the most innovative force in the world has
become downright bad at it. The US auto industry,
for example, has quickened its pace of development. It now
gets a car to market faster. The US commercial aircraft
industry has trended slightly slower. Yet in the realm of military aircraft,
something dramatic has occurred. What used to take
three or five or seven years now stretches
into decades. A key part of the problem is that
the government has taken the inefficiencies of the public sector and pushed
them into the private sector, where they can be profited upon.
When developing a new generation of aircraft or ship or
anything, the DoD sets strict parameters that
flips traditional incentive structures. Most industries see
the private sector innovate in order to create new products that their
customers will want. In this case, the customer tells
the private sector exactly what they want. And this industry spends
heavily on lobbyists, many of whom used to work for the DoD in order
to shape contracts towards where they can build with minimal risky
research and development, therefore stifling innovation.
But even then, the risk for the contractor is mitigated
further because a big chunk of contracts are awarded on
a cost plus basis. That's to say, the government
pays for what it costs to build a given technology. Then the contractor
gets a percentage on top of that as profit. This directly
disincentivizes cost efficiency, as the more a project costs,
the more the contractor makes. Of course,
in normal industries, the contractor would still be incentivized towards efficiency in
order to win the next contract. But in this industry, two thirds of
major weapons system contracts for example, are bid upon by just one
company, while yet more contracts are awarded without a competitive
bidding process. Perhaps most egregiously, it's well
understood that some contracts are awarded to struggling,
ineffective companies simply because the US government does
not want that company to go bankrupt and therefore for
its manufacturing capabilities to be lost.
This is perhaps one of the strongest justifications for the spending
the US military cannot afford for Lockheed or Boeing
or Raytheon or the other contractors to go bankrupt because they are
the only companies in the world capable of producing the
technologies that bestow the fighting force with such a technological
advantage. So a situation has been crafted where these companies are
too important to fail, and they know that. So they can profit
off of their necessity rather than their effectiveness.
The aforementioned only scratches the surface of the deep
web of incentives that keeps the military industrial complex alive.
But at its core, it's as simple as this.
It is good for politicians politically, and good for contractors
economically to create the perception of problems that simply
do not exist. No one gets punished when a
threat does not materialize. In fact, they can
argue that their response, upon which they profited politically or economically,
mitigated the threat. Meanwhile,
individuals are punished when a threat they argued did not
exist, materializes, disincentivizing anyone from doing so.
Fear is an incredibly powerful emotion,
and at its core, the military industrial complex has
created an incredibly effective system to capitalize
upon it.
As you might have noticed, the last Wendover video is no longer
on YouTube. It's a somewhat long and frustrating story, but to
summarize, there was a quick clip in it where you could see some personal info
on a passport. YouTube's harassment and cyberbullying policy includes
a provision against sharing personally identifiable information such as this.
And even though it was clearly unintentional, the video was taken down as a policy
strike, which seems fair given the wording of this policy.
Unfortunately, unlike with most privacy issues on YouTube videos,
because this was taken down as a policy strike, there is no ability
for us to rectify the issue, even though it could be done with a quick
blur. So the video is down permanently, at least on YouTube.
You see, a couple years ago, some creator friends and I got together to try
to both build on the best parts of YouTube and rectify some of its issues.
We called it Nebula, and it's gone fantastically, with over half
a million subscribers, hundreds of thousands of monthly active users,
streaming award nominations, and more. But one small way we improved
from YouTube was by adding this, a little button on our back end
that allows the creator to swap files on a video to correct mistakes,
make improvements, or in this case, blur that passport.
So the video's still up on Nebula, but we also designed the platform with
a unique business model that allows us to fund higher budget, exclusive content.
So another video that's up on Nebula is the latest episode of the logistics of
X about arms manufacturing. It builds on this video's topic to show the
nitty gritty of how the US military and its industry partners manufacture and
distribute the physical weapons of war, without those weapons endangering
anyone along the way. Clearly, you made it to the end of this video,
so I know you'll enjoy that one as it was written from the beginning to
appeal to those that enjoyed this video. We have a huge slate
of originals incoming over the next couple of months, plenty of which I'm sure you'll
want to watch. Then, in addition to the logistics of X, we have
perhaps the most ambitious, highest budget Wendover original to date in
pre production right now. And if all that's not convincing enough already, it's worth
mentioning that we designed Nebula to really be worthwhile, not only to you,
the viewer, but also to the creators. When you sign up at our link,
we'll get a portion of your subscription revenue for as long as you stay subscribed,
which gives us stable, predictable monthly revenue that we can rely
on for growth, unlike with the ebbs and flows of ad rates.
So if you'd like to get access to Nebula's huge catalog of original
content and help support the channel, just click the button on screen or head to
Nebula TV, Wendover. And when you do, you'll get 40% off an annual
plan, which brings the cost down to under $3 a
month.